Kiss
キス
We welcome Vice President Lee to host the performance of in national talent competition
李副大統領を全国人材コンクールの司会者として迎えます
Hu Yu for
胡YUFOフィーバー
Welcome Vice President tree
ウェルカム副社長ツリー
Extra
追加
The speakers of our session will be
私たちのセッションのスピーカーは次のとおりです。
report EI ONS is the same as NZ Hi
レポート EI ONS は NZ と同じです こんにちは
The speaker of our session will be
私たちのセッションのスピーカーは、
depth ty peugeot
デプｔｙ プジョ
This
これ
Senator
上院議員
Colleagues in the hospital and our friends from Academia Sinica
病院の同僚と中央研究院の友人たち
good night everyone
おやすみなさい、皆さん
I am very glad that you all come to our Academia Sinica today
今日は皆さんが中央研究院に来てくださってとても嬉しいです
Feast of knowledge in November this year
今年11月の知識の饗宴
We all enjoyed a very sumptuous dinner just now
私たちは今とても豪華なディナーを楽しみました
But apart from this bodily feast
しかし、この肉体的な饗宴とは別に、
More importantly, we have a feast of knowledge
さらに重要なのは、私たちには知識の饗宴があるということです
So we are very happy that you can come to participate today
本日はぜひご参加いただけると嬉しいです
Let's try, psychologically and intellectually
心理的にも知的にもやってみよう
Both can improve, both can increase our own nutrition
どちらも改善でき、どちらも私たち自身の栄養を増やすことができます
Let me briefly introduce our speaker today
今日のスピーカーを簡単に紹介しましょう
Today we are very happy to invite you to our Central Research Institute
本日は、皆様を中央研究所にご招待させていただきます。
Researcher and Deputy Director of the Institute of Biomedical Sciences
生物医科学研究所 研究員兼副所長
Deputy director Shen Zhiliang came to tell us all
副所長の沈志良が私たちにすべてを話しに来ました
Health issues that everyone cares about
誰もが気になる健康問題
is to tailor your health
あなたの健康を調整することです
Personal Medicine in the 21st Century
21世紀の個人医療
We often say, oops, why would someone have two meetings earlier?
私たちはよくこう言います。「おっと、なぜもっと早く会議を 2 回行う必要があるのでしょうか?」
some people get this disease some people get that disease
この病気になる人もいるし、その病気になる人もいる
Because everyone's illness is different
病気は人それぞれ違うから
Then when SARS came
そしてSARSが来たとき
Some people get sick and some don't
病気になる人もいるし、かからない人もいる
So what is the reason?
では、その理由は何でしょうか？
What about our Chinese medicine?
私たちの漢方薬はどうでしょうか？
called Chinese medicine
漢方薬と呼ばれる
different personalities
さまざまな個性
Personal physique is different
個人の体格は違います
Actually there is an important one
実は重要なことがあります
Just the genetics may be different
遺伝子が違うだけかもしれない
Are genetic diseases related to human diseases?
遺伝病は人間の病気と関係があるのでしょうか？
what is the relationship
関係は何ですか
We are the deputy director of the province
私たちは県の副局長です
He is at the Academia Sinica
彼は中央研究院にいます
the research done
行われた研究
They are all very unique insights in this regard.
それらはすべて、この点に関して非常にユニークな洞察です。
He was in 1983 and 1987
彼は1983年と1987年にいた
from the National Taiwan University of Public Health
国立台湾公衆衛生大学出身
After graduating from departments and graduate schools
学部・大学院卒業後
Go to North Carolina in the United States to train a doctor
医師を養成するためにアメリカのノースカロライナ州へ行く
So back after the Ph.D.
それで、博士号取得後に戻ります。
has been in our Central Research Institute
弊社中央研究所に在籍しております
Research Fellow at the Institute of Biomedical Sciences
医歯薬科学研究所 研究員
His research is quite outstanding
彼の研究は非常に優れています
so what
だから何
he has been all the way
彼はずっとやってきました
Both left molecular and genetic epidemiology
左の分子疫学と遺伝疫学
He is an internationally renowned scholar
彼は国際的に有名な学者です
Let me give you an example like the research on breast cancer that I will talk about later.
例として、乳がんの研究については後ほど話しましょう。
In addition to doing a good job with domestic breast cancer research
国内の乳がん研究で良い仕事をしていることに加えて、
We also participate in international cooperation projects
国際協力プロジェクトにも参加しています
is the first global team
初のグローバルチームです
To perform a full gene scan on the genes of breast cancer patients
乳がん患者の遺伝子に対して完全な遺伝子スキャンを実行するには
To find the gene for this heterosensitivity
この不均一感受性の遺伝子を見つけるために
He will share with you today
彼は今日あなたと共有します
Then we all often take medicine and say
それから私たちはよく薬を飲んでこう言います。
Oops, this A.R.M.A. eats watermelon Huan Jane
おっと、この A.R.M.A. はスイカを食べるフアン ジェーン
That means we often take medicine
つまり、私たちは頻繁に薬を服用します
Sometimes there are side effects and some people don't
副作用が出る場合もあるし、出ない人もいる
What are the side effects of this drug?
この薬の副作用は何ですか?
what genes are affected
どの遺伝子が影響を受けるか
Here's the research their team did
彼らのチームが行った調査は次のとおりです
this research is very important
この研究は非常に重要です
Admire the best clinical research in the world
世界最高の臨床研究を賞賛する
Beyond New Eagle Liver Medicine
新しいイーグル肝臓医学を超えて
It is important that the results of this study
この研究の結果が重要である
Also makes the US Drug Inspection Bureau say
米国麻薬監督局にもこう言わせています
When you want to take a certain medicine in the future
将来、ある薬を服用したいとき
which gene to test
どの遺伝子を検査するか
have this genotype
この遺伝子型を持っています
it can't be like this
こんなことはありえない
because of serious side effects
重篤な副作用のため
It has made a great contribution to the care of mankind.
それは人類のケアに多大な貢献をしてきました。
So we are very happy to invite the priest and director today
ですから、今日は司祭とデ​​ィレクターをお招きできることをとても嬉しく思います
Come give us a talk like this
こんな話をしに来てください
Let me tell you a little secret
ちょっとした秘密を教えましょう
Father and Director, besides doing a good job in research
父親であり所長であり、研究でも優れた仕事をしている
he is internationally renowned
彼は国際的に有名です
He is also the winner of many domestic academic awards
国内の学術賞も多数受賞
He is the recipient of the National Science Council's Relief Award.
彼は米国科学会議から退院賞を受賞しています。
Then in mid-December when he
そして12月中旬、彼は
I want to take this from Wang Mingning
王明寧からこれを受け取りたい
Outstanding Research Contribution Award
優秀研究貢献賞
That is the highest award in the civil state of Washington, second only to the President's Award
これはワシントン州では大統領賞に次ぐ最高の賞である。
so we welcome him to speak to us
だから私たちは彼が私たちに話してくれるのを歓迎します
Congratulations to his award
彼の受賞をおめでとうございます
OK
OK
Thank you Father Dean for your introduction
ディーン神父、紹介してくれてありがとう
I am very happy that today our good friends inside and outside the courtyard
今日は中庭の内外で私たちの良い友達ができてとてもうれしいです
tonight
今夜
I hope to be able to give everyone a
皆さんにもお届けできればと思います
What the priest and dean said just now
司祭と学部長が今言ったこと
A rewarding evening in every way
あらゆる意味で充実した夜
Then I'll give you a very simple start
それでは、とても簡単なことから始めましょう
Because it is now 100 years since the founding of the country
建国100年だから
There is a national movement in this place
ここで国民運動が起こっている
Among them, the State Council of the Forbidden City has the so-called wonderful 100
その中で、紫禁城国務院にはいわゆる素晴らしい100の組織があります。
There is the National Security Agency
国家安全保障局がある
that was a few days ago
それは数日前のことです
I went with my father-in-law and mother-in-law to see the national security guards in the Forbidden City
私は義父と義母と一緒に紫禁城の国家警備隊を見に行きました
One of the interesting words is
興味深い言葉の一つが、
One from the Southern Song Dynasty is called Jia Sigu
南宋時代のものは賈思姑と呼ばれます
painter
画家
He drew a painting called Yanguan Ancient Temple
彼は「塩官古寺」という絵を描いた
Then this ancient temple of Yanguan is known to many people in China better than me
そして、この塩官の古代寺院は中国では私よりも多くの人々に知られています
Our Chinese landscape painting is a very important boutique
私たちの中国の風景画は非常に重要なブティックです
He painted that pine
彼はその松を描きました
On that rugged mountain
あの険しい山の上で
This temple is very famous
このお寺はとても有名です
Look at the lower left corner in Jasko
Jasko の左下隅を見てください。
Jascu also put himself
ジャスクも自分自身を置きました
leave your name on it
あなたの名前を残してください
Well, of course I don't have an artistic flair.
まあ、もちろん私には芸術的才能はありません。
I love this painting
この絵が大好きです
really make me
本当に私を作る
most interested in
最も興味がある
These two things in the lower right corner
右下隅にあるこれら 2 つのこと
it looks like you zoomed in on it
拡大したようです
like the guy in the transformers
トランスフォーマーの男のように
And think what is this
そして、これは何なのか考えてみてください
Then someone told me
それから誰かが私に言いました
Ah, this thing, that is
ああ、これ、つまり
Judgment of Yang Ling's only breath is too bad
ジャッジメントヤンリンの唯一の息が悪すぎる
What are you actually?
あなたは実際何ですか？
Just look at the Qingming River Scene
清明河の景色を見てください
right there
すぐそこに
Our most original Song Dynasty Zhang Zheduan's Qingming Riverside Picture
私たちの最も独創的な宋代の張哲端の清明河畔の絵
Qingming Shanghe map has
清明上河地図には
The part with the bridge and the part with the river
橋のある部分と川のある部分
and that part of the street
そして通りのその部分
on this street
この通りで
Hey there is a person
おい、人がいるよ
you magnify it
あなたはそれを拡大します
What is that, ancient stranger?
それは何ですか、古代の見知らぬ人ですか？
So it turns out that Gu Sigu painted this thing just now.
それで、グ・シグがたった今これを描いたことが分かりました。
It's a stranger, it's just used oblique
他人だよ、斜めに使われてるだけだよ
That abstract method draws it
その抽象メソッドがそれを描画します
It's a person with this thing on it
これをつけてる人です
so it looks like a transformer
だからトランスフォーマーみたいだ
That's why Justin draws it more clearly
だからこそ、ジャスティンはそれをより明確に描いています
It's the one in the Qingming River Scene
清明河のシーンです
In ancient times, in my current words, monks
昔、今の言葉で言えば僧侶。
the monk of course
もちろん僧侶
make it more
もっと作る
see that clearly
それをはっきりと見てください
Hezang in Tang Dynasty and Song Dynasty
唐と宋の河蔵
Of course the most famous monk is Tang Sanzang
もちろん最も有名な僧侶は唐三蔵です。
take seven days
7日かかります
Tangshan Tibet in Dunhuang Dihua
敦煌迪化の唐山チベット
He also brought one like the one at that time
当時のものと同じものも持ってきてくれました
That's the same. He bid farewell to the Tang Dynasty emperor and said
それも同じだ、彼は唐の皇帝に別れを告げてこう言った。
I'm going to the West to learn Buddhist scriptures
私は仏教の経典を学ぶために西洋へ行くつもりです
so be yourself
だからあなた自身でいてください
what does this have to do with us tonight
これは今夜私たちと何の関係があるのですか
relevance
関連性
I thought of one thing with this
これで一つ思いついたのが
That is to say, we all have a Buddha
つまり、私たちには仏陀がいるということです。
That buddhist friend wants to say
あの仏教徒の友人が言いたいのは
Buddhism teaches that all beings should be equal
仏教はすべての存在は平等であるべきだと教えます
so can't kill
だから殺せない
So Buddhism cannot eat that animal
だから仏教はその動物を食べることができない
But in fact the habit of being a vegetarian in Buddhism
しかし実際には、仏教における菜食主義の習慣は
In fact, from the Tang Dynasty
実は唐の時代から
Because from the past, although Buddhism can say
なぜなら、昔から仏教ではこう言えますが、
try not to kill
殺さないようにしてください
But it's really going to be the time of the two and five emperors
でもこれからは二皇、五皇の時代になる
That's why we in Buddhism can't kill
だから私たち仏教は人を殺してはいけないのです
As long as the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代まで
Buddhist vegetarianism has only begun to become a
仏教の菜食主義はまだ普及し始めたばかりです。
Now everyone agrees that the one on the Niguel River
今では誰もがニゲル川沿いのものに同意します。
Can't just eat vegetables
野菜しか食べられない
Can't be vegetarian
ベジタリアンにはなれない
Then this thing is important to our medicine
それならこれは私たちの薬のためです
A big influence is
大きな影響力があるのは、
Vegetarian thing
ベジタリアンのもの
Thinking about it now is a healthy thing
今思えば健全なことだ
why is it healthy
なぜ健康なのか
Then let’s talk about the Vice President Chen’s speech just now.
それでは、先ほどの陳副総統のスピーチについてお話しましょう。
Specialized in my laboratory research
私の研究室の研究に特化しています
breast cancer in girls
女児の乳がん
Was there any breast cancer in the Tang and Han Dynasties?
唐や漢の時代にも乳がんはありましたか?
Yes, I have
はい、持っています
In the Song Dynasty there was one of the oldest
宋の時代には最も古いものの一つがありました。
The Treasures of Chinese Surgery
中国外科手術の至宝
It's called "Unrecorded Treasure Book"
その名も「未収録秘蔵本」
in this book
この本の中で
In fact, in Chinese history
実は中国の歴史では
the word cancer
がんという言葉
was in AD 1170
西暦1170年に
it really started to have the word cancer
本当に癌という言葉が使われ始めた
that in this book
この本の中でそれ
also began to point out a phenomenon
現象も指摘し始めた
That phenomenon is our epidemiological
その現象は私たちの疫学です
The golden rule that is often said nowadays
最近よく言われる黄金律
that is, breast cancer
つまり乳がんです
The incidence of breast cancer in girls is 40 years old
女児の乳がんの発生率は40歳以上
You see this is the incidence of so-called common cancers
これがいわゆる一般的ながんの発生率であることがわかります。
Female breast cancer after the age of 40
40歳以降の女性乳がん
began to happen gradually
徐々に起こり始めた
In this China's oldest
この中国最古の
It is mentioned in ancient surgical books that
古い外科の本には次のように記載されています。
Girls' breast cancer will start to climb gradually after the age of 30 or 40
女子の乳がんは30～40歳を過ぎると徐々に増え始める
And it took about three years to become ill
そして発病するまでに3年ほどかかった
then i put
それから私は置きます
just said
今言いました
Buddhism says to be vegetarian
仏教では菜食主義といわれています
breast cancer
乳癌
get together
集まる
It is one of our medical
私たちの医療の一つです
What is often seldom observed before is the
これまでほとんど観察されなかったのは、
nun
修道女
Nun because he is in Buddhism
尼僧は仏教を信仰しているので
he doesn't eat meat
彼は肉を食べません
so he is vegetarian
だから彼はベジタリアンです
But this vegetarian
しかし、このベジタリアンは
that is to say girls
つまり女の子たち
Don't nuns get married and don't have children?
修道女は結婚しても子供はいないのですか？
Usually wait and see
通常は様子見します
Girls who don't have children are more likely to get breast cancer
子どものいない少女は乳がんになる可能性が高い
But Nun Nico
でも尼僧ニコ
he does not have children
彼には子供がいません
But his chance of getting breast cancer is much lower than the average person
しかし、彼が乳がんになる確率は平均的な人よりもはるかに低いです
so everyone wants
だからみんなが望んでる
Nuns and ordinary girls
修道女と普通の女の子
The biggest difference between a nun and ordinary girls is that he does not eat meat
修道女と普通の女の子の最大の違いは肉を食べないことだ
therefore
したがって
Being vegetarian can prevent girls from getting breast cancer
菜食主義者であることは少女の乳がんを防ぐことができる
rare
レア
Everyone had this idea before
以前は誰もがこの考えを持っていました
Then we put our observations
次に、私たちの観察を述べます
From the Tang Dynasty to the Song Dynasty
唐の時代から宋の時代へ
Get our Taiwan today
今すぐ台湾を手に入れましょう
This is our girl from Taiwan
これは私たちの台湾人の女の子です
incidence of common cancers
一般的ながんの発生率
you can find
発見できる
Uterine Well Cancer Because of Lifestyle Habits
子宮がんは生活習慣が原因
Improvement in Hygiene Habits
衛生習慣の改善
Uterine well cancer is getting lower and lower
子宮頸がんはどんどん減少しています
But breast cancer is increasing
でも乳がんは増えてる
Breast cancer is now a common cause of girls in Taiwan
乳がんは現在、台湾の少女の一般的な原因となっている
Ranked by incidence
発生率によるランク付け
cancer number one
がんナンバーワン
is a very important
とても重要です
public health issues
公共衛生問題
Therefore standing on a medical
したがって、医療機関の上に立つ
researchers would like to say
研究者たちはこう言いたい
why is it getting higher and higher
なぜどんどん高くなるのですか
In fact the answer
実は答えは
Since then on the Niguel
それ以来、ニゲル川では
already told us
すでに私たちに言いました
Let's see again because of breast cancer
乳がんのためまた受診しましょう
a structure of our breasts
私たちの胸の構造
like our lungs
私たちの肺のように
like big trees
大きな木のように
big trees with big limbs
大きな枝を持つ大きな木
is the structure of milk ducts
乳管の構造です
What is breast cancer in the structure of milk ducts
乳管の構造における乳がんとは何ですか
Breast cancer refers to the structure of these milk ducts
乳がんとは、この乳管の構造を指します。
A certain cell starts from one to two and two to four
あるマスは1から始まり2になり、2は4になります
until the end of the milk duct is full
乳管の端がいっぱいになるまで
run out at the end
最後に使い果たされる
You use that histology section to say
その組織学のセクションを使って次のように言います
Suppose a breast cancer patient you cut a piece of cancer tissue
乳がん患者ががん組織の一部を切り取ったとします。
You can see that the normal milk duct is everyone
正常な乳管は誰でもあることがわかります
Below you can see that this is very similar to a pipe-by-pipe situation
以下では、これがパイプごとの状況と非常によく似ていることがわかります。
Let's talk about cancer cells starting to grow randomly
がん細胞がランダムに増殖し始めることについて話しましょう
always long long long
いつも長い長い長い
Fill the whole breast cancer
乳がん全体を埋める
We call it original cancer
私たちはそれを原始癌と呼んでいます
It looks like you see here on the right
ここの右側に見えるようです
It's the whole thing full of you see
それはあなたが見ているものでいっぱいです
Originally, the milk ducts were empty because of the absence of milk
もともと、乳管は乳が存在しないため空でした。
But primary cancer is to fill up the entire milk duct
しかし、原発がんは乳管全体を埋めることになります。
Once penetrated, it becomes a cancer cell
侵入するとがん細胞になる
running around
走り回る
This is breast cancer as we know it
これは私たちが知っている乳がんです
Through our awareness of breast cancer
乳がんについての理解を通じて
We explain why breast cancer is on the rise
乳がんが増加している理由を説明します
Because one of the leading causes of breast cancer
乳がんの主な原因の1つであるため、
female hormone
女性ホルモン
It's a chemical mask like this
こんな感じのケミカルマスクです
because it's simple
シンプルだから
boys and girls
少年少女
The difference between girls is that boys are almost free from breast cancer
女の子との違いは、男の子には乳がんがほとんどないことです。
Girls are prone to breast cancer
女児は乳がんになりやすい
Where is the difference between boys and girls
男の子と女の子の違いはどこにあるのか
boys do not menstruate
男の子には生理がありません
Girls have menstruation
女の子には生理がある
when girls menstruate
女の子が生理になるとき
In our warm tide will produce this female hormone
温かい潮流がこの女性ホルモンを生み出す
What is the main function of female hormones
女性ホルモンの主な働きは何ですか
We have female hormones to thank
私たちには感謝すべき女性ホルモンがあります
Because female hormones go to our breast cells
女性ホルモンは胸の細胞に行き渡るので、
Estrogen travels to the cells of our uterus
エストロゲンは子宮の細胞に移動します
will make one cell become two
1つのセルが2つになります
two to four
2〜4
where is the purpose
目的は何ですか
The purpose is to replace the fetus that may come
目的は、生まれてくる可能性のある胎児を置き換えることです
build a house first
まず家を建てる
you want
あなたが欲しい
The fetus is about to implant in the womb
胎児が子宮に着床しようとしている
Then of course we have to build a home for him first.
それからもちろん、私たちはまず彼のために家を建てなければなりません。
So the role of the hormone itself is
つまり、ホルモン自体の役割は
sudden death breast cells
突然死した乳房細胞
sudden death endometrial cell proliferation
突然死 子宮内膜細胞の増殖
to give a girl a chance to meet
女の子に会う機会を与える
coming baby
来る赤ちゃん
But this situation
しかし、この状況
Know the cancer cells
がん細胞を知る
what do we say cancer cells
癌細胞は何と言いますか
cancer cell
がん細胞
I just mentioned this situation
先ほどこの状況について触れました
so would have been a good thing
それで良かったでしょう
Hypothetically for cancer cells to take advantage of
がん細胞が利用する仮説
A normal cell
正常な細胞
Assuming that after giving it to cancer cells to steal it
それをガン細胞に与えて盗んだと仮定すると、
Cancer cells say I will use it
がん細胞は私が利用すると言う
This hormone prompts the cells
このホルモンは細胞の活性化を促します
This property of proliferation
この増殖の性質
that can easily lead to breast cancer
乳がんになりやすい
because girls have this
女の子にはこれがあるから
So girls get breast cancer
だから女の子も乳がんになるんだよ
boys don't have this
男の子にはこれがない
Boys don't get breast cancer
男の子は乳がんにならない
Then you say that this air belt causes breast cancer
それから君はこのエアベル​​トが乳がんの原因だと言う
What does it matter if you get higher and higher
どんどん高くなっても何の意味があるの？
That's the clue the nun told us
それが修道女が私たちに教えてくれた手がかりです
because where does hermon come from
ヘルモンはどこから来たのでしょうか
The source of hormone is from our cholesterol
ホルモンの供給源はコレステロールです
where does cholesterol come from
コレステロールはどこから来るのか
Cholesterol is in western food
コレステロールは洋食にも含まれています
high fat content
脂肪含有量が高い
So Nidi gradually became smaller
それでニディはだんだん小さくなっていった
Why now breast cancer is getting higher and higher
なぜ今乳がんが増えているのか
or you said just now
それとも今言いましたか
Why nuns are less likely to get breast cancer
なぜ修道女は乳がんになりにくいのか
Because the nun is vegetarian?
修道女がベジタリアンだから？
vegetarian results
ベジタリアンの結果
leading to their lower fat intake
脂肪摂取量の減少につながる
lower fat intake
脂肪摂取量を減らす
low cholesterol
低コレステロール
less hormones
ホルモンの減少
Cells are less likely to grow randomly
細胞がランダムに増殖する可能性が低い
So of course nuns don't get breast cancer
だから修道女は乳がんにならないのは当然だ
the same reason
同じ理由
So why is breast cancer more and more common now?
では、なぜ今、乳がんがますます増えているのでしょうか?
we joke
私たちは冗談を言います
Because now
因為現在
Everyone grew up eating McDonald's
みんなマクドナルドを食べて育った
Traditional oriental food has less fat
伝統的な東洋料理は脂肪分が少ない
Western food is more fatty
西洋料理は脂肪が多い
Now everyone pays
今はみんな払ってるよ
eat that eat western food
西洋料理を食べる
under the influence of western food
西洋料理の影響で
Of course the fat is higher
もちろん脂質も高いです
high cholesterol
高コレステロール
Of course, the cell proliferation is faster
もちろん細胞の増殖も早くなります
Therefore, the chances of getting breast cancer will increase
そのため、乳がんになる可能性が高くなります
So we know without looking at this
だからこれを見なくてもわかる
we often read newspapers
私たちはよく新聞を読みます
middle school lady
中学生の女性
Primary school has not yet graduated
小学校はまだ卒業していない
started puberty
思春期が始まった
That's because everyone is eating western food now
それは今みんなが洋食を食べているからです
Relatively speaking
相対的に言えば
breast development
乳房の発達
development of the uterine lining
子宮内膜の発達
like our grandmothers
私たちの祖母のように
was much taller at that time
当時はもっと背が高かった
that plus
そのプラス
Just mentioned that hormones will promote cell proliferation
先ほどホルモンが細胞増殖を促進すると言いましたが、
Of course he is now causing breast cancer to be higher and higher
もちろん、彼は現在乳がんを引き起こしており、ますます高くなっています
In addition to the effect of this muscle cell food
この筋細胞食品の効果に加えて、
There is another reason
別の理由があります
It is a law of economics and education that we teach medical students
私たちが医学生に教えるのは経済と教育の法則です
What is the law of economics and education?
経済と教育の法則とは何ですか?
That is to say, a cell in our body
つまり、私たちの体の細胞は、
is a cell
細胞です
midlife in terms of cells
細胞の観点から見た中年期
he only does three things
彼はたった3つのことだけをする
The first thing is called the opposite
最初のものは反対と呼ばれます
assassination of cells
細胞の暗殺
What is cell assassination? That is
細胞暗殺とは何か?
normal cells when found
正常な細胞が見つかった場合
when the environment doesn't need it
環境がそれを必要としないとき
It will show a high degree of sentiment and say that it is better to die
感情高ぶって死んだほうがマシだと言うだろう
like what?
どのような？
like our thymocytes
私たちの胸腺細胞のように
We grew up with a thymus as a child without a thymus
私たちは胸腺のない子供の頃、胸腺を持って育ちました
Why?
なぜ？
Thymocytes are the source of immune cells
胸腺細胞は免疫細胞の源です
Normally, our immune cells come from the bone marrow
通常、私たちの免疫細胞は骨髄から来ます。
But when we were just born
でも、私たちが生まれたばかりの頃は
Incomplete bone marrow development
不完全な骨髄発達
When we were young, we depended on thymocytes
私たちが若い頃、私たちは胸腺細胞に依存していました
produce immune cells
免疫細胞を生成する
But when we grow up
でも、私たちが大人になると、
After the bone marrow is fully developed
骨髄が完全に発達した後
Thymocyte Discovery Says It Doesn't Need It
胸腺細胞の発見はそれを必要としないと言う
I used a high degree of love to say that I am dead
私は高度な愛を使って私は死んだと言いました
So this is a phenomenon of a normal cell
つまり、これは正常な細胞の現象です
First
初め
Cells say a second thing besides the first
細胞は最初のこと以外に次のことを言う
That is to say, it is called cell division
つまり細胞分裂といいます
like we grow up in adolescence
私たちが思春期に成長するように
One bone cell becomes two
1つの骨細胞が2つになる
Only when two become four can we grow taller
2人が4人になって初めて身長が伸びることができる
So the second thing is called cell proliferation
2番目のことは細胞増殖と呼ばれます
what are cancer cells
がん細胞とは何ですか
A cancer cell is a cell
がん細胞も細胞です
replicative proliferation too divisive
複製増殖は分裂を招きすぎる
we just said
私たちは今言いました
The hormone itself will suddenly kill the excessive cell proliferation
ホルモン自体が細胞の過剰な増殖を突然殺します。
So we just said
それで私たちは今言いました
Hormones are what cause, for example
例えばホルモンが原因です
too much fat in the diet
食事中の脂肪が多すぎる
lead to more hormonal exposure
より多くのホルモンへの曝露につながる
So the chances of Drew coming are higher.
したがって、ドリューが来る可能性はより高くなります。
Drew's coming also has something to do with the third thing
ドリューが来るのは3つ目とも関係がある
In addition to death, suicide and proliferation of cells
細胞の死、自殺、増殖に加えて
The third thing is called
3番目のものはと呼ばれます
What is differentiation? A cell does what it is supposed to do
分化とは何ですか? 細胞は本来の役割を果たします
is called differentiation
微分といいます
So we joke about cell division versus cell differentiation
そこで私たちは細胞分裂と細胞分化について冗談を言います。
A cell will only choose one thing to do again
細胞はもう一度行うことを 1 つだけ選択します
It means that as far as cells are concerned, there is no further study.
それは、細胞に関する限り、これ以上の研究はないことを意味します。
That is to say, studying at school is studying at school
つまり、学校で勉強することは学校で勉強することです
Play a specific role in social work
ソーシャルワークにおいて特定の役割を果たす
He can't do two things together
彼は二つのことを一緒にできない
So a very important concept is what is called cell differentiation
したがって、非常に重要な概念は細胞分化と呼ばれるものです。
Cell differentiation means that a cell does what it is supposed to do
細胞の分化とは、細胞が本来の役割を果たすことを意味します
So a very important concept arises
そこで非常に重要な概念が生まれます
Since three things or two things will only choose one thing to do
3つや2つのことはやるべきことを1つだけ選ぶので
Thus differentiated cells do not divide
したがって、分化した細胞は分裂しない
Cells that divide do not differentiate
分裂した細胞は分化しない
That is, assuming a breast cell does what it's supposed to do,
つまり、乳房細胞が本来の役割を果たしていると仮定すると、
less likely to get breast cancer
乳がんになる可能性が低くなります
I just thought, what are breast cells supposed to do?
ふと思ったのですが、乳房細胞は何をしているのでしょうか？
Breast cells are supposed to produce breast milk
乳房細胞は母乳を生成するはずです
So everyone thinks that the answer to the mystery will be revealed gradually.
そのため、徐々に謎の答えが明らかになるのではないかと誰もが思っています。
What kind of opportunity would make a girl
女の子を作るきっかけは何ですか？
breast cells that produce breast milk
母乳を生成する乳房細胞
Pregnant and have a baby
妊娠して赤ちゃんが生まれる
Therefore, pregnancy and childbirth is to protect a girl
だから、妊娠・出産は女の子を守るためにあるのです。
A very important factor in preventing breast cancer
乳がんを予防する上で非常に重要な要素
So put it together, the mystery is gradually revealed
だからそれを組み立てると、謎は徐々に明らかになります
So why are we getting more and more breast cancer now?
では、なぜ今乳がんが増えているのでしょうか?
On the one hand, Cellfood has more fat and more cholesterol
一方で、セルフードはより多くの脂肪とより多くのコレステロールを含んでいます
Hormones are high, cell proliferation and division are more
ホルモンが高く、細胞の増殖と分裂が活発になる
Of course, it is getting higher and higher. Two aspects, changes in pregnancy behavior
もちろん、その割合はますます高くなっています 2 つの側面、妊娠行動の変化
Why don't you get married now, get married late, don't have children, have children late
なぜ今結婚しないのか、晩婚なのか、子供を持たないのか、遅くに子供を産むのか
The number of children is small, and there is no time to replenish milk after giving birth
子どもの数が少なく、出産後はミルクを補給する時間がない
If this natural protective factor is used less and less
この自然の防御因子の使用がますます少なくなると、
Of course, she has more chances of splitting
もちろん、彼女は別れる可能性が高くなります
Of course, the incidence rate of cancer is relatively high.
もちろん、がんの発生率は比較的高いです。
Therefore, these two reasons fully explain breast cancer
したがって、これら 2 つの理由で乳がんが完全に説明されます。
happening higher and higher
ますます高く起こっている
A long time ago, three or four years ago, with the Tri-Service General Hospital
昔、3、4年前、トライサービス総合病院で
Vice President Yu Zhicheng said in our cooperation
副社長の余志成氏は、我々の協力について次のように述べた。
Since the risk factor you just mentioned
先ほどおっしゃった危険因子があるので、
What is early?
早いとは何ですか？
Not pregnant or the first birth is late
妊娠していない、または初産が遅れている
or have no breastfeeding experience
または授乳経験がない
These factors are really so important
これらの要素は本当に重要です
then let's find
それから見つけてみましょう
Come to find girls in Taiwan after all
やっぱり台湾で女の子を探しに来てください
Each of these three risk factors
これら 3 つの危険因子はそれぞれ
Doubling the risk of breast cancer
乳がんのリスクが倍増する
So 759 patients were recruited at Tri-Service General Hospital
そこでトライサービス総合病院では 759 人の患者を発見しました。
Of course it's not just about seeing patients.
もちろん患者さんを診るだけではありません。
A total of 1,200 healthy girls were found
合計1,200人の健康な女の子が発見された
that than what
それよりも
It's easier than this, one, two, three, what is it?
これより簡単です、1、2、3、何ですか？
These patients are no different from healthy people
これらの患者は健康な人と何ら変わりません
One is bad, two is bad or three is bad
1 つが悪い、2 つが悪い、または 3 つが悪い
Do the statistics and find that
統計を取って次のことを確認してください
Breast cancer in Taiwan is indeed related to these three traditional factors
台湾の乳がんは確かにこれら 3 つの伝統的な要因と関連しています。
Hormonal factors are highly correlated with pregnancy factors
ホルモン因子は妊娠因子と高い相関関係がある
Because sick people compare with healthy people
病気の人は健康な人と比べてしまうから
Each additional
それぞれの追加
1.4 to 3 times more likely to develop breast cancer
乳がんを発症する可能性が1.4～3倍高い
With this conclusion, we were itching to be healed at the time.
この結論で、当時私たちは癒されたくてうずうずしていました。
As a result, Dr. Yu told his patients
その結果、ユウ医師は患者たちにこう言いました。
As a result, immediately filled with frustration, immediately choked by his patient
その結果、すぐに欲求不満でいっぱいになり、すぐに患者に窒息させられました
Why do we compare patients to controls—comparing
患者と対照を比較する理由 - 比較する
Indeed, patients are more likely than controls to have risk factors
実際、患者は対照よりも危険因子を持っている可能性が高い
But why is it choked up?
しかし、なぜ窒息するのでしょうか？
look at the patient carefully
患者を注意深く見る
On the one hand, we acknowledge that these risk factors are important
一方で、これらのリスク要因が重要であることを認識しています
But you really see patients
しかし、あなたは本当に患者を診ています
There are also as high as nearly 40%
40％近いものもあります
What about 39% of patients?
患者の 39% はどうでしょうか?
Not a single risk factor
危険因子はひとつもありません
The representative said, are these factors important? Of course they are
代表者は、「これらの要素は重要ですか? もちろん重要です」と言いました。
But these factors
しかし、これらの要因
There is no way to explain all that happens in breast cancer
乳がんで起こるすべてを説明する方法はありません
In fact, this matter is often found abroad
実はこの件、海外ではよくあることなんです
For example, let me show you
たとえば、お見せしましょう
A recent study
最近の研究
was made in Europe
ヨーロッパで作られた
One of the things he does is called dietary intervention.
彼が行っていることの 1 つは、食事介入と呼ばれるものです。
Because we just said that aunts don't get breast cancer
おばさんは乳がんにならないってさっき言ったから
So in the European study here
ここでのヨーロッパの研究では
A total of 4690 girls were found
合計4690人の女の子が見つかりました
The regulations say that you are 2349 people in the control group
規制によれば、あなたはコントロール グループの 2349 人です
2340 people said that eating meat is not good
2340人が肉食は良くないと回答
start eating vegetarian
ベジタリアンの食事を始める
Therefore, there are 2,340 vegetarians and 2,300 in the control group
したがって、2,340 人の菜食主義者と 2,300 人の対照群が存在することになります。
Observed 16 years to see their lives
16年間観察して彼らの人生を見つめた
let's see
どれどれ
For the control group it happened like this
対照群では次のようになりました
Of course, the longer you track, the easier it is to get breast cancer
もちろん、追跡期間が長くなるほど、乳がんにかかりやすくなります。
it's useless
無駄だ
our main concern is
私たちの主な関心事は
What happens to the intervention group equal to the bland food group?
味気のない食品グループと同じ介入グループはどうなるでしょうか?
what's on our mind
私たちが考えていることは何ですか
Eating bland food should have no fat
当たり障りのない食べ物を食べるには脂肪があってはならない
It's hard to get breast cancer
乳がんになりにくい
But everyone found
でもみんな見つけた
come and see
見に来て
I just found out a few months ago
つい数ヶ月前に知りました
published results
公表された結果
it turns out
それが判明
look at their reality
彼らの現実を見てください
The blue ones are on top of the yellow ones in terms of statistics
統計上、青いものは黄色のものよりも上位にあります
16 years of being a nigga doesn't do any good
16年間ダチでいることは何の役にも立たない
Relatively speaking, there is a 1.19 times more chance of breastfeeding than the creator
相対的に言えば、最終的に母乳育児をする可能性は創造主よりも 1.19 倍高い
In fact, this conclusion is not surprising at all.
実際、この結論はまったく驚くべきことではありません。
This conclusion was called overweight during the most famous medical period in the United States in 2006
この結論は、2006 年の米国で最も有名な医学期間中に過体重と呼ばれました。
There has been a larger study
もっと大規模な研究がありました
Harvard University
ハーバード大学
It tracked 200,000 of that so-called nurse
いわゆる看護師のうち20万人を追跡した
Because nurses are very supportive of medical research
看護師は医学研究に非常に協力的であるため
Therefore, in the tracking of this 8
したがって、この 8 の追跡では、
200,000 nurses tracked over 8 years
20万人の看護師を8年間にわたって追跡
We look at the incidence of common cancers
一般的ながんの発生率を調べます
and the incidence of chronic diseases we're talking about
そして私たちが話している慢性疾患の発生率
The first is breast cancer
まずは乳がん
The black ones refer to the bland food group
黒いものは味気のない食品グループを指します
The gray one is generally we joke that it is bigger than the big meat group
灰色のものは、一般的に、大きな肉グループよりも大きいと冗談を言います。
This is what everyone sees
これは誰もが見ているものです
Although the bland food group was slightly
薄味の食べ物群は少しありましたが、
would for the first point
最初のポイントにします
But doing statistical analysis brings congratulations
しかし、統計分析を行うと祝福がもたらされます
What is drawn is superscript and subscript
描かれているのは上付き文字と下付き文字です
Considering from the result of superscript
上付きの結果から考えると
In fact, there is not much difference between the two
実際、両者に大きな違いはありません
Been a nun for eight years
修道女になって8年になる
In fact, the prevention of breast cancer
実は乳がんの予防には
don't contribute at all
全く貢献しない
According to this foreign study
この海外の研究によると
Let's look at Chinese studies
中国の研究を見てみましょう
is my good friend
私の良い友達です
That Professor Zheng is there
鄭教授がそこにいるということ
The so-called famous Shanghai
いわゆる有名な上海
Breast Cancer Study
乳がんの研究
He is in the Shanghai area
彼は上海エリアにいます
Followed nearly a thousand girls
1000人近くの女の子をフォローした
and then depending on their diet
そして食事の気分に応じて
For example, you see
たとえば、ご覧のとおり、
One, two, three, four is the group of vegetarians
1 2 3 4 はベジタリアンのグループです
Instead, he is divided into a little element
代わりに、彼は小さな要素に分割します
a little more vegetarian
もう少しベジタリアン
To the last fourth is to be completely vegetarian
最後の4分の1までは完全なベジタリアンであること
One, two, three, four should be lighter
1、2、3、4 は軽いはずです
But look at the incidence of breast cancer
しかし、乳がんの発生率を見てみると、
If the first group is regarded as one
最初のグループを一つとすると
one point zero one point zero one point zero one point zero
ワンポイントゼロワンポイントゼロワンポイントゼロワンポイントゼロ
how is it
どうですか
no help
助け無し
Hence this result
したがってこの結果は
just tell us a frustrating
イライラしたことを教えてください
That is to say, the occurrence of Hollanda is of course closely related to breast cancer.
つまり、オランダ病の発生は当然乳がんと密接な関係があるのです。
But how much breast cancer does it explain?
しかし、乳がんはどの程度説明できるのでしょうか?
looks very limited
非常に限られたものに見える
That girl is crazy
あの女の子は狂っている
Said that you didn't seem to have any risk factors before
以前は危険因子がなかったようだと言いました
In terms of public health
公衆衛生の観点から
take extreme precautions
細心の注意を払う
It seems that it is not easy to have a good effect
良い効果を得るのは簡単ではないようです
The public health scientist is like the deputy dean
公衆衛生学者は副学部長のようなものです
He said we started doing stimulus prevention
彼は私たちが刺激予防を始めたと言いました
how to stimulate prevention
予防を促進する方法
Early detection and early treatment
早期発見・早期治療
Therefore breast cancer
したがって乳がん
Girls aged four to five now in the Department of Health
現在保健省にいる4～5歳の少女たち
every two years or three years
2年か3年ごとに
The government health insurance supplements the payment once
政府の健康保険が一度の支払いを補います
so-called mammography
いわゆるマンモグラフィー
Because you said that the food is actually bland
だって、食べ物は実は味気ないって言ってたから
that doesn't do much good
それはあまり良いことはありません
Then we have no choice but to retreat to the second line
ならば第二線まで後退するしかない
with early detection by mammography
マンモグラフィーによる早期発見で
for early detection of breast cancer
乳がんの早期発見のために
Then of course do mammography
もちろんマンモグラフィーも行います
psychology itself
心理学そのもの
That's very brave, I want to say I'm going to surgery
とても勇気がいるよ、手術に行くと言いたい
It's troublesome to line up with others
他人と並ぶのが面倒
And that good friend who had a mammogram must know
そして、マンモグラフィーを受けたその友人は知っているはずです
It's very, very painful.
とてもとても痛いです。
Girls can't stand it
女の子たちはそれを我慢できない
but no way
でも仕方ない
Striking the bathroom does not work
トイレを叩いても効果がない
Then we start early detection
それから早期発見を始めましょう
That benefits Taiwan's advanced medical standards
それは台湾の高度な医療水準に利益をもたらします
The one who did the mammography has a lot of doctors who are very good
マンモグラフィーを撮った先生はとても上手な先生が多いです
The main thing in mammography is to catch a little
マンモグラフィーで重要なことは、少しでも捉えることです。
the so-called capping point
いわゆるキャッピングポイント
That is to say, there's still obvious finesse here.
つまり、ここには明らかな繊細さがまだ残っているということです。
That is to say, some girls will see a little bit in the middle of the breast
つまり、胸の真ん中が少し見える女の子もいるということです。
Gaihua dots like grains of rice
米粒のようなガイファドット
For example, the cover point is obvious
たとえば、カバーポイントは明らかです
or is it
またはそれは
I saw that the so-called Department of Histology was seen on the right hand side
いわゆる組織学部が右側に見えるのが見えました
Just now this is a normal breast duct.
今のところ、これは正常な乳管です。
as we just saw
先ほど見たように
So the assumption is that the milk ducts are starting to proliferate a little bit normally.
したがって、乳管は正常に少し増殖し始めていると考えられます。
There are more and more cells like this
こういう細胞がどんどん増えていく
Another less favorable situation is called
別のあまり好ましくない状況は次のように呼ばれます。
Abnormal hyperplasia is called ADH
異常過形成はADHと呼ばれます
The difference between here and here is that there are more cells
こことここの違いはセルの数が多いことです
therefore
したがって
Therefore by mammography
そこでマンモグラフィーによって
Hoping to find a cover point
カバーポイントが見つかることを期待しています
and the circumstances in which this ADH is found
そしてこのADHが見つかった状況
Because I hope to catch it earlier
早く捕まえたいから
Abnormal proliferation of cells
細胞の異常増殖
If you find a capillary point or an abnormal growth
毛細血管点や異常増殖を見つけたら
It may mean that the breast cells have begun to grow randomly
乳房細胞がランダムに増殖し始めたことを意味する可能性があります
So the surgeons say it's not good
それで外科医はそれは良くないと言う
You should take that cell out and cut it off
その細胞を取り出して切断する必要があります
Wow that girl was struggling
うわー、あの頃あの子は苦労してたんだ
Going to that or that official surgery for him to have an operation
彼が手術を受けるために、あれかその公式の外科に行く
it hurts him to pull in
彼が引き込むと痛い
I want that wound
その傷が欲しい
And that two or three months can not touch the water
そして、その2、3ヶ月は水に触れることはできません
And that smoked a piece of meat
そしてそれは肉片を燻製した
Pull it in and take it out sometimes the breasts will deform
抜き差しすると胸が変形してしまうこともあります
So it's a simple outpatient procedure
ですので、外来で簡単にできる処置です
So there is no way
だから仕方ない
That person talks about that and that Gaihua point
あの人が語るあのことやあの凱華ポイント
Or that ADH is a precursor to bisexual breast cells
あるいは、ADHは両性乳房細胞の前駆体であるということ
Therefore, because the screening tools in Taiwan are very developed now
したがって、台湾のスクリーニングツールは現在非常に発達しているため、
So there are a lot of cover points and ADH
だからカバーポイントとADHがたくさんある
was found that a lot of that that
その多くが見つかった
women would worry
女性は心配するだろう
Am I a malignant breast cell?
私は悪性の乳房細胞ですか?
But really you ask an oncologist
しかし実際は腫瘍専門医に尋ねてみてください
you ask a surgeon
あなたは外科医に尋ねます
What are the chances of this changing here?
ここで状況が変わる可能性はどのくらいでしょうか?
40 so only 15%
40なのでたったの15%
That is to say
つまり
85% of girls get white cancer after that injection
その注射の後、85%の少女が白色がんになる
It's all pain, it's all white pain
それはすべて痛みだ、それはすべて白い痛みだ
Because most of the generalized points
なぜなら、一般化されたポイントのほとんどは
ADH
ADH
It's all benign and it doesn't matter.
すべて良性なので問題ありません。
So it's hard to retreat to the second line
だから2列目に後退するのは難しい
We hope to find an earlier discovery
より早期の発見を期待しています
Indicators of breast cancer such as mammography
マンモグラフィーなどの乳がんの指標
But it seems that the result is also
しかし、その結果もそうなっているようです
85% of that and that's irritation prevention is for nothing
イライラ予防の 85% は無駄です
So from what you said just now that dietary intervention
つまり、今おっしゃったことによると、食事介入は
eat bland food
当たり障りのない食べ物を食べる
Or back off to the second line for mammography
またはマンモグラフィーのために 2 番目のラインに戻ります
Tell us about the spirit mentioned by Dean Zeng Wu just now
今、曾呉学部長が述べた精神について教えてください
tell us about the risk factors
危険因子について教えてください
Very important. These risk factors include light
非常に重要です。これらの危険因子には光が含まれます
That diet eats too much oil
その食生活は油を摂りすぎます
What Covered Points Are Included
対象となるポイントは何ですか
these things are important
これらのことは重要です
But these things can't be explained
しかし、これらのことは説明できません
all disease occurrences
あらゆる病気の発生
Even a large proportion of breast cancers occur
乳がんも大部分が発生します
There is no way to explain it by these traditional factors
これらの伝統的な要因によってそれを説明する方法はありません
what to do
何をすべきか
so keep going
だから続けてください
Not just male breast cancer, but female breast cancer
男性乳がんだけでなく女性乳がんも
Let's look at breast cancer in boys
男児の乳がんについて見てみましょう
Liver cancer ranks first among male breast cancers
男性の乳がんでは肝臓がんが第1位
The incidence of liver cancer is gradually decreasing
肝臓がんの発生率は徐々に減少しています
Why is the incidence of liver cancer gradually decreasing now?
なぜ現在、肝臓がんの発生率は徐々に減少しているのでしょうか?
Thanks to the famous Professor Bisley
有名なビズリー教授に感謝します
in 1981
1981年に
He followed a group of more than 20,000 people from Taiwan
彼は台湾からの2万人以上のグループを追跡した
turn out
消す
b Incidence of liver cancer in the generation of the liver
b 肝臓の世代における肝臓がんの発生率
During this 15-year track
この15年の軌跡の中で
Not more than 200 times that of forced liver
強制肝臓の200倍以下
Liver Generation
肝臓の生成
relationship with liver cancer
肝臓がんとの関係
In fact, there is another important discovery
実はもう一つ重要な発見がありました
It is discovered that this liver B can be vertically transmitted
この肝臓Bは垂直感染することが判明
Can be passed from mother to child
母から子へ受け継がれる可能性がある
Therefore, we can predict that the incidence of liver cancer will gradually decrease after vaccination
したがって、ワクチン接種後、肝臓がんの発生率は徐々に減少すると予測できます。
But why is it still so high?
しかし、なぜまだこんなに高いのでしょうか？
At that time, it is worth mentioning a recent study by our Vice President Chen
その際、チェン副社長による最近の研究に言及する価値があります。
Except liver B
肝臓Bを除く
What is another important risk factor for liver cancer?
肝臓がんのもう一つの重要な危険因子は何ですか?
Hepatitis C
C型肝炎
Hepatitis virus A, B, C, D keeps going
A型、B型、C型、D型肝炎ウイルスは感染を続けています
Beyond Hepatitis B
B型肝炎を超えて
following a hepatitis C virus
C型肝炎ウイルス感染後
It's just a very important event.
それだけとても大切なイベントなのです。
This is a great student of Vice President Chen
この人は陳副学部長の素晴らしい生徒です
Dr. Mi Hyun Lee
イ・ミヒョン博士
A study published in the world's most prestigious cancer journal last year
昨年、世界で最も権威のあるがん専門誌に研究結果が掲載されました
It’s long-term tracking, how much tracking, and ten years of tracking to see what to say
長期的な追跡、どの程度の追跡、そして何を言うかを見るには10年間の追跡です
Hepatitis C very high Hepatitis C very low
C型肝炎が非常に高い C型肝炎が非常に低い
Hepatitis C undetectable or no hepatitis C at all
C型肝炎が検出されないか、C型肝炎がまったく検出されない
divide it into four groups
4つのグループに分ける
you did find
あなたは見つけました
Ten years ago, the group with the highest Qixing Qiannian
10年前、Qixing Qiannianが最も高かったグループ
Indeed, compared with the following three groups
実際、以下の3つのグループと比較すると、
Ten years after Ganya, the occurrence rate of Ganya is much higher
ガンヤから10年後、ガンヤの発生率はさらに高くなっています
no doubt
間違いない
tell us again
もう一度教えてください
Infection in Qixing Qiannian is Taiwan
七星銭の感染は台湾
Ganya is a very important factor
ガンヤは非常に重要な要素です
But let's look at this picture again
しかし、もう一度この写真を見てみましょう
the same story happened again
また同じ話があった
you said very high
あなたはとても高いと言いました
is relative to 14.71, relative to 6.4, relative to 1.1
14.71 との相対、6.4 との相対、1.1 との相対
High compared to 0.4
0.4と比較して高い
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
Let's say I'm the Great Plainsman of Xigan
私が西ガンの大平原民だとしましょう
I'm afraid to say it when I see this
これを見たら言うのが怖い
This assumption I am very high
この仮定は非常に高いです
then i'm scared
それから私は怖いです
Will you get Gan Ya after ten years?
10年後にガンヤを手に入れることができますか？
But everyone see
でもみんな見てる
14.1 will also get Gan Ya
14.1 には Gan Ya も追加されます
what the representative said
代表が言ったこと
85% of the high Xigan Dayuan people after ten years
10年後、西崗大園の高層住民の85％
Still won't get Gan Ya
まだガンヤは手に入らない
what are you afraid of
あなたが恐れているのは何ですか
Most Xigan people will not get Ganya
ほとんどの西ガン住民はガンヤに罹らないだろう
So the story just now came again
それでさっきの話がまた戻ってきました
Can Xi Gan do it?
シ・ガンはそれができるだろうか？
of course do not do
もちろんしません
But can he explain
でも彼は説明できるだろうか
All of the Peerless Diseases
比類のない病気のすべて
can't
できない
And peerless
そして比類のない
Most people with western liver disease will not get liver cancer
西洋肝疾患患者のほとんどは肝臓がんにならない
Just now the story happened again
たった今、また話が始まりました
What about the diet?
ダイエットについてはどうですか？
these things are not important
これらのことは重要ではありません
let's do that
そうしよう
put these things don't smoke
タバコを吸わないものを置いてください
Don't drink, don't be sick wolf
飲まないでください、病気にならないでください、オオカミ
Then you say smoking is good?
じゃあ喫煙は良いって言うの？
Of course smoking is bad
もちろん喫煙はダメです
Smoking is four times more likely to get lung cancer than non-smoking
喫煙は非喫煙に比べて肺がんになる確率が4倍高い
Among those 100 lung cancer patients
その100人の肺がん患者の中には
There are 80 smokers
喫煙者は80名です
so smoking is bad
だから喫煙は悪いことだ
That's why that Sister Sun Yue asked us to say
だからこそ、あの孫悦姉妹は私たちにこう言いました。
Ah, don't smoke
ああ、タバコは吸わないでください
But you ask people to quit smoking
でもあなたは人々に禁煙を求めます
what people think
人々が何を考えているか
Guess everyone
みんな推測してください
100 smokers
喫煙者100人
In the end, how many people got liver cancer?
結局何人が肝臓がんになったのでしょうか？
In fact only how much
実際にはいくらだけ
That is to say
つまり
You tell people to quit smoking
あなたは人々に喫煙をやめるよう言います
Why don't people quit smoking
なぜ人々は喫煙をやめないのか
Because 85% of people who smoke will not get liver cancer
喫煙者の85％は肝臓がんにならないからです
It's the same story as before
さっきと同じ話だよ
Therefore these things
したがって、これらのこと
fully tell everything
すべてを完全に話す
occurrence of disease
病気の発生
Although
それでも
risk factors matter
危険因子が重要
But these risk factors seem to explain only a fraction of the disease
しかし、これらの危険因子は病気の一部しか説明できないようです
It's not just the disease that happens
病気だけが起こるわけではない
It's not just cancer
癌だけじゃないよ
The same goes for other chronic diseases.
他の慢性疾患についても同様です。
Here you can see that it is the diabetes we are talking about.
ここで、私たちが話しているのは糖尿病であることがわかります。
what is diabetes about
糖尿病とは何ですか
The doctor must have told his patient
医者は患者にこう言ったに違いない
Ah, your medicine doesn't work
ああ、薬が効かない
what is the best medicine
一番良い薬は何ですか
lose weight first
まず体重を減らす
because
なぜなら
Everyone, what you have seen
みなさん、見てきたものは
What about the horizontal axis?
横軸はどうでしょうか？
is what we call the obesity index
私たちが肥満指数と呼んでいるものです
square your weight
体重の二乗
What about the heavy shaft?
重いシャフトはどうでしょうか？
It is the percentage of occurrence of diabetes
糖尿病の発症率です
what about blue
青はどうですか
a diabetic patient
糖尿病患者
what about white
白はどうですか
just normal
ただ普通の
so-called non-diabetic people
いわゆる非糖尿病の人たち
Then just say it
それならそれを言ってください
blue is to the right of white
青は白の右側にあります
It's the blue diabetic patient
青い糖尿病患者です
his body mass index
彼のBMI指数
Distribution of the obesity index
肥満指数の分布
fatter than average
平均より太っている
So this is what doctors often say
医者はよくこう言います
The best medicine is to lose weight first
一番の薬はまず体重を減らすことだ
But now medicine is definitely not saying this
しかし今、医学は決してそうは言っていません
unimportant
不重要
what medicine sees now
医学は今何を考えているのか
the following
以下
you see blue people
青い人が見えますね
Some people are also below BMI22.5
BMI22.5未満の人もいます
that's light
それは軽いです
Why Not Everyone With Diabetes
なぜ全員が糖尿病ではないのか
overweight
太りすぎ
the same reason
同じ理由
to ask someone to lose weight
人に体重を減らすように頼むこと
Why do people want to lose weight?
なぜ人は痩せたいと思うのでしょうか？
there are a lot of people
人がいっぱいいます
you see white
白が見えますね
There are a lot of people whose BMI is above 30 or 35
BMIが30か35を超える人はたくさんいます
But not all overweight people
しかし、すべての太りすぎの人がいるわけではありません
will get diabetes
糖尿病になります
The story just came again
話がまた戻ってきました
occurrence of disease
病気の発生
occurrence of lung cancer
肺がんの発生
occurrence of breast cancer
乳がんの発生
occurrence of liver cancer
肝臓がんの発生
occurrence of diabetes
糖尿病の発症
Tradition matters
伝統は重要
But these factors
しかし、これらの要因
Cannot explain all disease occurrences
すべての病気の発生を説明することはできません
let's take a step back
一歩下がってみましょう
disease treatment
病気の治療
For example, for a girl
たとえば女の子の場合
she started saying
彼女は言い始めた
will i get
もらえますか
why do you get
なぜ得られるのですか
These things were mentioned to you just now
これらのことは今あなたに話しました
what to do after you get it
手に入れた後はどうするか
how to treat
治療方法
what method to use to be effective
どのような方法を使えば効果的か
Also faced the same problem just now
ちょうど今同じ問題に直面しました
for example
例えば
in terms of breast cancer
乳がんに関しては
Because this is what I know best
それは私が一番よく知っていることだから
among breast cancer
乳がんの中でも
I just talked about Hormon himself
私は今、何孟自身について話しました。
Hormon itself can promote cell proliferation
ホルモン自体が細胞増殖を促進する可能性がある
Promoting cell proliferation leads to cancer
細胞増殖の促進はがんの原因となる
How does the hormone promote cell proliferation
ホルモンはどのようにして細胞増殖を促進するのか
It is He Meng, the green part that everyone sees
誰が見ても緑色の部分が何蒙です
There is a hormone receptor on the surface of our Wufang cells
私たちの五方細胞の表面にはホルモン受容体があります
two connected together
二つがつながっている
Hormonal receptors are like a medicine stone hole
ホルモン受容体は薬石の穴のようなもの
Hormon is like a medicine stone
ホルモンは薬石のようなもの
Once opened, the cells start to grow randomly
開封すると細胞がランダムに増殖し始める
So there is a medicine
だから薬もあるよ
That medicine is a very good medicine
その薬はとても良い薬です
It's called Tamasifen
タマシフェンといいます
It can treat a patient with female cancer
女性がん患者の治療に使用できる
how it cures
どのように治るのか
Its treatment method is very simple and clear
治療方法は非常にシンプルかつ明確です
it's the medicine
それは薬です
I will go with Hormon to grab the Hormon acceptor
ホルモンアクセプターを掴みにホルモンと一緒に行きます
Assuming this receptor is taken away by drug
この受容体が薬物によって奪われたと仮定すると、
This He Meng will not follow this
この何孟はこれに従わない
This acceptor is connected
このアクセプタは接続されています
so the cells do not proliferate
細胞が増殖しないように
So here is one way
そこで、ここに一つの方法があります
But what are the disadvantages of using Tamasifen
しかし、タマシフェンを使用することの欠点は何ですか
it's a cheap
安いです
medicine with few side effects
副作用の少ない薬
But it took two
でも2回かかった
After three years, the infection will become resistant
3年経つと感染症に耐性ができるようになる
Even some people start Tamasiva
タマシバを始める人もいる
it doesn't seem to work
うまくいかないようです
So that tumor can be said to be
その腫瘍は次のように言えます
Don't worry, there's another pill now
心配しないでください、今は別の薬があります
It's called Lephtharol
レフタロールといいます
This drug goes a different way
この薬は違う方向に進みます
In this way, we call it the bird thief and the first bird king
こうやって鳥泥棒と初代鳥王と言うのです
how to say
どのように言って
It is aimed at the girls after the poultry essence
チキンエッセンス後の女の子向けです
After Lephtharol is special about what is poultry essence
レフタロールが家禽エキスとは何かについて特別な後
It's just that warm tides don't produce hormones
暖かい潮流ではホルモンが生成されないだけです
Warm tides do not produce hormones
暖かい潮流はホルモンを生成しない
It's not that we don't have hormones in our bodies
私たちの体内にホルモンがないわけではありません
Because we just said that hormones come from fat
ホルモンは脂肪から来ると言いましたから
So the hormones before the poultry essence
鶏肉エッセンスの前にホルモン
will accumulate in our adipose tissue
私たちの脂肪組織に蓄積されます
Once the poultry essence, these past accumulated
かつて家禽のエッセンスが蓄積されたこれらの過去
is released by an enzyme
酵素によって放出される
That enzyme is called Aromatase
その酵素はアロマターゼと呼ばれています
will put past poultry essence before
前に過去の鶏肉エッセンスを入れます
The accumulated hormones are affected by Aromatase
蓄積されたホルモンはアロマターゼの影響を受ける
It will be converted into hormonal bird essence and then used
鳥ホルモンエッセンスに変換されて使用されます。
That is the pharmacological mechanism of creating this medicine
この薬が生まれる薬理学的メカニズム
It is to give this converted enzyme to
この変換酵素を与えるのが
block him
彼をブロックする
Of course that's what I just said
もちろんそれは私が今言ったことです
Qin thief pre-Qin king
秦の盗賊、秦王以前
After putting the whole Pingjin, the source of Horrer Horrer
平津全体を入れた後、ホラーホラーの源
After blocking
ブロック後
Of course the hormones are less
もちろんホルモンも減ります
cells will not rot
細胞は腐らない
Then of course the cancer can be controlled
そうすれば当然癌は制御できる
Then you have to use Qin thief and Qin king's trick
それなら秦盗賊と秦王の策略を使うしかない
Or use the trick of grabbing the position
あるいはポジションを掴むという技を使う
According to our common sense
私たちの常識によれば
It should be more effective
もっと効果があるはずだ
Because it was blocked from the beginning
最初からブロックされてるから
Because here is still going to grab
ここはまだ掴むつもりだから
sometimes win sometimes lose
勝つこともあるし負けることもある
But here is the source of fundamental hormones
しかし、基本的なホルモンの源はここにあります
After blocking
ブロック後
Of course it's less likely to get breast cancer
もちろん乳がんになる可能性も低くなります
real
本物
Indeed, judging from the five-year clinical trials conducted in the United States
確かに、米国で行われた5年間の臨床試験から判断すると、
This is the incidence of breast cancer
これが乳がんの発生率です
after another year
さらに一年後
In the Tamasibon group just now
ただいまタマシボングループにて
just now
ちょうど今
The one who grabbed the position in this group
このグループでポジションを掴んだのは
The breast cancer recurrence rate is
乳がんの再発率は、
That 13.6%
その13.6%
But the group of Qin bandits before the king of Qin is 10.3%
しかし、秦王の前の秦賊のグループは10.3％です
Indeed, the group of Qin bandits and pre-Qin kings is more effective
確かに、秦の盗賊と秦以前の王のグループの方が効果的です。
But you ask a patient and a surgeon
しかし、あなたは患者と外科医に尋ねます。
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
Does train meat work?
トレインミートは効果がありますか？
Of course it works
もちろん機能します
in October 2009
2009年10月に
start health insurance
健康保険を始める
But train meat has a lot of sequelae
でもトレインミートには後遺症がたくさんある
why
なぜ
That's what a lot of older girls want
それは多くの年上の女の子が望んでいることです
girls get sick
女の子は病気になる
called menopause
更年期障害と呼ばれる
how is it
どうですか
Hormones are a good thing.
ホルモンっていいものですね。
Hormones regulate body temperature
ホルモンは体温を調節する
Hormones prevent bone transport
ホルモンが骨の輸送を妨げる
so some girls
それで何人かの女の子が
after her menopause
彼女の閉経後
Just after the warm tide stopped giving birth
暖かい潮が出産を止めた直後
after menopause
閉経後
flushing throughout the day
一日中フラッシング
I feel that face is dirty all day long, as if I have a fever
一日中顔が汚くて熱があるみたい
Then there will be bone transport
それから骨の輸送があります
Then you use an artificial way now
じゃあ今度は人為的な方法を使うんだね
Block this too
これもブロック
The source of the hormone is not
ホルモンの供給源はそうではありません
Of course after menopause
もちろん閉経後も
It's serious
深刻です
So after the train meat is used
なのでトレインミートが使われた後は
My good friend from Chang Gung Hospital
長庚病院からの私の親友
Director Chen Xinshe said
陳新社監督はこう語った。
what joint pain
何の関節痛ですか
bone transport
骨の輸送
Flushing
フラッシング
Tired
疲れた
headache side effects
頭痛の副作用
will make many patients
多くの患者を作ることになる
Can’t bear it, it’s just a serious stop and stop task group.
耐えられない、それはただの深刻な停止と停止のタスクグループです。
What to do then he said please bear with me
それでどうすればいいのかと彼は言いました、我慢してください
Unfortunately, Zeng Qingshe is a boy.
残念なことに曾清社は男の子です。
Didn't he know just now that you can't work, stop the task group?
彼は今、あなたは仕事ができない、ミッショングループをやめることを知らなかったのですか？
what a pain
なんという痛み
So the same reasoning comes
したがって、同じ推論が成り立ちます
what about that girl
あの女の子はどうですか
It's better to choose one
どちらかを選んだ方が良い
but more side effects
しかしさらなる副作用
or choose a comparison
または比較を選択してください
not so good
あまりよくない
medicine with less side effects
副作用の少ない薬
This is also a problem
これも問題です
same treatment strategy
同じ治療戦略
But every choice
しかし、どの選択も
It seems that there is no fixed answer
決まった答えはないようです
I just talked about TOMASKIN
トマスキンについて話しました
It doesn't matter if the super meat is effective
スーパーミートが効くかどうかは関係ない
some medicine
いくつかの薬
This is my exaggerated report in 2005
これは2005年の私の誇張されたレポートです
That is, there is a doctor at National Taiwan University Hospital who said
それは、国立台湾大学病院の医師がこう言ったということです。
We have high cholesterol now
私たちは今コレステロール値が高いです
But what?
でも何？
The so-called lipid-lowering drugs we take
私たちが服用するいわゆる脂質低下薬
100% take basic medicine
基本薬を100%服用
Everything you eat is free
食べるものはすべて無料です
It's useless to eat everything
全部食べても無駄だよ
Just now you said that the super meat is still effective.
先ほど、スーパーミートはまだ効果があるとおっしゃいました。
Some medicines have no effect at all
全く効果のない薬もある
That didn't work at all. It doesn't matter.
それはまったくうまくいきませんでした。それは問題ではありません。
what's more serious
もっと深刻なことは何ですか
There will be drug damage
薬害もあるだろうし
Some medicines can also cause serious
薬によっては重篤な症状を引き起こす可能性もある
that allergic reaction
そのアレルギー反応
Our Department of Health has a foundation
私たちの保健省には基盤があります
It's called that medicine, that relief.
それはその薬、その治療法と呼ばれています。
the Drug Injury Relief Committee
薬害救済委員会
After counting
数えた後
8 From 1999 when he founded to 2011
8 1999年創業から2011年まで
A total of 705 successfully appealed cases
合計705件の控訴が成功した
Among them, the first place is 305
その中で1位は305です
It's the famous Steven Johnson
あの有名なスティーブン・ジョンソンです
Stevenson Johnson
スティーブンソン・ジョンソン病
It's a severe skin allergy.
重度の皮膚アレルギーです。
it's the skin like a burn
火傷のような肌です
The whole skin turns up like this
肌全体はこんな感じになります
The skin we are talking about has a normal protective function
私たちが話している皮膚には正常な保護機能があります
If you must turn it up
音量を上げる必要がある場合
It's easy to get infected
感染しやすい
The drug rash that covered the whole body
皮がむけ全身を覆った薬疹
So what medicine should I take
それで、何の薬を飲めばいいですか
Some medicines work and some medicines don't
効く薬もあれば効かない薬もある
drugs that don't work sometimes
時々効かない薬
can also cause severe allergic reactions
重度のアレルギー反応を引き起こす可能性もあります
what to do
何をすべきか
Therefore these things
したがって、これらのこと
Now is the problem that medicine is facing now
今、医療が直面している問題は
from the beginning we just said
最初からただ話しただけ
Can a nun get breast cancer?
修道女が乳がんになることはありますか?
Tell us that privacy is important
プライバシーが重要であることを教えてください
But privacy can't explain the whole of the decision.
しかし、プライバシーだけでこの決定の全体を説明することはできない。
occurrence of disease
病気の発生
disease progression
病気の進行
disease treatment
病気の治療
full of differences from person to person
人によって違いがいっぱい
those factors are important
それらの要素は重要です
However, these factors do not seem to be able to explain
しかし、これらの要因は説明できないようです
all diseases
すべての病気
So we physicians say
そこで私たち医師はこう言います
Then can we tailor-made
じゃあオーダーメイドできるのかな
like a tailor
仕立て屋のように
Of course we are now ours
もちろん、私たちは今、私たちのものです
When you go shopping for clothes, there are
服を買いに行くとき
small has medium, has s, has m, has l
小は中、sはある、mはある、lはある
It's us who come to match the look of this dress
このドレスの見た目に合わせるのは私たちです
that's that
それはそれです
That rich man they don't go with everyone
あの金持ちはみんなとは行かない
Which department store buys m or l
M または L を購入するのはどのデパートですか
he will ask a tailor to come to his house
彼は仕立て屋に家に来てもらうつもりだ
Tailored for him
彼に合わせた
according to his figure
彼の姿によると
Sin fits him and don't fit m and won't divide into l
罪は彼に適合しますが、mには適合せず、lに分割されません
He only needs the medicine that suits his figure
彼の体型に合った薬だけが必要です
Thus the concept of personalized medicine was born
こうして個別化医療という概念が生まれました
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
that privacy is important
プライバシーは重要だということ
But can't explain the disease
でも病気は説明できない
Is the overall progression of the disease critical?
病気の全体的な進行は重大ですか?
What kind of medicine to take? Will the treatment have any side effects?
どのような薬を服用しますか?治療に副作用はありますか?
Then can we adapt to each person's different situation?
では、一人ひとりの異なる状況に適応できるのでしょうか？
Tailored for him
彼に合わせた
The best strategy for the treatment of disease progression
病気の進行を治療するための最良の戦略
So that's what we're going to tell you tonight
それが今夜私たちが皆さんにお伝えすることです
Personalized medicine is based on the individual
オーダーメイド医療は個人に基づいたものです
disease prevention or treatment
病気の予防または治療
In other words, as far as it is concerned, it is called prescribing the right medicine
言い換えれば、それに関する限り、それは正しい薬を処方すると呼ばれます
Prescribe the right medicine, okay?
適切な薬を処方してください。
Of course yes, for the same disease
もちろん同じ病気です
Giving the same medicine is what we have in mind
同じ薬を与えることが私たちの考えです
In this medicine, the vast majority of people are effective
この薬は大多数の人に効果があります
But some people have no effect
でも効果が出ない人もいる
Some people even seriously hear the sound of death
死の音を真剣に聞く人もいる
Well, personalized medicine is just like that.
まあ、個別化医療というのはそういうものです。
We want to be able to drug people
私たちは人々に麻薬を投与できるようにしたいのです
It is equal to consider that people are different from each other
人はお互いに違うと考えるのは平等だ
Why are people different? Vice President Chen just said
人々はどのように違うのでしょうか? チェン副社長は先ほど言いました
It's not the same as physique
体格と同じではない
Some people are expensive to smoke
タバコを吸うとお金がかかる人もいる
Some people will not be expensive if they smoke for a lifetime
一生喫煙してもお金がかからない人もいる
Can each person's physical factors be considered first?
人それぞれの身体的要因を第一に考えられるでしょうか？
Then, after taking physical factors into consideration
次に、物理的要因を考慮した上で、
decide later
後で決める
It is established that progression is the best strategy for treatment
進行が最良の治療戦略であることが確立されている
what is physique
体格とは何ですか
it's genetic
それは遺伝的です
It's where people are different
そこが人々と違うところだ
Consider each person's genetic status
それぞれの人の遺伝的状態を考慮する
to decide who should eat
誰が食べるかを決める
Who should take this medicine
この薬を服用すべき人
that medicine
その薬
So this is the concept of so-called personalized medicine
これがいわゆる個別化医療の概念です
From prescribing the right medicine to prescribing people
適切な薬の処方から人々への処方まで
Treatment for disease progression
病気の進行に対する治療
make better predictions
より良い予測をする
So you've all learned about genetics before
皆さんは遺伝学について学んだことがありますか
We all know what a gene is
私たちは遺伝子が何であるかを知っています
Of course I'm the one here
もちろんここにいるのは私です
That class is doing a lot of work.
そのクラスはたくさんの仕事をしています。
what is gene
遺伝子とは何ですか
Genes are in our body
遺伝子は私たちの体の中にあります
The ruler of any life center
あらゆる人生の中心の支配者
inside our body
私たちの体の中に
Let's look at the following
以下を見てみましょう
inside everyone's body
みんなの体の中に
It is composed of individual cells
個々の細胞から構成されています
The composition of everyone is the same
全員の構成が同じ
So our body is like a house
つまり、私たちの体は家のようなものです
our house
私たちの家
is a maximum of ten trillion cells in a house
家の中には最大10兆個の細胞がある
Every cell is constantly being renewed
すべての細胞は常に更新されています
What is the master in the cell?
独房の中の主人とは何ですか？
inside each of our cells
私たちの細胞のひとつひとつの中に
where a commander in chief lives
最高司令官が住んでいる場所
the president's house
大統領の家
That place is called the cell box
その場所はセルボックスと呼ばれます
you take out the cell box
あなたは携帯ボックスを取り出します
It's what we learned in middle school biology
それは中学校の生物で習ったことです
are called chromosomes
染色体と呼ばれます
What are chromosomes?
染色体とは何ですか?
we used to carry
私たちはいつも持ち歩いていました
We humans have 23 pairs of chromosomes
私たち人間には23対の染色体があります
every cell is the same
どの細胞も同じです
Of the 23 pairs of chromosomes
23対の染色体のうち、
half from dad
半分はお父さんから
half from mom
半分はお母さんから
Chromosomes are like balls of yarn
染色体は毛糸玉のようなもの
Once you pull the yarn inside the yarn ball
毛糸玉の中で糸を引っ張ると、
That's what high school students learn now
それが今の高校生の習い事だ
It's what we call genes
それは私たちが遺伝子と呼ぶものです
That's what we call DNA
それが私たちがDNAと呼ぶものです
why
なぜ
In our 23 pairs of chromosomes
私たちの23対の染色体には
It is among the 46 balls of yarn
毛糸46玉の中です
There are 30,000 genes in total
遺伝子は全部で3万個ある
There are 3 billion nuclei
原子核は30億個ある
how to say this sentence
この文をどう言うか
What is 30,000 genes
3万個の遺伝子とは
Then I am also a tiger.
それなら私も虎です。
that is
あれは
in our body
私たちの体の中で
The achievement of any physiological phenomenon is protein
あらゆる生理現象の実現はタンパク質です
Proteins that fight on the front lines, such as
など、最前線で戦うタンパク質。
I see a dog wants to pet me, I want to run faster
犬が私を撫でたがっているようだ、もっと早く走りたい
How can I run faster? My kidneys
どうすればもっと速く走れるでしょうか? 私の腎臓
My kidneys are pumping out adrenaline
腎臓がアドレナリンを分泌している
contract my muscles
筋肉を収縮させる
let me run faster
より速く走らせてください
So adrenaline is a protein
つまりアドレナリンはタンパク質です
or the one just now
あるいは今のもの
That stuff is delicious, my stomach is going to produce acid
あれはおいしいよ、お腹から酸が出そう
Stomach acid is also a protein
胃酸もタンパク質です
The achievement of any physiological phenomenon depends on
あらゆる生理学的現象の達成は、
protein to do
やるべきプロテイン
But
しかし
People who fight on the front line don't always obey orders
最前線で戦う人は必ずしも命令に従うわけではない
What is the total eating order? What I just said
合計の食べる順番は何ですか?今言ったこと
A cell inside a cell and a ball of yarn inside
細胞の中の細胞とその中に毛糸玉
DNA inside
内部のDNA
Why? Because we often say a word
なぜかというと、私たちはよく言う言葉だからです。
It is now that junior high school students start
いよいよ中学生が始まります
Recite that sentence, what DNA does
その文を暗唱してください、DNA は何をするのか
RNA makes protein, protein expresses function
RNAがタンパク質を作り、タンパク質が機能を発現
why? because
なぜ?なぜなら
total food order in the body
体内の食物の総順序
will be based on the present
現在に基づいています
I saw a dog wanting to pet me, so
犬が私を撫でようとしていたので、
The DNA that makes adrenaline turns on
アドレナリンをオンにするDNA
DNA to itself
DNAそのものへ
as a template
テンプレートとして
make a message
メッセージを作る
Let's look at it with a simple diagram
簡単な図で見てみましょう
DNA imitates in its own message
DNAは独自のメッセージで模倣する
Make a simple piece of RNA
単純な RNA を作成する
RNA will help DNA help the general order
RNAはDNAを助け、全体の秩序を助ける
pass as orderly
秩序正しく通過する
to whom
誰に
outside the nucleus
核の外側
that is
あれは
Now it's an adrenaline rush
今はアドレナリンラッシュです
so you want the adrenaline-producing protein
つまり、アドレナリンを生成するタンパク質が必要になるのです
How to do it
どうやってするの
how to do it here
ここでどうやってやるのか
It is also what our children in junior high school started to learn.
それは中学生の子供たちが学び始めたことでもあります。
It turned out that this RNA was sent out
このRNAが発信されていたことが判明
use yourself as a template
自分自身をテンプレートとして使用する
to catch different amino acids
さまざまなアミノ酸をキャッチする
so take care of that
だからそれを大事にしてください
eat the night before
前の晩に食べる
one thousand three hundred dollars
1300ドル
number of steaks
ステーキの枚数
It's still five yuan for breakfast
朝食はまだ5元です
Nucleated eggs are useless
有核卵は役に立たない
eat into our stomachs
私たちの胃に食い込む
we'll put thirteen hundred dollars
1300ドル入れます
A few steaks or five dollars
ステーキ数枚または 5 ドル
the protein in that nucleated egg
その有核卵のタンパク質
Amino acids cut one by one
アミノ酸を一つ一つカット
that one amino acid
その1つのアミノ酸
will be based on
に基づきます
This RNA series
このRNAシリーズは
call over
呼び寄せます
therefore
したがって
DNA is different
DNAが違う
RNA is different
RNAは違う
The amino acid called is different
呼ばれるアミノ酸が違う
Amino acids are different
アミノ酸が違う
The protein produced is different
生成されるタンパク質が違う
therefore
したがって
you see the dog keeps biting you
犬があなたを噛み続けているのがわかります
you opened
あなたは開きました
adrenaline gene
アドレナリン遺伝子
made out of adrenaline
アドレナリンで作られた
You see that delicious food now
美味しそうな食べ物が見えてきましたね
You're turning on the gene for stomach acid
胃酸の遺伝子をオンにしている
It is made of gastric acid, the protein
胃酸というたんぱく質からできています
This is the basics that middle school students are starting to learn now
中学生が今から学び始める基礎はこれだ
Fundamental
基本原理
Then tell me what we just said
それなら今言ったことを教えてください
More humane liquid difference
より人道的な液体の違い
where is the importance
どこが重要なのか
because
なぜなら
everyone is human
誰もが人間です
people are the same
人々も同じです
But
しかし
This one actually has a meringue
実はこれにはメレンゲが入っているんです
what is that meringue
そのメレンゲは何ですか
The DNA in our 46 balls of yarn
46 個の糸玉に込められた DNA
99.9% the same
99.9%同じ
almost everyone the same
ほぼ全員同じ
Then you say it's so strange
それからあなたはそれはとても奇妙だと言います
Oddly enough
奇妙なことに
Didn't we just talk
ただ話しただけじゃないですか
The DNA in our body
私たちの体の中にある DNA
There are 3 billion editing teams
編集チームは 30 億人いる
you put
あなたが置く
3 billion times the remaining 0.1%
残りの0.1%の30億倍
so what
だから何
very big
とても大きい
3 billion multiplied by 0.1% is what
30 億掛ける 0.1% は何ですか
3000000
3000000
What will become of this 3 million
この300万はどうなるのか
The 3 million decided to say
300万人はこう言うことに決めた
We all have hair genes
私たちは皆髪の遺伝子を持っています
But some people have straight hair
でもストレートヘアの人もいる
someone has curly hair
誰かが巻き毛をしています
everyone has that
誰もがそれを持っています
eye genes
目の遺伝子
But some people are slit-eyed
でも切れ長の目をしている人もいる
some people's eyes just look
一部の人々の目はただ見ています
That round one doesn't look very pretty
その丸いものはあまり美しく見えません
Everyone has face genes
誰もが顔の遺伝子を持っている
But some people can make idol stars look handsome
しかし、アイドルスターをハンサムに見せることができる人もいます
But some people look like me and look very ordinary
でも、私と同じように見えて、ごく普通に見える人もいます
so these things
それで、これらのこと
Although this is 3 billion
これは30億ですが
Although in our genes
私たちの遺伝子の中に
percent
パーセント
everyone is the same
誰もが同じです
This 99.2% is 900 million
この99.2%は9億です
But this little 0.1%
でもこのわずか0.1%
You multiply 3 billion by 3 million
30億×300万を掛けます
It is decided that people are different from people
人と人は違うに決まっている
These people are different
この人たちは違います
as usual some people are taller
いつものように背が高い人もいます
some people are short
背が低い人もいる
some people are handsome
ハンサムな人もいます
some people are ordinary
普通の人もいる
some people have straight hair
ストレートヘアの人もいる
some people have curly hair
巻き毛の人もいる
Some people who smoke make them shorter
喫煙する人の中には身長が短くなる人もいます
some people
人によっては
I will regret not smoking
タバコを吸わなかったことを後悔するだろう
Some people are allergic to medicine
薬にアレルギーのある人もいる
Some people take medicine without allergies
アレルギーがなくても薬を飲む人もいる
Therefore, the current medical research
したがって、現在の医学研究では、
just want to study this
これを勉強したいだけです
3 billion times zero percent
30億倍ゼロパーセント
The nucleotide sequence of the 3 million
300万個の塩基配列
how to explain
どのように説明するか
How to decide the development and treatment of the disease
病気の発症と治療をどのように決定するか
What's more, many genetic mutations
さらに、多くの遺伝子変異
or the day after tomorrow
あるいは明後日
So this is what we have in mind
これが私たちが考えていることです
personalized medicine
個別化医療
That humanized medicine is just mentioned
先ほど触れた人間化医療について
We hope to take advantage of the fact that people are different from others
人は他人とは違うということを活かしていきたいと考えています
to explain disease
病気を説明する
disease progression disease treatment
病気の進行 病気の治療
By taking this into consideration
これを考慮すると
Differences in each person's physique
人それぞれの体格の違い
Impact of treatment on progression
進行に対する治療の影響
In fact, this concept has long been
実はこの概念は昔からある
It was in 2001 AD
それは西暦2001年のことでした
After the so-called genetic decoding
いわゆる遺伝子解読後
These 3 billion nucleotides
この30億個のヌクレオチドは
After understanding how it is arranged in order
順番を理解した上で
everyone is full of fantasy
みんなファンタジーに満ち溢れている
that is, can we
つまり、できますか
Explain that by 0.1 percent of the three billion
30億のうち0.1パーセントだと説明してください
Let's take a look at these treatments for the progression of the disease
病気の進行に対するこれらの治療法を見てみましょう
what kind of impact
どのような影響があるのか
that's unfortunate
それは残念だ
Over the past ten years or so, our efforts have not been enough.
過去10年ほど、私たちの努力は十分ではありませんでした。
It seems that the explanation is still very limited.
説明はまだ非常に限られているようです。
a few months ago this year
今年の数ヶ月前に
We are in that biomedicine
私たちはその生物医学の中にいます
The most famous journal is called cell
最も有名な雑誌はセルと呼ばれます
It means you and us scientists are not working hard enough
それはあなたと私たち科学者が十分に努力していないことを意味します
what we hope
私たちが望んでいること
It is called genomic reach to the clinic
診療所へのゲノムリーチと呼ばれます
That is to say, can the study of the genome be used in
つまり、ゲノムの研究は次のようなことに活用できるでしょうか。
clinic is clinical
クリニックは臨床です
it talks and talks
それは話します、話します
only two so far
今のところ2つだけ
Only two examples in the last year or two
ここ 1 ～ 2 年で 2 例だけ
what is the first example
最初の例は何ですか
The first example is the treatment of skin cancer
最初の例は皮膚がんの治療です
Just talking about a drug for skin cancer
皮膚がんの薬の話です
Then this drug is based on the assumption that there is no genetic allergy
したがって、この薬は遺伝的アレルギーがないことを前提としています。
may decide which one it is
どちらであるか決めるかもしれない
It's not surprising that we see this
私たちがこれを見ても不思議ではありません
In fact, we have more famous examples in Taiwan
実際、台湾にはもっと有名な例があります。
It's the broadcast that you often hear on your mobile phone
携帯電話でよく聞く放送です
just to do
ただするだけ
Targeted therapy for lung cancer
肺がんの標的療法
The medicine he talked about is called
彼が話した薬の名前は
It's called L-Resa Dark Heat Sha
その名もエルレサ・ダークヒート・シャ
Because Taiwan was long ago
台湾は昔からあったから
Professor Yang Banshi from National Taiwan University Hospital
国立台湾大学病院のヤン・バンシ教授
they joined long ago
彼らはずっと前に参加した
International long-term follow-up study
国際長期追跡調査
just found one thing
ただ一つのことを見つけた
That is to say, all lung cancer patients
つまり肺がん患者全員が
can be based on one is called
と呼ばれるものに基づくことができます
EGFR is what you hear on the radio
EGFRはラジオで聞こえるものです
performance factor
パフォーマンス要因
Is the receptor mutated?
受容体が変異しているのでしょうか？
seems to decide
決めるようです
Who should use it?
誰が使用すべきですか?
What does Ivresa say?
イブレサは何と言っていますか？
Everyone look at the upper right corner
みんな右上見てください
The upper right corner is called EGFR
右上隅はEGFRと呼ばれます
mutant group words
突然変異グループの単語
The horizontal axis is tracking
横軸はトラッキングです
4 months 8 months 12 months 16 months
4個月 8個月 12個月 16個月
The vertical axis is the patient's survival rate
縦軸は患者の生存率です
What about the gray group?
灰色のグループはどうですか？
The gray group is to eat
灰色のグループは食べることです
Irresa's group
イレーサのグループ
The black group is general chemotherapy
黒のグループは一般的な化学療法です
You can discover the hypothesis
仮説を発見できる
EGFR is mutated
EGFRが変異している
sorry i said it the other way around
ごめんなさい、逆に言ったんです
The survival rate of eating ERESA is much higher than that of not eating ERESA
ERESAを食べた場合の生存率は食べなかった場合よりもはるかに高い
On the contrary, the assumption is that EGFR is good for pigs and sheep to change color
逆に、EGFR は豚や羊の体色を変えるのに良いと考えられています。
So now a very important personalization
さて、非常に重要なパーソナライゼーションです
some concepts arise
いくつかの概念が生まれる
lung cancer is scary
肺がんは怖いです
Lung cancer can only be treated with general chemotherapy
肺がんは一般的な化学療法でしか治療できません
Chemotherapy is very large and not necessarily effective
化学療法は非常に大規模であり、必ずしも効果があるとは限りません
Can that be based on a specific
それは特定のことに基づいているのでしょうか
Advertisement for treatment, this is the so-called advertised treatment.
治療の広告、いわゆる広告治療です。
ERESA is a good example
エレサが良い例です
But he said ERESA is not available for everyone
しかし彼は、ERESAは誰でも利用できるわけではないと述べた
Because the condition of EGFR should be considered if it is assumed that it is a person with a mutation
変異のある人だと仮定するとEGFRの状態を考慮する必要があるため
Is ERESA valid
エレサは有効ですか
People who are not mutants are ERESA ineffective
変異体ではない人にはエレサは無効です
What is EGFR?
EGFRとは何ですか?
EGFR is what we just said that there is an electric spirit on the surface of every cell
EGFR は、すべての細胞の表面に電気的な精神があると先ほど述べたものです。
This electric spirit is one that receives messages from the outside world.
この電気の精霊は外界からのメッセージを受け取る精霊です。
main receptor
メインレセプター
So what is the main role of this electric spirit?
では、この電気の精霊の主な役割は何でしょうか？
outer cells say
外側の細胞は言う
If it takes longer, the electric spirit will notify the commander-in-chief in the cells and pancreas to say
それ以上時間がかかる場合は、電気の精霊が細胞と膵臓の最高司令官に次のように通知します。
please grow up
成長してください
Therefore, many patients with lung cancer just said
したがって、多くの肺がん患者はこう言いました。
Assuming that EGFR is a mutation
EGFRが突然変異であると仮定すると、
what is this patient
この患者は何ですか
His electric spirit can't play when pressed
彼の電気の精霊は押しても再生できません
Just as the false biography of the holy will said, hurry up and grow
聖遺書の偽伝のとおり、急いで成長せよ
RESA is the drug that blocks the electric spirit
RESAは電気の精神をブロックする薬です
The process of passing on the whole message
メッセージ全体を伝えるプロセス
Therefore, if EGFR is assumed to be broken
したがって、EGFRが壊れていると仮定すると、
is RESA valid
RESAは有効ですか
EGFR is supposed to be that normal
EGFRはそれが正常であるはずです
It's the RESA that doesn't work
機能しないのはRESAです
So this is a very successful
ということで、これは大成功です
The concept of personalized medicine
個別化医療の概念
For the treatment of lung cancer
肺がんの治療に
Taking into account the fact that a person is genetically different
人は遺伝的に異なるという事実を考慮に入れる
Is it EGFR positive?
EGFR陽性ですか？
Still EGFR negative
まだEGFR陰性
positive give this medicine
肯定的にこの薬を与えてください
Negative do not give this medicine
陰性の人はこの薬を与えないでください
can determine each patient's season
各患者の季節を判断できる
as far as our breast cancer is concerned
私たちの乳がんに関する限り
It is also related to this EGFR
このEGFRにも関係します
EGFR has a relative
EGFRには親戚がいます
The other name is called
もう一つの名前はこう呼ばれます
Another relative of EGF in breast cancer is
乳がんにおける EGF のもう 1 つの親戚は、
burn
燃えた
What is HR2 the same as EGF just now
さっきのHR2とEGFって何ですか？
It is also the electric spirit on the surface of the cell membrane.
それは細胞膜の表面にある電気の精霊でもあります。
That's an example of long-term tracking
これは長期追跡の一例です
base it on what was just said
今言われたことに基づいて
Hormone receptors are just mentioned
ホルモン受容体は先ほど述べたものです
see the ER
ERを参照してください
Or whether HR2 is positive or negative
または HR2 がプラスかマイナスか
Break it down into these groups
これらのグループに分類します
You can find that the worst group is the green group
最悪のグループは緑のグループであることがわかります
The horizontal axis is tracking years
横軸は年を追跡しています
The main axis is the patient's survival rate
主軸は患者の生存率
You can find out who the green group is
緑のグループが誰であるかを知ることができます
The green group is HR2 positive
緑色のグループは HR2 陽性です
Even if Dianling presses the button, it can't be squeezed out.
典玲がボタンを押しても絞り出すことができない。
So is it possible to consider a person
それで人を考慮することは可能ですか
HR2 status to give specific drugs
特定の薬剤を投与するための HR2 ステータス
Just like considering the status of a person's EGF
人のEGFの状態を考えるのと同じように
To consider whether he can give ERSR
ERSR を与えることができるかどうかを検討するため
Of course the most famous example of breast cancer is this
もちろん、乳がんの最も有名な例はこれです。
Just check the status of that HR2 first
まずは HR2 のステータスを確認してください
Now the health insurance bureau is saying
今、保険局はこう言っています。
Suppose to check that HR2 first
まず HR2 を確認するとします。
what is this thing
これはなんですか
This thing is to see a patient
これは患者を診ることです
Or look at each cell of you and me
あるいは、あなたと私の細胞一つ一つを見てください
Is the Horn Rabbit over-acting?
ホーンラビットは過剰行動ですか？
Assuming that the Horn rabbit is normal, it should be
ホーンウサギが正常であると仮定すると、次のようになります。
The Horn Rabbit given by Dad The Horn Rabbit given by Mom
お父さんからもらった角ウサギ お母さんからもらった角ウサギ
There should only be two red dots
赤い点は 2 つだけあるはずです
But look at this cancer cell
しかし、このガン細胞を見てください
Horror rabbits have so many points like this cell
ホラーウサギにはこの細胞のようなポイントがたくさんあります
On behalf of the volume of the Horn rabbit has changed a lot
代表してウサギのホーンのボリュームが大きく変わりました
The volume of Hole rabbits has changed a lot, and the power has changed several times
穴ウサギの体積は大幅に変更され、パワーは数回変更されました
Of course the cells keep growing
もちろん細胞は成長し続けます
So the NHS says
そこでNHSは言う
Assume that the patient is a Holle rabbit
患者がホレウサギであると仮定します。
If it belongs to more than two planes
3 つ以上の平面に属している場合
then specific medicines can be given
その後、特定の薬を投与することができます
Not only to see if this Horn rabbit is over-performing
このホーンウサギがパフォーマンスを出しすぎているかどうかを確認するためだけではありません
Sometimes to stain the protein of the Horn rabbit
時々ホーンウサギのタンパク質を染色するため
When the protein is dyed, it becomes brown
タンパク質が茶色に汚れる
You see this is what we say
これが私たちが言っていることです
The position of the Horn rabbit is outside the cell
ホーンウサギの位置は細胞の外です
your outside is brown brown
あなたの外側は茶色です
What about normal cells?
正常な細胞はどうでしょうか？
Normal cells should not be so concentrated
正常な細胞はそれほど集中すべきではありません
But some patients are so strong
でも患者の中にはとても強い人もいる
So for breast cancer
つまり乳がんに関しては
Horror Rabbit Positive vs. Horror Rabbit Negative
ホラー ラビット ポジティブ vs. ホラー ラビット ネガティブ
Hordu-positive people have particularly poor survival
ホルドゥー陽性者の生存率は特に低い
Can it be the same as the IRA killing against the DGA just now?
それは先ほどのDGAに対するIRAの殺害と同じことになるのだろうか？
Is there any special medicine for Hordu?
ホルドゥに効く特効薬はありますか？
Because if it is assumed to be Hordu positive
ホルドゥ陽性だと仮定すると
If it is known in advance that the patient is Hordu positive
患者がホルドゥ陽性であることが事前にわかっている場合
That should give him special medicine.
そうすれば彼に特別な薬が与えられるはずだ。
Indeed, health insurance pays for a drug
確かに、薬の代金は健康保険で支払われます
It is Hercetin hormone cancer bottle
ハーセチンホルモンガンボトルです
That is, assuming the surgical findings say
つまり、手術所見が次のようになると仮定します。
if hordu overacts
ホルドゥが過剰行動したら
you can give him a hormone cancer bottle
彼にホルモンガンボトルをあげてもいいよ
then at most one year
それから長くても1年
give him 13 times a year
年に13回彼に与えてください
He said why is the NHS so stingy?
彼は、なぜNHSはそんなにケチなのかと言いました。
So personalization together with another concept was born
そこで、別のコンセプトを組み合わせたパーソナライゼーションが誕生しました
We're all talking about targeted therapy now
今、私たちは標的療法について話しています
They say I should drug people
彼らは私が人々に薬物を投与すべきだと言う
Instead of just prescribing the right medicine
ただ適切な薬を処方するのではなく、
Shouldn't all be just the usual chemotherapy drugs
すべてが通常の化学療法薬であるべきではない
It should be seen whether each person is
それぞれの人がそうであるかどうかを見るべきです
Hercetin Hordu positive
Hercetin 荷爾杜陽性
Assuming Hercetin Hordu positive
ハーセチン・ホルドゥ陽性と仮定
Just give him a cancer hormone bottle, a cancer hormone bottle
彼に癌ホルモンのボトルを与えてください、癌ホルモンのボトルを
There are special medicines for Hordu positive
ホルドゥ陽性には特別な薬があります
But why is the NHS so bright and stingy?
しかし、なぜNHSはあんなに明るくてケチなのでしょうか？
Because of Hordu
ホルドゥのせいで
More than 60,000 yuan is a year
年間6万元以上
Health insurance will pay 800,000
健康保険では80万円が支払われます
Therefore, the National Health Insurance Bureau did not dare to open
したがって、国保局はあえて開設しなかった。
Hersetting is the first medication
ハーセッティングは最初の治療薬です
Later passed by legislators
その後議員によって可決された
after some surgeons
何人かの外科医の後
Go through a hospital and have a group
病院を通ってグループを作る
say no no no
ノーノーノーと言う
Breast cancer is now the No. 1 cancer in Taiwan
乳がんは現在、台湾で第1位のがんとなっている
You should consider individualized medicine for each individual
一人ひとりに合わせた個別医療を考える必要がある
don't say anything
何も言わないでください
Herto was given only when chemotherapy failed.
ヘルトは、化学療法が失敗した場合にのみ投与されました。
Only to hersetting
ハーセッティングのみ
make it a second medical
二次医療にする
it's too late
もう手遅れです
Should have paid for it from the start
最初から金払えば良かった
But our personalized medicine
しかし、私たちの個別化医療
Another concept is emerging
別の概念が生まれつつある
Consider the cost
コストを考慮する
Hersetting costs 800,000 a year
ハーセッティングの費用は年間80万
every disease
あらゆる病気
Everyone said, I want targeted therapy.
誰もが「標的療法が必要だ」と言いました。
Why is there so much money to build a country?
なぜ国を建てるのにそんなにお金がかかるのでしょうか？
So this is our concept of personalized medicine
これが私たちの個別化医療のコンセプトです
many derived problems
多くの派生問題
gradually came into being
徐々に生まれてきました
So in another example
したがって、別の例では
Just another example
もう一つの例
That's the example we're going to tell you
それがこれからお話しする例です
It says that in addition to targeted therapy for cancer
がんの標的療法に加えて、
Another very successful example
もう一つの非常に成功した例
It was published in March of this year
今年の3月に出版されました
Just now Vice President Chen mentioned that our Voice Institute
ちょうど今、チェン副社長が私たちの音声研究所について言及しました。
With 150 neurologists from 23 hospitals in Taiwan
台湾の23の病院から150人の神経科医が参加
Published in the most beautiful heart in the world
世界で最も美しい心で出版
This article in one man's medical journal
ある男性の医学雑誌に掲載されたこの記事
called in the past two years
過去2年間に電話した
One of the two most successful examples of personalized medicine
個別化医療の最も成功した 2 つの例のうちの 1 つ
he does one thing
彼は一つのことをします
There are three main ingredients in that thing
その中には主に3つの成分が含まれています
the first is medicine
一つ目は薬です
This drug is called Cover Masben
この薬はカバーマスベンと呼ばれます
what to treat
何を治療するか
Epilepsy and trigeminal neuralgia
てんかんと三叉神経痛
Toothache, trigeminal neuralgia
歯痛、三叉神経痛
Sometimes joint pain
時々関節痛
It is also possible to give this Cover Masben
このカバーにマスベンを施すことも可能です
it is a very effective pain reliever
それは非常に効果的な鎮痛剤です
And it can also treat the day
そして、それはまた、その日を治療することができます
Also treats bipolar disorder
双極性障害の治療も行っております
Many mental illnesses can give it Cover Masben
多くの精神疾患が原因となる可能性があります。
because it's cheap
安いから
This is the first we've seen in this study is Cover Masben
この研究で最初に確認されたのはカバー・マスベンです
What about the second one?
2番目のものはどうですか？
That is to say, this drug has a chance to cause the Steven Johnson just mentioned
つまり、この薬はスティーブン・ジョンソンが先ほど述べた症状を引き起こす可能性があります。
third factor
第三の要素
who will cause steven johnson
誰がスティーブン・ジョンソンを引き起こすのか
It's the 1502 genotype.
1502遺伝子型です。
Thus a concept arises
こうして概念が生まれる
can we check one person first
まず一人を確認してもいいですか
called HLAV1502 for
HLAV1502と呼ばれる
For example, in our lecture hall
たとえば、私たちの講堂では
Someone is 1501, someone is 1503,
誰かが1501、誰かが1503、
If someone is that 3101, don't be afraid
誰かがその 3101 なら、恐れないでください
But suppose it is 1502
しかし、それが 1502 年であると仮定します。
Had a chance to eat cabbage after this
この後キャベツを食べる機会がありました
It will be that Stephen Johnson who was so serious just now.
さっきまで真剣だったあのスティーブン・ジョンソンでしょう。
Then I'm down here
それから私はここにいる
Just use our example to tell you
私たちの例を使って説明してください
Assuming that when personalized medicine is to be
個別化医療が実現するときを想定すると、
what kind of things should we consider
どのようなことを考慮すべきか
We don't just talk
私たちはただ話すだけではありません
This 1502, then we will do genetic screening for everyone
この1502年、私たちは全員の遺伝子検査を行います
As far as the whole cabamas this leads to
カバマ全体に関して言えば、これは次のことにつながります
steven johnson's 1502 words
スティーブン・ジョンソンの言葉 1502
In general textbooks it is called
一般の教科書ではこう呼ばれています
This is a very interesting example
これは非常に興味深い例です
be able to put things that should be considered in personalized medicine
個別化医療において考慮すべきことをまとめることができる
from start to finish
最初から最後まで
So our second half will help
したがって、後半は役に立ちます
Take everyone through this process once
全員にこのプロセスを一度実行してもらいます
What is the first process?
最初のプロセスは何ですか?
In the first process, of course you have to discover
最初のプロセスでは、もちろん発見する必要があります
What kind of person eats Kabob Mas powder?
カブマスパウダーを食べる人はどんな人？
got that Stephen Johnson so
スティーブン・ジョンソンがそうだったので、
You mean that in terms of our research
私たちの研究の観点から言うと、
you are looking for related
関連したものを探しています
You have to see if the correlation is strong
相関関係が強いかどうかを確認する必要があります
This correlation-inconsistency
この相関関係の不一致
So is this correlation causal?
では、この相関関係には因果関係があるのでしょうか？
or indirectly related
または間接的に関連する
And is this factor single factor or multiple factor
そして、この要因は単一要因ですか、それとも複数要因ですか
let's look at the first one
最初のものを見てみましょう
How on earth do we find relevant
一体どうやって関連性があると判断するのでしょうか
Find related in our medicine
私たちの医療に関連するものを見つける
The easiest way is to compare
一番簡単な方法は比較することです
Comparing who eats more C-B-Z
どちらがより多く C-B-Z を食べるかを比較する
the song just now
今の歌
who will get Stephen Johnson
誰がスティーブン・ジョンソンを獲得するのか
Better to eat C-B-Z than to get Stephen Johnson
C-B-Zを食べてもスティーブン・ジョンソンにはなれません
than two groups
2つのグループよりも
let's say gene mutation
遺伝子の突然変異と言いましょう
1501 1502 1503 3501
１５０１ １５０２ １５０３ ３５０１
look at which gene variant
どの遺伝子変異かを調べてください
Will be super tall with Stephen Johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンと一緒に超背が高くなります
tantamount to saying
言ってるのに等しい
Assuming that the gene mutation
遺伝子変異があると仮定すると、
if it has something to do with the disease
それが病気と関係がある場合
Because I saw people with stomach allergies taking medicine
胃アレルギーで薬を飲んでいる人を見たので
He belongs to 1502
彼は1502に所属しています
The group of 1502
1502のグループ
people who are not allergic
アレルギーではない人
Neither belong to the group of 1502
どちらも 1502 のグループには属していません
It is indeed our Chen Yuancong
まさに我らの陳元宗です
Inspect my colleagues in the firm
会社の同僚を検査する
In 2004 the world's most famous
2004 年に世界で最も有名な
This thing discovered by Nature Tikan
Nature Tikan が発見したこれ
Let's start from the top
上から始めましょう
he checks 1502 first
彼は最初に 1502 をチェックします
Discover
発見
People who are allergic to CBZ
CBZにアレルギーのある人
just said
今言いました
this group
このグループ
of forty-four
44のうち
Generation 1502
代一五零二
compared to taking medicine
薬を飲むのと比べて
not allergic
アレルギーではありません
only three percent
たったの3パーセント
100% higher than
よりも 100% 高い
You say you are different, do you want to be strong?
自分は違うって言うけど、強くなりたい？
that three percent
その3パーセント
Then look at other positions
続いて他のポジションも見てみる
Ninety-three percent to sixteen percent
93パーセントから16パーセント
Eighty-one percent to ninety-seven and five to eleven percent
81 パーセントから 97 パーセント、および 5 から 11 パーセント
None of the other locations
他の場所にはありません
first position so strong
最初のポジションはとても強い
So this is what we just said
これが私たちが今言ったことです
must think about
考えなければなりません
And the cut kind of correlation is
そしてカットの種類の相関関係は
After that, the story is not over
その後も物語は終わらない
Are you looking at whether the correlation is causal or indirect?
相関関係が因果関係か間接的かを調べていますか?
I mean to put it in terms of what I just said
私が今言ったことを言い換えるつもりです
Just to show you this picture
この写真を見せるためだけに
I wouldn't say we saw the example
私たちがその例を見たとは言えません
This is the Vice President Chen
こちらは副社長の陳です
When I graduated from Pop with Us
Pop with Usを卒業したとき
often taken example
よく例に挙げられる
You see, people who drink alcohol will get short of breath
お酒を飲む人は息切れするのがわかります
Why do you get breathless when you drink alcohol?
お酒を飲むとどうして息切れしてしまうのでしょうか？
Actually drinkers love to smoke
実は酒飲みはタバコが大好き
Smoking actually causes asthma
実は喫煙は喘息の原因になる
Then why do you get breathless when you see people who drink alcohol?
では、なぜお酒を飲む人を見ると息が詰まるのでしょうか？
That's because people who drink have to smoke
お酒を飲む人はタバコを吸わなければならないからです
people who don't drink don't smoke
お酒を飲まない人はタバコを吸いません
What really causes asthma is smoking
喘息の本当の原因は喫煙です
So you see the relationship between drinking and asthma
飲酒と喘息の関係がわかります
is an indirect relationship
間接的な関係です
So let's ask a question
それで質問しましょう
It is the relationship between 1502 and Stephen Johnson mentioned earlier
先ほどの1502とスティーブン・ジョンソンの関係です。
Is it the indirect connection between drinking and asthma?
飲酒と喘息の間には間接的な関係があるのでしょうか？
Or something between smoking and wheezing?
それとも喫煙と喘鳴の間の何かでしょうか？
How do I do it?
どうすればいいのですか？
He said that drinkers also love foot soldiers and wolves
彼は酒飲みは歩兵や狼も大好きだと言いました
That foot soldier might actually be causing asthma
その歩兵は実際に喘息を引き起こしている可能性があります
Everyone, don't have preconceived notions
皆さん、先入観を持たないでください
Maybe the cause of the asthma is the foot soldier wolf
喘息の原因は歩兵狼かもしれない
That's why drinkers love cigarettes and drinkers love foot soldiers
だからこそ酒飲みはタバコが好き、酒飲みは歩兵が大好きなのです
then you can't figure it out
それならあなたはそれを理解することはできません
So in the end the cause of the asthma is smoking, drinking or foot soldiers
結局のところ、喘息の原因は喫煙、飲酒、または歩兵です。
Then how to clarify? The medical scientist said
ではどうやって解明すればよいのでしょうか?医学者はこう言いました。
That’s no way, you need to use other indicators
それは無理です、他のインジケーターを使用する必要があります
For example, do you see if a finger turns yellow?
たとえば、指が黄色くなっているかどうかわかりますか?
Because of smoking for a long time, the fingers will turn yellow
長時間タバコを吸っていると指が黄色くなります
Can you see if a person coughs? If you cough for a long time, you will cough
人が咳をしているかどうかわかりますか? 長く咳をしていると咳き込んでしまいます。
Can you see if a person will have oral diseases?
その人が口腔疾患に罹患する可能性があるかどうかわかりますか?
Because of oral lesions of the foot soldier wolf
歩兵オオカミの口腔病変のため
hypothetical hypothetical you can't tell
仮定の、仮定の、あなたには言えません
Smoking or foot soldier wolf is asthma
喫煙または歩兵オオカミは喘息です
Then suppose it's the foot soldier wolf that really caused the asthma
では、実際に喘息を引き起こしたのは歩兵のオオカミだったとします。
what will you see what will you see
何が見えますか 何が見えますか
Oral lesions, yellow fingers, cough
口腔病変、黄色い指、咳
No oral lesions, yellow fingers, cough
口腔病変、指の黄ばみ、咳なし
This man is breathing high
この男は息が上がっている
So it's a very simple principle of medicine
これは非常に単純な医学の原理です
You have to further distinguish
さらに区別する必要があります
who is directly related
直接の関係者は誰ですか
still healthy
まだ健康です
You are looking for more indicators
さらに多くのインジケーターを探しています
come to meet, to clarify
会いに来る、明確にするために
Who is Brother Yuan?
ユアン兄弟とは誰ですか？
Therefore, that
したがって、それは
After academician Chen and the others discovered this correlation
陳学者らがこの相関関係を発見した後
To see such a strong correlation
これほど強い相関関係が見られるとは
who is strong
誰が強いですか
But is it directly related?
しかし、それは直接関係しているのでしょうか？
So he was there
それで彼はそこにいました
That is, we look at this
つまり、これを見ます
It is the 1.502 mentioned just now
先ほどの1.502です
right here, elsewhere in the gene
ここ、遺伝子のどこかに
because he will be together
彼は一緒にいるから
Take off the water, maybe it's the gene next to him
水を取りなさい、おそらくそれは彼の隣の遺伝子です
I'm just showing you this picture
この写真を見せているだけです
that is
あれは
You can see that the position of a gene is related to the disease
遺伝子の位置が病気に関係していることがわかります
He may be reflecting his right gene
彼は正しい遺伝子を反映しているかもしれない
also left gene
遺伝子も残した
like the example i always give
私がいつも挙げる例のように
I take the high-speed rail
高速鉄道に乗ります
to Taichung, fly out of Taichung
台中へは台中から飛行機で行きます
found my friend coming in to pick me up
友達が迎えに来ているのを見つけた
I said happily in my heart, why do you think I'm coming
私は心の中でうれしそうに言いました、なぜ私が来ると思うのですか
you were so enthusiastic before
あなたは前にとても熱心でした
you run to the train station to pick me up
あなたは私を迎えに駅まで走って行きます
My friend said you change the car
友達が車を変えたって言ってた
I'm not coming to pick you up at all
全然迎えに来ないよ
He came to pick up his girlfriend
彼はガールフレンドを迎えに来た
why
なぜ
because me and his girlfriend
なぜなら私と彼のガールフレンドだから
Take the same high-speed train
同じ高速鉄道に乗ります
what does he mean
彼はどういう意味ですか
Mom and Dad gave us
お父さんとお母さんが私たちにくれた
Not sent to us one by one
1件ずつ送られてくるわけではありません
what mom and dad gave us is
お母さんとお父さんが私たちにくれたのは
Chromosomes sent to us one by one
1本1本送られてくる染色体
So you find that one of the chromosomes
つまり、染色体の 1 つでそれが見つかるのです
A certain position is related to the disease
特定の立場が病気に関係している
Maybe it's the chromosome
たぶんそれは染色体です
next to him
彼の隣に
People who take the high-speed train with me
一緒に高速鉄道に乗る人たち
maybe that's the one
たぶんそれがそれです
who my friend wants to pick up
私の友達が迎えに行きたい人
so what to do
じゃあ何をすればいいの
Divorce is just like saying
離婚って言ってるのと同じだ
Then you do a few more
それからさらにいくつかのことを行います
Therefore, the laboratory of Academician Chen Yuanhong
したがって、アカデミー会員の陳元紅氏の研究室は、
What are you doing near 1502 just now?
さっき1502付近で何をしてたんですか？
HRAR is other
HRARはその他です
I will read it to everyone
みんなに読んであげます
That's the first one above
上の最初のものです
private medicine for allergies
アレルギーの民間薬
70 vs. 46
70 対 46
looks like no difference
違いはないようです
93 against 13
93対13
90 to 4
90対4
start raising
育て始める
Change 6, 98 change 4 are very high
変化6、98変化4は非常に高い
95 becomes 13, and the relative lower one starts
95が13になって相対的に低いほうが始まる
68 becomes 16, lower
68 が 16 になり、さらに低くなります。
equal to these you can see
あなたが見ることができるこれらに等しい
Starts low, then the correlation gets stronger and stronger
低く始まり、相関関係がどんどん強くなります
To the lowest, the area where the results intersect
最下位、結果が交差する領域
The only gene is just said HRAB
唯一の遺伝子はHRABとだけ言われています
So here is to find the relevant
したがって、ここで関連するものを見つけます
may be directly related than we think
私たちが思っているよりも直接関係しているかもしれない
indirectly related
間接的に関係する
On the other hand, this correlation is in our medicine
一方、この相関関係は私たちの医学にもあります。
That means there must be so-called consistency
つまり、いわゆる一貫性が必要です
What about consistency?
一貫性についてはどうですか？
different people, different times, different places
違う人、違う時間、違う場所
The results of the research done should be the same
行われた研究の結果は同じであるはずです
Then the research of 1502 from the 2004 of Chen Academician Tang
その後、唐陳学者の2004年から1502年の研究
After publishing Nature
『Nature』出版後
Many countries in the world, including Japan, South Korea, Germany, France
日本、韓国、ドイツ、フランスを含む世界の多くの国
learn from them to do experiments
彼らから実験を学ぶ
It turned out that a very interesting thing
とても興味深いことが分かりました
Everyone look to the right first
みんなまず右を見てください
There are four regions
4つの地域があります
Including Taiwan, Hong Kong, Thailand and Washington
台湾、香港、タイ、ワシントンを含む
South China, the south of China
中国南部、中国南部
Discover
発見
CBZ with
CBZ付
Steven Johnson's relationship is strong
スティーブン・ジョンソンとの関係は強い
on the contrary
反之
What kind of Japan is our neighbor's Japan?
私たちの隣の日本とはどんな日本なのでしょうか？
South Korea
韓国
that german french
あのドイツ系フランス人
Could not find the relationship between CBZ and Steven Johnson
CBZとスティーブン・ジョンソンの関係は見つかりませんでした
Why
なぜ
here Miri is here
ここにミリがいます
Because none of these people carry 1502 at all
なぜなら、これらの人々は誰も 1502 を持ち歩いていないからです。
It is equal to that they are all 1501
それらはすべて 1501 であることに等しい
1503 3101
１５０３ ３１０１
Others wake up
他の人も目覚める
on the contrary
反之
Those strongly correlated regions
相関の強い領域
Just like us in Taiwan, like us in this classroom
台湾の私たちと同じように、この教室にいる私たちと同じように
5 out of 100 people
100人中5人
200 people have 10 people with 1502 ah
200人は1502ああで10人いる
therefore
したがって
1502 high area
1502高地
have a strong correlation
強い相関関係がある
1502 low area
1502 低域
no strong correlation
強い相関関係はない
This is another form of consistency
これも一貫性の別の形です
tell us
教えて
this
これ
Probably the culprit of the disease
おそらく病気の元凶
So it's called
それで、それは呼ばれます
You really want to personalize medicine
医療を個別化したいと考えている
Of course do some research
もちろんリサーチもします
Need some evidence
いくつかの証拠が必要です
How strong is the correlation
相関関係はどの程度強いのか
Whether the correlation is direct or indirect
相関関係が直接的か間接的か
And we don't have time to mention it to you
それをあなたに話す時間はありません
Is it single factor or multifactor
単一要因か多要因か
The first point is really just the first step
最初のポイントは本当に最初のステップにすぎません
second step
第二段階
We just compared the past and the past are more relevant
過去を比較しただけですが、過去の方がより関連性があります
But there is no actual data
しかし実際のデータはありません
Let's get to the bottom of this
この件の真相に迫りましょう
How must be the factor
要因は何でしょうか
Second, you still have laboratory evidence
第二に、実験室での証拠がまだ残っています
Then Chen Yuan has done a very good job since TV
チェン・ユアンはテレビ以来とても良い仕事をしてきた
They will come to explain first
彼らは最初に説明に来ます
why Steve
なぜスティーブ
Steven Johnson skin turns up
スティーブン・ジョンソンの肌が盛り上がる
To paraphrase the sentence just now
今の文を言い換えると
Steven Johnson is our skin cells
スティーブン・ジョンソンは私たちの皮膚細胞です
to commit suicide
自殺する
like once after suicide
自殺後に一度のように
Just bubble water, soak water a few more
水泡水泡水をもう少し作ってください
turn the whole skin over
肌全体をひっくり返す
Therefore, Chen Yuan first researched from the TV side
そこで、チェン・ユアンはまずテレビ側から調査した。
Exactly a Steven Johnson guy
まさにスティーブン・ジョンソンの男
the place where the blisters
水疱ができている場所
In the end the difference
結局のところ違いは
Where is the genetic difference
遺伝子の違いはどこにあるのか
this looks complicated
これは複雑に見えます
actually a bit of skin color
実際には少し肌色です
Three types of organizations, the first one you will see
3 種類の組織、最初に表示される組織
The blistered tissue of Steven Johnson's patient
スティーブン・ジョンソンの患者の水疱組織
He took out the tissue with blisters and the second one
彼は水ぶくれのある組織と2番目の組織を取り出しました
man of steven johnson
Steven Johnson的人
The Tissue Without Blisters by Steven Johnson
「水疱のない組織」スティーブン・ジョンソン著
Just to get blood cells as a control
対照として血球を取得するためだけに
The same person is sick and not sick, and compared to a third person
同じ人が病気である場合と病気でない場合を第三者と比較する
It is the blood cells of ordinary people, you, me, and other healthy people
それは普通の人々、あなた、私、そして他の健康な人々の血球です
Let's compare some genes related to cell suicide
細胞自殺に関連するいくつかの遺伝子を比較してみましょう
It turned out that one of the genes was called Greolizing
遺伝子の1つはグレオリゼーションと呼ばれていることが判明した
You can see that the tissue in the blister is performing better than healthy cells
水疱内の組織が健康な細胞よりも優れたパフォーマンスを発揮していることがわかります。
Or the patient's healthy cells are significantly higher
または、患者の健康な細胞が大幅に増加している
You said this is also related to cytology?
これも細胞診と関係があるとおっしゃいましたね？
Is this correlation causal?
この相関関係には因果関係があるのでしょうか？
He mentioned this kind of Greolizing here, after all, it is to extract the organization to do it.
彼はここでこの種のグレオリジングについて言及しましたが、結局のところ、それを行うための組織を抽出することです。
If you really want to see the sick place, you can really get the performance of Greolizing
本当に病んでいる場所を見たい場合は、実際にグレオリジングのパフォーマンスを得ることができます
indeed performance
確かにパフォーマンス
Show this coffee color
このコーヒー色を表示
no performance is no color
パフォーマンスがなければ色もない
The upper left corner is the place where the blister
左上隅に水ぶくれができている場所があります
The lower right corner is where there is no blister
右下隅は水ぶくれのないところです
where he gets sick
彼が病気になる場所
also found that
それも見つけました
blisters
水疱
It's not as good as being sexually expressive
性的表現には及ばない
But these are just related
しかし、これらは単に関連しているだけです
what kind of related
どのような関係があるのか
have blisters have personal sex
水ぶくれがある 個人的なセックスをする
no blisters no personal sex
水ぶくれはありません 個人的なセックスはありません
But this personal love
でもこの個人的な愛は
is it right?
そうですか？
What about Steven Johnson's causality?
スティーブン・ジョンソンの因果関係はどうなるのでしょうか？
he is doing an experiment
彼は実験をしています
just put the cells
セルを入れるだけ
One blue dyes one cell
1つの青が1つの細胞を染める
what to make him
彼に何をさせるか
bubble personalities
泡個人愛性
You see, after having some personal sex
ほら、個人的なセックスをした後
will turn red
赤くなります
red is a dye
赤は染料です
That's called Ernestine Fier
それはアーネスティーン・フィアーと呼ばれています
What is Ernestine Fierce?
アーネスティーン・フィアース・インジケーターとは
indicator of suicide
自殺の兆候
turn out to be
であった
In terms of cytology
細胞診に関しては
Cell de-soaking after personal love sex
個人的な愛のセックス後の細胞の浸漬
cells will have
細胞は持つでしょう
Aptosis kills itself
アプトーシスは自ら死滅する
Therefore, at the cytological level
したがって、細胞学的レベルでは、
proved
証明された
Personal love is the cause of cell
個人的な愛が細胞の原因となる
Causes of Aptosis
アプトーシスの原因
then you are just cells
それではあなたはただの細胞です
So he beat Glasgow to the rat organization
それで彼はグラスゴーをネズミ組織に打ち負かした
After two hours, four hours, five hours
2時間後、4時間後、5時間後
The epidermal cells of mice produce a lot of aptoces
マウスの表皮細胞はアプトースを大量に生成する
Therefore, it has been confirmed in front of zoology
したがって、動物学の前で確認されました
The blistered one that Gerasin and the patient saw
ゲラシンと患者が見た水疱
causal correlation
因果関係
So he first discovered in 2008
そこで彼は 2008 年に初めて発見しました
Why One Can Get Stephen Johnson's Molecular Gene Transfer
スティーブン・ジョンソンの分子遺伝子移植が可能な理由
The base transfer is in the vesicular tissue cells
塩基の移動は小胞組織細胞内で行われます
There are many Grassin performances
グラッサン公演が多い
The expression of these corusoids will make the cell aptoces
これらのコルソイドの発現により、細胞はアプトースになります。
But this has no answer
しかし、これには答えがありません
Because the answer we need is
なぜなら私たちが必要とする答えは
Then why eating CBZ will produce Gorax
ではなぜCBZを食べるとゴラックスが生まれるのか
more importantly
さらに重要なことには
Why only the 51502 person will behave
なぜ51502の人だけが行動するのか
The following is the result of more than a year of hard work
1年以上の努力の結果がここにあります
this hasn't been published yet
これはまだ公開されていません
Let's keep it a secret
それは秘密にしておきましょう
he first
彼が最初に
He found someone who was allergic to CVZ
彼はCVZにアレルギーのある人を見つけました
Sorry, patients who eat CVZ
CVZを食べている患者さん、ごめんなさい
take out his blood cells
彼の血球を取り出します
Treat him to the CVZ and get his blood cells out
彼をCVZで治療し、血球を取り出してください
Treat the general physiological experiment water
一般生理学的実験水の処理
It was found that these patients
これらの患者は、
His cells once processed CVZ
彼の細胞はかつてCVZを処理しました
As mentioned earlier, the performance of Glienoxyne is particularly high.
前述したように、グリエノキシンの性能は特に高いです。
Therefore, the initial establishment of CVZ
したがって、CVZ の初期設立は、
Let the cells show the causal relationship between Glienoxyne and each other
細胞にグリエノキシンと相互の因果関係を示させます
Assuming everyone will believe that
誰もがそれを信じると仮定すると、
I just talked about Glienoxyne because it causes cellular Atosis
先ほどグリエノキシンについて話しましたが、それは細胞アトーシスを引き起こすからです。
That's half the answer
それは答えの半分です
But another bigger doubt is
しかし、もう一つの大きな疑問は、
Then why only 1502 waited to take medicine to be like this
ではなぜ1502だけが薬を飲むのを待ってこうなったのか
It's not 1502 it doesn't look like this
1502ではありません、こんな感じではありません
it's better to do a study
研究をしたほうが良いです
it is written in the heart
それは心の中に書かれています
immune response in the body
体内の免疫反応
basically relying on what we just said
基本的には今言ったことに基づいています
HLA
HLA
We say that everyone has
誰もが持っていると言います
HA has HA1, HA2, 150
HAにはHA1、HA2、150があります
What is the main function of this HA
この HA の主な機能は何ですか
HA is a very important molecule that compares the difference between you and me
HAはあなたと私の違いを比較する非常に重要な分子です
we often talk
私たちはよく話します
This person will have that allergic reaction
この人はそのアレルギー反応を起こすでしょう
In other words, all organ transplants are rejected
言い換えれば、臓器移植はすべて拒否される
Why is there rejection
なぜ拒否反応があるのか
you are 1502
あなたは1502です
I am 1501
私は1501です
You kindly donate your blood to me
親切に私に献血してくださいました
1502 meets 1502
1502 と 1502 の出会い
1501 Two HAs are different
1501 2 つの HA が異なります
cause allergic reaction
アレルギー反応を引き起こす
Why
なぜ
Because HA is recognized by some immune cells
HAは一部の免疫細胞によって認識されるため
immune cell discovery says
免疫細胞の発見は言う
this is not mine
これは私のものではありません
release some hormones
いくつかのホルモンを放出する
Let cells produce aposis
細胞にアポシスを生成させる
So it thinks of one thing in its heart
それでそれは心の中で一つのことを考えます
will that
それはするだろうか
will this medicine
この薬はありますか
Will be stuck in HLA
HLAに引っかかってしまう
Let one of my immune cells follow my skin cells
私の免疫細胞の1つを私の皮膚細胞に従わせてください
It was a family
それは家族だった
My immune cells should say
私の免疫細胞はこう言うはずです
This is my own
これは私自身のものです
Will this, this, this medicine get stuck on it?
これ、これ、この薬がくっついてしまうのでしょうか？
let my immune cells say
私の免疫細胞に言わせてください
If you don't understand this thing
このことが理解できない場合
toxins
毒素
So this my skin cells will produce atosis
これで私の皮膚細胞はアトーシスを引き起こすでしょう
He came to apply for this matter
彼はこの件を申請しに来た
But after applying for this matter
しかし、この件を申請した後、
He did a very important research
彼は非常に重要な研究をしました
That is to say, everyone assumes that slightly
つまり、誰もがわずかにそれを想定しています
Those who have studied immunology in high school all say one sentence
高校で免疫学を学んだ人は皆、この一言を言います。
That sentence means
その文の意味は、
The HA of this cell shows that it has been processed by the cell
このセルの HA は、セルによって処理されたことを示します。
It's like saying we have the flu today
今日はインフルエンザだと言っているようなものだ
After the flu virus enters our body
インフルエンザウイルスが私たちの体内に入った後
will be processed by cells in the body
体内の細胞によって処理されます
After processing the flu protein
インフルエンザタンパク質を処理した後
Expressed on HA
HAで発現
Immune cells can't understand
免疫細胞に理解させない
So he thought the pill was so small
だから彼は錠剤がとても小さいと思った
Those medicines are very small
それらの薬はとても小さいです
Does it need to be processed by that cell to manifest?
発現するにはその細胞によって処理される必要がありますか?
So he did two very important studies
そこで彼は 2 つの非常に重要な研究を行いました
Also this study is also the one that hasn't been published
また、この研究も未発表のものです
The first study is to put
最初の研究は、
It's a different cell
違う細胞だよ
Putting the difference to it handles CBZ
CBZの扱いに違いを生む
handle two situations
2つの状況に対処する
The first condition is blood cells
最初の条件は血球です
The second is the blood cells or cells
2番目は血球または細胞です
The second condition is to shake the cell
2番目の条件はセルを振ることです
He's here to test the drug after all.
結局のところ、彼は薬物をテストするためにここにいます。
The relationship with this HA
このHAとの関係
Are they really strong together?
彼らは一緒に本当に強いですか？
Just shake it and it's gone
振るだけで消えます
As a result you can see that
その結果、次のことがわかります
Gave CBZ or a drug that looks like CBZ
CBZ または CBZ に似た薬物を投与した
Assuming that before shaking
振る前にそう仮定して
immune response so strong
免疫反応がとても強い
After shaking you shake this cell
振った後、このセルを振ってください
he has no immune response
彼には免疫反応がありません
represent one thing
代表一件事情
That thing is important for immunology
それは免疫学にとって重要です
that thing is to say
それはつまり
Don't take this medicine the way of traditional flu
この薬を使って従来のインフルエンザのようなことをしないでください
Traditional Flu Way
伝統的なインフルエンザのやり方
After the flu virus is eaten by this cell, it is cut into several pieces
インフルエンザウイルスがこの細胞に食べられると、いくつかの小片に切り分けられます。
Then the strong ones will stick to the HLA
そうすれば、強いものはHLAに固執します
But from this experiment, it seems that after shaking it, it disappears.
しかし今回の実験では、振ると消えるようです。
The representative said that the relationship between this drug and HLA is very slight.
担当者は、この薬とHLAとの関係は極めて軽微であると述べた。
glued together
接着された
Does not seem to require treatment by cells
細胞による治療は必要ないようです
This is the first one
これが最初のものです
to prove this
これを証明するために
He's going to treat the cells with another drug
彼は細胞を別の薬で治療するつもりだ
Called Paraformer Op.1
コールドパラフォーマー Op.1
What is the main function of the main chemical drug in this medicine
この薬の主な化学薬品の主な機能は何ですか
Let the outside of the cell build a layer of copper and iron walls
細胞の外側に銅と鉄の壁の層を構築させます
where is the purpose
目的は何ですか
keep outside things out
外部のものを入れないようにする
what's inside can't get in
中にあるものは入らない
he means
彼が意味するのは
Assuming that this drug does not need to be processed by cells
この薬剤が細胞によって処理される必要がないと仮定すると、
there will be a reaction
反応があるだろう
That means you build an iron wall
それは鉄の壁を築くということです
had no effect on the stimulation of the immune response
免疫反応の刺激には影響しなかった
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Immune response before and after dosing
投与前後の免疫反応
no difference
変わりはない
represents what
何を表しているのか
Means this medicine is not needed
この薬は必要ないということです
Run into the cell and be processed by the cell
細胞に突入し、細胞によって処理される
send it out
それを送り出す
Because you borrowed the same foot blood wall
同じ足の血の壁を借りたから
The contents should not be delivered
内容は配信してはいけません
Things outside can't get in.
外にあるものは入ってきません。
therefore
したがって
It leads to a very important basis transfer
それは非常に重要な基礎移転につながります
that is
あれは
CBG is such a small medicine
CBGはとても小さな薬です
immune response
免疫反応
Probably not the traditional flu route
おそらく従来のインフルエンザの経路ではないでしょう
It will be directly stuck on this HA
この HA に直接貼り付けられます
With this evidence
この証拠をもって
It can directly do an experiment
直接実験ができる
that experiment is
その実験は
Check the annual ability of CBG and HA
CBGとHAの年間実力をチェック
therefore
したがって
The famous result comes out
有名な結果が出ます
someone is 1501
誰かが1501です
someone is 1502
誰かが1502です
Someone 1503
誰か 1503
Someone 4001
誰か4001
Someone 5101
誰か5101
View separately
個別に表示する
CBG is the drug just now
CBGは今の薬です
or strong structure
または強い構造
Much like ECBG
ECBGによく似ています
see separately
別々に見る
The annual capacity of CBG and 1501
CBGの年間生産能力は1501
It is tantamount to directly examining the two-year
それは2年間を直接調べることに等しい。
Because since we don't directly deal with
直接取引していないので、
you can see
見ることができます
will it stick to it
くっつくのか？
it turns out
それが判明
1501 can't stick 1501
1501 は貼り付けられません 1501
Live in 103 years, live in 4001 years, live in 510 years, live in 510 years
103年後に生きる、4001年後に生きる、510年後に生きる、510年後に生きる
only what?
ただ何？
1502 is closely related to the strong adhesion of this medicine
1502はこの薬の強力な付着力と密接に関係しています
So, the mystery gradually picks up
ということで、徐々に謎が解けていきます
Why only 1502 etc. are allergic?
なぜ1502などだけがアレルギーなのでしょうか？
that is because
それはなぜですか
Everyone takes CVD medicine
誰もがCVDの薬を服用しています
But only after 1502 took the medicine
しかし、1502年に薬を服用した後になって初めて
This pill will stick to it very strongly
この錠剤は非常に強くくっつきます
1501 will be sticky, but shake it and it will disappear
1501はベタつきますが振ると消えます
1503 Shake and disappear
1503 揺れて消える
But only 1502 will stick to it strongly
でも1502だけは強くくっつく
Can't shake it down
振り落とせない
Then you stick to one cell, of course you don’t understand
それからあなたは1つのセルに固執します、もちろんあなたは理解していません
Because there is an extra piece of this kind of thing on the top
上にこんなのが余分に付いているので
Release the Genericin just mentioned to him
先ほど彼に話したジェネリックシンを解放してください
Once the Genericin is released
ジェネリックシンが発売されたら
The Apocytus just seen produced
たった今見たアポサイトスが生産された
So these bits and pieces understand the evidence
つまり、これらの断片は証拠を理解しています
Including the discovery that Genericin is a part of Apocytus
ジェネリシンがアポサイトスの一部であるという発見を含む
and Keeneb explains 1502
そしてキーネブは1502年について説明する
Why do only 1502 and so on get sick?
なぜ 1502 などだけが病気になるのでしょうか?
So found out that
それで分かったのは、
basic evidence
基本的な証拠
So for a personalized medicine
個別化医療の場合
Why is it called the most successful story abroad
海外で最も成功した物語と呼ばれる理由
You will start with the initial
イニシャルから始めます
This is then further correlated with laboratory evidence
これはさらに実験室の証拠と相関します
to find the basal rotation that it says takes place
起こっているという基礎回転を見つける
With these foundational transfers,
これらの基礎的な移転により、
We can really use it in clinical use
実際に臨床で使用できます
But clinical application is not as easy as imagined
しかし臨床応用は想像ほど簡単ではない
This is why our study
これが私たちの研究の理由です
Reasons to be in the New England Journal of Medicine
New England Journal of Medicineに掲載される理由
The reason for this being in the New England Journal of Medicine
その理由はニューイングランド・ジャーナル・オブ・メディスンに掲載されています。
definitely not that we found
決して私たちが見つけたものではありません
CBZ will cause Didi to do this because of 1502
CBZ は 1502 のために Didi にこれを行わせるでしょう
what are the details
詳細は何ですか
Discovered in 2004
2004年に発見
And the academician and his laboratory also found that the base transfer
そして学者と彼の研究室はまた、塩基移動が
One of the greatest successes of this study is that
この研究の最大の成功の 1 つは、
we really proved that
私たちはそれを本当に証明しました
Genetic Screening Before Medication
投薬前の遺伝子スクリーニング
under the right circumstances
適切な状況下で
in an appropriate clinical setting
適切な臨床現場で
Genetic screening before this medication
投薬前の遺伝子スクリーニング
Allergic reactions after anti-depressant medication
抗うつ薬投与後のアレルギー反応
then let's see
それでは見てみましょう
What does the research here tell you?
ここでの研究から何がわかるでしょうか?
This thing is known to everyone
このことは誰でも知っています
Personalized medicine is really used clinically
個別化医療は実際に臨床で使われている
is a very important thing
とても重要なことです
That is what we often say
それは私たちがよく言うことです
You have to take into account positive predictive value and negative predictive value
陽性的中率と陰性的中率を考慮する必要があります
What kind of positive predictive value negative predictive value
陽性的中率と陰性的中率はどのような値ですか
We see that the horizontal axis is
横軸が
Allergic to medicine
薬に対するアレルギー
There are two kinds of people who are not allergic to medicine
薬にアレルギーがない人には2種類いる
The heavy axis is the check
重軸が王手
1502 is positive
1502は正です
1502 is negative
1502は負です
1502 people will be allergic to medicine
1502人が薬でアレルギーになる
Than 1502 will not be allergic to medicine
1502より薬アレルギーにならない
Strong correlation
強い相関関係
we just said
私たちは今言いました
The correlation is about 1357 times
相関は約1357倍
But a strong correlation does not necessarily mean
しかし、相関関係が強いということは必ずしも意味するわけではありません。
You can use it in personalized medicine
個別化医療に活用できる
because of personalized medicine considerations
個別化医療を考慮しているため
Not so-called sensitivity and specificity
いわゆる感度と特異度ではない
What sensitivity specificity is
感度特異性とは
among people allergic to medicine
薬にアレルギーのある人の中には
How many people are in 1502
1502年は何人ですか
Among those who are not allergic to medicine
薬にアレルギーのない方の中には
How many people are not in 1502
1502年にいない人は何人いますか
Sensitivity is especially high
特に感度が高い
This stuff doesn't mean anything to patients.
こんなものは患者にとって何の意味もありません。
What does the patient care about?
患者は何を気にしているのでしょうか？
count from above
上から数えて
suppose i'm positive
私がポジティブだと仮定してください
Will I be allergic to the medicine?
薬に対してアレルギーになるのでしょうか？
assume i'm negative
私がネガティブだと仮定してください
Is it okay if I take the medicine?
薬を飲んでも大丈夫ですか？
This is the so-called positive awareness value
これはいわゆるポジティブな認識値です
Negative Awareness
ネガティブな意識
Positive Awareness Points, Negative Awareness Points
ポジティブな認識ポイント、ネガティブな認識ポイント
basically depends on sensitivity and specificity
基本的には感度と特異度に依存します
and to what extent
そしてどの程度まで
In terms of whether 1502 is allergic to medicine
1502が薬に対してアレルギーがあるかどうかについて
Positive consciousness value is ultra-low, only 5.6%
ポジティブ意識値はわずか5.6%と超低い
Only 5.6%
わずか5.6%
Suppose you are 1502 positive
あなたが 1502 陽性だとします
As far as we are concerned, there are about 10 of the 200 people
私たちの知る限り、200人中10人くらいです。
you eat CBG
あなたはCBGを食べます
He said my dentist gave me CBG
彼は私の歯科医が私にCBGをくれたと言いました
Do not worry
心配しないでください
There will really be 4 out of 100 talents and 5
実際には、100 人の才能のうち 4 人と 5 人が存在します。
95% of people are fine
95%の人は大丈夫
Then you say of course checking this is useless
それからあなたは、もちろんこれをチェックするのは無駄だと言います
But this research
しかし、この研究は
The most important thing about this TES is the negative awareness value
このTESで最も重要なことは、ネガティブな認識値です。
close to 100%
接近100%
99.9%
９９。９％
what negative district medical set value
マイナスの地区医療設定値は何ですか
if you are negative
あなたが否定的な場合
that is
あれは
Almost you don't have to worry that you will be allergic to the medicine
薬に対するアレルギーの心配はほとんどありません
is B
Bです
B plus the lower of the first cent
B加第一分之低
Just assuming you're a negative person
自分がネガティブな人だと仮定して
you probably
あなたはおそらく
Take medicine 99.9%
薬を飲む 99.9%
not allergic
アレルギーではありません
So this is for a patient
ということで、これは患者さん向けです
one thing I care about most
私が最も気にかけていることの 1 つ
I am positive can I eat or not
食べてもいいですか、食べてはいけないと確信しています
I am negative can eat can not eat
私は陰性です 食べられます 食べられません
Just CBZ and Steven Johnson
CBZとスティーブン・ジョンソンだけ
With 1502 and CBZ cited by Steven Johnson
1502年とCBZはスティーブン・ジョンソンを引用した
Although the positive predictive value is not very good
陽性的中率はあまり良くありませんが、
negative predictive value
陰性的中率
almost super high
ほぼ超高値
Once you tell people that if you are Naked
裸だと人に言うと
you can almost safely take your medicine
ほぼ安全に薬を服用できます
that's what we just said
それが私たちが今言ったことです
we are in our holy clinic
私たちは聖なる診療所にいます
in two years
2年
invited in Taiwan
台湾に招待されました
The help of 150 neurologists in 23 hospitals within two years
2年間で23の病院の150人の神経内科医の支援
A total of invited
招待された合計
4,855 patients who had the opportunity to take CBZ
CBZを摂取する機会があった4,855人の患者
Genetic screening before medication
投薬前の遺伝子スクリーニング
Decide if the assumption is negative
仮定が否定的かどうかを判断する
Said please rest assured to take medicine
安心して薬を飲んでくださいと言われました
positive?
ポジティブ？
that means please be careful
ということは気をつけてください
you better change your medicine
薬を変えたほうがいいですよ
How many are negative?
マイナスは何人ですか？
92.3%
９２。３％
positive?
ポジティブ？
7.7%
７。７％
The 7.7% said
7.7%はこう言った
please change your medicine
薬を変えてください
because
なぜなら
Although you are only 5.6%
あなたはわずか 5.6% ですが、
But
しかし
Professor Stephen is so serious
スティーブン先生はとても真剣です
you better not eat
食べないほうがいいよ
but what is important
しかし何が重要なのか
If it is negative
マイナスの場合
you can rest assured to eat
安心して食べられます
So feel free to eat if you are negative
だから陰性でも安心して食べてください
positive dressing change
積極的な着替え
Then start tracking for two months
その後、2 か月間追跡を開始します
Let's talk
話しましょう
Is it by this
これによってですか
Genetic Screening Before Medication
投薬前の遺伝子スクリーニング
Can really prevent after medication
投薬後は本当に予防できる
allergic skin reaction
アレルギー性皮膚反応
At the beginning, of course we counted
もちろん最初は数えました
masculine and feminine
男性性と女性性
Neurologists in Taiwan
台湾の神経科医
Who will drive CBZ?
誰がCBZを運転するのでしょうか？
Results Among our more than 4,800 patients
4,800 人を超える患者様の中での結果
14% are bumps
14% はバンプです
Then there is 54.14% neuralgia
次に、54.14% が神経痛です。
The vast majority of patients in Taiwan who take CBZ
台湾ではCBZを服用している患者の大多数が
One out of two suffers from neuralgia
2人に1人が神経痛に悩む
Only 14.24% of codes and
コードのわずか 14.24% と
What about other neurological symptoms?
他の神経症状についてはどうですか？
So it's just that we start with the basic data of the patient
つまり、患者の基本データから始めるだけです
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
800 people in this world do genetic screening first
世界中の800人がまず遺伝子検査を受ける
Follow up for two months
2ヶ月間のフォローアップ
Negative take medicine lightly
ネガティブ 軽く薬を飲む
If positive, ask him to change the medicine
陽性の場合は、薬を変更するように依頼してください
As a result, during these two months
その結果、この２ヶ月の間に、
Although we cannot avoid
避けることはできませんが、
It's positive and negative
男性的であり女性的です
Those symptoms such as itching
かゆみなどの症状
rash, blisters
発疹、水疱
There are different situations of mouth ulcers and itching
口内炎やかゆみにはさまざまな状況があります
among the positive
ポジティブなものの中では
among negative people
ネガティブな人たちの間では
more or less there will still be some
多かれ少なかれ、まだいくつかあるでしょう
a slightly uncomfortable allergic reaction
少し不快なアレルギー反応
itchy blisters
癢起水泡
But what?
でも何？
What we care about is the following
私たちが大切にしているのは以下のことです
but in this world
でもこの世界では
Of the 4800 patients
4800人の患者のうち
Positive patients are 0
陽性患者は0人
Negative patients are 0
陰性患者は0人
from now on
今後
no more steven johnson
もうスティーブン・ジョンソンはいない
Among the 4800 patients
4800人の患者のうち
Although we can't
できませんが
completely prevent
完全に防ぐ
The comparisons just mentioned
先ほど述べた比較
mild allergic reaction
軽度のアレルギー反応
But the worst Steven Johnson
でも最悪のスティーブン・ジョンソン
Among our 4800 patients
4,800人の患者の中から
During the two-month follow-up
2ヶ月間のフォローアップ中に
completely invisible
完全に目に見えない
so this is
それでこれは
What the New Infectious Medicine Journal said is that
『New Infection Medical Photo』誌は次のように述べています。
by pre-medication
前投薬による
1502 Genetic Screening
1502 遺伝子スクリーニング
can really avoid
本当に避けられる
Really take that CBZ
CBZを本当に取ってください
caused by steven johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンが原因
just avoid it completely
ただ完全に避けてください
He said why he succeeded
彼は成功した理由をこう語った
There are several conditions for success
成功するにはいくつかの条件があります
Although these conditions are examples of our study
これらの条件は私たちの研究の一例ですが、
But everyone is going further
でもみんなはさらに進んでいく
We have to think about it at the end and say
私たちは最後にそれについて考えて言わなければなりません
If you want to succeed as a personalized medicine
個別化医療として成功したいなら
There are several conditions
いくつかの条件があります
First
初め
The Light of Our Taiwan
私たちの台湾の光
You have to check CBZ very well
CBZをよくチェックする必要があります
then you should get checked
それなら検査を受けるべきです
Taiwan's medical and public health standards are very high
台湾の医療と公衆衛生の水準は非常に高い
It is equivalent to the clinical level of a country's public health
国の公衆衛生の臨床レベルと同等です
I have to be very tall to be qualified to say that I want to do personalized medicine
個別化医療をやりたいと言う資格を得るには、背が高くなければなりません
Otherwise, you can't even diagnose the disease.
そうでなければ、病気を診断することさえできません。
I can't figure out whether it is the drug diagnosis, the red diagnosis or the lung itching
薬の診断なのか、赤い診断なのか、肺のかゆみなのかわかりません。
How can you do personalized medicine if you can’t figure it out?
それが分からない場合、どうやって個別化医療を行うことができるのでしょうか?
so it was a great success
それで大成功でした
A very important condition of this study in Taiwan is that
台湾でのこの研究の非常に重要な条件は、
Taiwan's own medical and public health standards are high
台湾自体の医療および公衆衛生基準は高い
The following more detailed reasons, for example, the first reason
より詳細な理由は次のとおりです。たとえば、最初の理由
We're close to 100% negative predictive value
陰性的中率は 100% に近づいています
So this is a very successful drug in this study
つまり、これはこの研究で非常に成功した薬です
100% negative predictive value
100% 陰性的中率
Just assuming that's the case, take the medicine with confidence.
そうだと思って安心して薬を飲んでください。
At this point, everyone is thinking about the relationship between breast cancer and vegetarianism just now.
この時点で、誰もが今、乳がんと菜食主義の関係について考えています。
Sugar content is not related to obesity
糖質量は肥満と関係ない
Think of these positive healers, negative healers
ポジティブなヒーラー、ネガティブなヒーラーについて考えてみましょう
you will understand
あなたは理解するでしょう
why why those chronic diseases
なぜなぜそれらの慢性疾患
There is no way yet to take into account a person's genetic status
人の遺伝的状態を考慮する方法はまだありません
risk of disease to a person
人に対する病気のリスク
make a very accurate assessment
非常に正確な評価を行う
Caused by 1502 and CBG
1502とCBGが原因
Steven Johnson Negative Healers Are Only Nearly 100%
スティーブン・ジョンソンのネガティブ・ヒーラーはほぼ100％しかいない
So we can safely say
したがって、安全に言うことができます
You're Nectin you're hardly weak at any price
あなたはネクチン、どんな代償を払ってもほとんど弱いものではありません
Just go take your medicine, it's fine
薬を飲みに行ってください、大丈夫です
This is the first requirement for success
これが成功の第一条件です
Second, did he think of one thing?
第二に、彼は何か考えましたか?
When we were doing this research it was
私たちがこの研究を行っていたとき、
alone alone
一人で一人で
Deciding only after diagnosis
診断後にのみ決定する
To take medicine or not to take medicine
薬を飲むか飲まないか
You just want to die alone
あなたはただ一人で死にたいだけです
You said you have to wait, wait a day, wait two days
あなたは待たなければならないと言った、一日待って、二日待って
tell you it's positive positive
ポジティブポジティブだと言ってください
So the more successful elements of this study
したがって、この研究のより成功した要素は、
This sounds uneducated
これは無教養に聞こえる
But you're talking about clinically important
しかし、あなたは臨床的に重要なことについて話しています
Because our testing reagents
なぜなら、当社の検査試薬は
results in three hours
3時間以内に結果が出る
Send the report and delay
レポートを送信して遅らせる
Another two days
あと二日
So this also sounds uneducated
したがって、これも無教養に聞こえます
But this is also the basic spirit of personalized medicine.
しかし、これは個別化医療の基本精神でもあります。
Suppose you want to wait a year and a half by yourself
一人で1年半待ちたいとします。
just said you can take medicine
薬を飲んでもいいと言ったばかりです
People have already died of pain
人々はすでに苦しみのために死んでいる
People quit a long time ago
人はずっと前に辞めてしまった
So here's what you're gonna say
それで、あなたが言いたいことは次のとおりです
Pre-Medication Genetic Screening to Help After Medication
投薬後に役立つ投薬前の遺伝子スクリーニング
to decide whether to prevent
阻止するかどうかを決める
allergic reaction after use
使用後のアレルギー反応
This is also a very successful factor
これも非常に成功した要因です
no knowledge at all
まったく知識がありません
But we only need the patient to wait two days
しかし、患者には2日間待つだけで済みます
you can talk to him
彼と話してもいいよ
you can eat you can't eat
食べられる、食べられない
It is also a very successful requirement
これも非常に効果的な要件です
The third
第3
alternative medicine
代替医療
suppose
仮定する
Check it out and say you can't eat it
調べて食べられないと言う
what to do
何をすべきか
No way, good way, you know the pain at home
まさか、それは良かった、あなたは家の痛みを知っていますか
then why should i check
では、なぜ確認する必要があるのでしょうか
You also have a medicine called Actonative medicine
活性薬という薬もあります
You have to find another way to go
別の方法を見つけなければなりません
you have to tell people
人々に伝えなければなりません
assume you are positive
あなたはポジティブだと仮定してください
Suppose you want to change the medicine
薬を変更したいとします
what should you do
あなたは何をするべきか
assuming it's useless
無駄だと仮定して
Then why do people want to do personalized medicine?
では、なぜ人は個別化医療をやりたがるのでしょうか？
so this stuff sounds uneducated
だからこの話は無教養に聞こえる
but it is
しかし、それは
Our research shows that
私たちの調査によると、
If you really want to do personalized medicine
本気で個別化医療をやりたいなら
You need to be able to cooperate with the whole environment
環境全体と協力できる必要がある
You have to consider these seem not very knowledgeable
これらはあまり知識がないと思われることを考慮する必要があります
This is called the editor over there
あそこではこの人を編集者と呼んでいます
To a very appropriate called proper clinical setting
適切な臨床現場と呼ばれる非常に適切な現場へ
appropriate clinical configuration
適切な臨床構成
This clinical configuration includes the whole country and the whole environment
この臨床構成には国全体と環境全体が含まれます
Public health and clinical standards can match
公衆衛生と臨床基準を一致させることができる
And how strong is the relationship between the disease itself and the gene?
そして、病気そのものと遺伝子との関係はどれほど強いのでしょうか?
and the relationships just mentioned
そして今述べた関係性
So this is the third step of what we call personalized medicine here
これがここで個別化医療と呼ぶものの 3 番目のステップです
That is, you left with relevant basic evidence.
つまり、関連する基本的な証拠を残したということです。
if you really want to do it
本当にやりたいなら
You have to take into account positive inhibitory values, negative inhibitory values
正の阻害値と負の阻害値を考慮する必要があります
You also need to consider other allergic reactions caused by this disease
この病気によって引き起こされる他のアレルギー反応も考慮する必要があります
What to do about your rash, the clinically feasible approach
発疹に対して何をすべきか、臨床的に実現可能なアプローチ
Can the patient wait for two days?
患者は2日間待ってもらえますか?
Probably can't wait for two weeks, and check it out
2週間も待てないのでぜひチェックしてみてください
That is to say, our research
つまり、私たちの研究は、
Our inspection department sometimes says it is too complicated
私たちの検査部門は時々「それは複雑すぎる」と言います
I don't want to do it. Maybe he strikes with you sometimes.
たぶん彼は時々あなたと衝突するでしょう。
You do a good job of developing those test designs
あなたはテスト設計をうまく開発していますね
and the alternatives just mentioned
そして今述べた代替案
Is there an alternative? Suppose there is.
代替手段はあるのでしょうか? あると仮定します。
It's really about personalization.
それは本当にパーソナライゼーションに関するものです。
So I can’t go back to the Hershiting I just talked about
だから今話したハーシティングには戻れない
nature has revealed that clue economics
自然は経済学の手がかりを明らかにした
This sentence means
この文の意味は、
We published it in the Sexy Together journal
『Sexy Together』誌に掲載させていただきました
The best journal in the world We are very good in our hearts
世界で最高のジャーナル 私たちは心の中でとても良いです
Proud of our central PR city
PR中心都市の誇り
a press conference is about to be held
記者会見がもうすぐ開かれます
because it can be a great sight
それは素晴らしい光景になるかもしれないから
As a result, the press conference, the reporter came
その結果、記者会見、記者が来た
Reported the next day, the first media said
翌日報道された最初のメディアは次のように述べた。
This is a major breakthrough in personalized medicine, benefiting from these seven years
これは、この 7 年間の恩恵を受けて、個別化医療における大きな進歩です。
Because it is to let the foreign media say the same
海外メディアにも同じことを言わせるためだから
But everyone turned over
でもみんなひっくり返った
You go Google my name and you can find
私の名前をGoogleに行けば見つけることができます
I was scolded badly by you
私はあなたにひどく叱られました
Because the Central News Agency said a word
中央通信社が一言言ったから
That sentence really puts us in a strong mood
その文は本当に私たちを強い気分にさせます
Don't miss the butterfly, what did he say?
蝶を見逃さないでください、彼は何と言ったでしょうか？
called
呼ばれた
For three yuan of medicine, you need to do a genetic screening for three yuan and three thousand yuan
3元の薬の場合、3元と3000元の遺伝子検査を行う必要があります
During this period, we suddenly acted violently. Scientists cannot handle scientific matters.
この時期に、私たちは突然暴力を振るいましたが、科学的なことは科学者には対応できません。
You have to take into account, economics
経済性を考慮する必要があります
CBZ only costs 3 yuan for a medicine
CBZは薬代たったの3元
You want health insurance, health insurance is now almost 1502 genetic screening
あなたは健康保険が必要です、健康保険は現在ほぼ1502の遺伝子検査です
Check a 1502, health insurance costs almost three thousand dollars, is it worth it?
1502 をチェックしてください。健康保険には約 3,000 ドルかかりますが、それだけの価値がありますか?
Therefore, personalized medicine cannot
したがって、個別化医療は不可能です。
I am very proud that the dominant activity of personalized medicine is unreasonable
私は個別化医療の支配的な活動が不合理であることを非常に誇りに思っています
You have to think about the situation in a real society
現実社会の状況を考えなければなりません
Can it be accepted in the end, so when we
最終的には受け入れてもらえるのでしょうか？
Of course I can't wait, the Central News Agency's Cheng Xiao can still be broken
もちろん待ちきれません、中央通信社のチェン・シャオはまだ壊れる可能性があります
In hindsight, it's because he made us think
今にして思えば、彼が私たちに考えさせてくれたからです
Personalized medicine can't just be scientific research
個別化医療は単なる科学研究ではありえない
Not only, as I just said, pharmacoeconomics should be taken into consideration
先ほど述べたように、薬経済学を考慮する必要があるだけでなく、
Therefore, we are not experts in pharmacoeconomics
したがって、私たちは薬物経済学の専門家ではありません
Let's do the math
計算してみましょう
In the past few years
過去数年間で
How is the use of CBZ in Taiwan?
台湾でのCBZの使用状況はどうですか?
you can find
発見できる
You see these curves
これらの曲線が見えます
Dark blue and light blue are the same
濃い青と水色は同じです
is that you found that from 2002 to 2008
2002 年から 2008 年にかけて見つかったということですね
CBZ usage actually declined
CBZの使用量は実際には減少した
you think
あなたは考える
such an effective medicine
こんなに効果的な薬
So cheap, a painkiller that costs 3 yuan is so cheap
安いですね、3元の鎮痛剤は安いですね。
It's the cheapest of all medicines
すべての薬の中で最も安い
Why is it getting lower and lower
なんでどんどん下がっていくんだろう
The incidence of that Steven Jones is actually getting higher and higher
スティーブン・ジョーンズの発生率は実際にますます高くなっています
Why
なぜ
After 2004, we did not just talk about
2004 年以降、私たちはただ話し合うだけではありませんでした。
Academician Chen and the others published in the famous Nature in 2004 that
チェン学者らは2004年に有名なネイチャー誌に次のような論文を発表した。
1502 is after CBZ what caused Steven Jones
1502はスティーブン・ジョーンズを引き起こしたCBZの後のものです
Everyone dare not prescribe that medicine
誰もがその薬を処方する勇気はない
So after 2004
それで2004年以降は
CBZ has been falling
CBZは落ちてきた
you don't want to be that
そうなりたくないでしょう
It means you don't want that or that
それはあなたがあれもこれも望んでいないことを意味します
The flower of the tight pen said that I have a very good test
タイトなペンの花は、私はとても良いテストをしたと言いました
I'm telling you now that I don't do tests at all
今言っておきますが、私はテストをまったく行っていません
I just need to change the medicine.
薬を変えるだけでいいのです。
What do you have to worry about 1502
1502について何を心配する必要がありますか
Just change your medicine
薬を変えるだけ
So it prompts us to think about one thing
そこで、私たちはあることを考えるようになりました
that's where we come to see
そこが私たちが来る場所です
think of one thing is to say
一つ言うことを考えてください
Then we have to actually calculate
次に、実際に計算する必要があります
In the end personalized medicine is really used in a society
最終的には個別化医療が実際に社会で活用される
one country
一個國家
What about medical costs
医療費はどうなるの
How much does it affect
どれくらい影響するのか
that's a good point to say
それは良い指摘だ
1502, Steve Johnson
1502年、スティーブ・ジョンソン
It is mentioned in foreign textbooks one day
いつか外国の教科書に載ってしまう
This is the best example
これがその最良の例です
because of trigeminal neuralgia
三叉神経痛のせいで
are two different situations
2つの異なる状況です
In addition to CVD
CVDに加えて
there is another medicine
別の薬があります
It is neurotic, gupmenting
神経質で、ぐちゃぐちゃになっている
It's a very good medicine
とても良い薬です
gupmenting is a bit of Steve Johnson's part
ググメンテーションはスティーブ・ジョンソンの一部です
CVD is what you have to worry about is it 1502
あなたが心配しなければならないのは CVD ですか 1502
So suppose a patient in the margin
そこで患者が限界にいたと仮定します
If he wants to eat CVD
彼がCVDを食べたいなら
in accordance with current standard practice
現在の標準的な慣行に従って
you have to do it first
あなたが最初にそれをしなければなりません
You have to spend 3,000 yuan for genetic screening first
最初に遺伝子検査に3,000元を費やす必要があります
Assuming it is a network
ネットワークだと仮定すると
You can rest assured to eat CVD
安心してCVDを食べられます
Because BZ is very cheap, it only costs three yuan a day
BZは非常に安いので、1日たったの3元です。
The annual drug fee is 2300 yuan
年間薬代は2300元
So 2300 plus 3000, one year we don't care
つまり、2300 プラス 3000、1 年は気にしない
In fact, patients with epilepsy can't just watch for a year
実際、てんかん患者は 1 年間ただ見守ることはできません。
Epilepsy patients move up because they eat for a long time
てんかん患者は長時間食事をするため順位が上がる
So assuming it's CBZ plus that 1502 genetic screening
つまり、CBZ に 1502 遺伝子スクリーニングを加えたものだと仮定すると、
It costs 5300 yuan a year
年間5300円かかります
But some people say I just change the medicine
でも薬を変えるだけだと言う人もいる
why do i take this risk
なぜこのリスクを負うのか
Neurotin costs 11 yuan a piece
ニューロチンは1個11元
It costs 10,000 yuan a year to eat
食費は年間1万元かかる
10,000 to 5300 which one is calculated
10,000から5300までどれを計算するか
Of course this calculation
もちろんこの計算は
so this is
それでこれは
execute us, we are very grateful to that miss chen
処刑してください、私たちはあのミス・チェンにとても感謝しています
help us tell you
あなたに伝えるのを手伝ってください
Although you said three thousand dollars
3000ドルって言ってたけど
Three dollars will cost 3,000 dollars for a genetic screening
遺伝子スクリーニングには 3 ドルで 3,000 ドルかかります
it sounds unreasonable
それは不合理に聞こえる
But in the long run
しかし、長期的には
Epilepsy patients have to take medicine for a lifetime
てんかん患者は一生薬を飲み続けなければなりません
even if you change the medicine
薬を変えても
very expensive
非常に高価な
certainly
そうです
We don't deny assuming you have money and are willing to pay for it
あなたがお金を持っていて、それを支払う意思があると仮定することは否定しません
Willing to spend 10,000 yuan a year
年間1万円は使いたい
then you really are your business
それならあなたは本当にあなたの仕事です
But considering a country
しかし国を考えると
2,0003 plus 3,000
2,0003 プラス 3,000
And genetic screening only needs to be done once
遺伝子スクリーニングは 1 回だけ行う必要があります
Because whether we are who or not in our whole life is 1502
なぜなら、私たちが生涯を通じて何者であるかは、1502 年にかかっているからです。
If you check once you do it
一度やってみたらチェックすれば
That will have a lifetime impact
それは一生に渡る影響を与えるだろう
It is to sign a document 2,0003 2,0003 2,0003
書類に署名することです 2,0003 2,0003 2,0003
This is 10,000 plus 10,000 plus 10,000
これは 10,000 プラス 10,000 プラス 10,000
In the long run, it seems that this is relatively accounting.
長い目で見ると、これは比較的会計的なものになるようです。
This is a case of subversion
これは転覆事件です
Indeed, from the point of view of the subverted patients
確かに、破壊された患者の観点から見ると、
Although there are good alternatives to
Dianzi に代わる良い選択肢はありますが、
Can not eat CBZ
CBZは食べられない
Immediately switch to alternative medicine
すぐに代替医療に切り替える
But as things stand now
しかし、現状では
Several common alternative medicines
いくつかの一般的な代替医療
There is no accounting from CBZ
CBZからの会計はありません
should say so
そう言うべきだ
There is no calculation other than CBZ plus genetic screening
CBZと遺伝子スクリーニング以外の計算はありません
This is a case of subversion
これは転覆事件です
the second
二番目
Three margins
三差成績
Didn't we just talk
ただ話しただけじゃないですか
Taiwan does have 50% of the people
台湾には人口の50％がいる
It's because of stacking pain and three plus scores
痛みとプラス3点が重なったせいだ
So we still eat CBZ
だから私たちはまだCBZを食べています
But another story happened
しかし、別の話が起こりました
for trigeminal neuralgia
三叉神経痛に
CBG is the front line
CBGは最前線です
and there is no alternative
そして代替手段はありません
won't be like that
そんなことはないだろう
There is copamenting in that side
その側にはコパメンティングがあります
trigeminal neuralgia
三叉神経痛
CBG is the best medicine
CBGは最高の薬です
so there is no alternative
だから代替手段はない
you have to think
考えなければなりません
Another way to think about talking to people
人と話すことについての別の考え方
just think
考えてみたまえ
How much does it cost me to prevent a patient
患者を防ぐのにいくらかかりますか
and i don't prevent
そして私は妨げません
I let him go free
私は彼を自由にさせた
I use ex post compensation
事後補償を利用します
How much do you have to pay
いくら払わなければなりませんか？
we really count
私たちは本当に数えます
Steven Johnson caused by CBG
スティーブン・ジョンソンの原因はCBG
The incidence rate is about 0.24%
発生率は約0.24%
According to the data we have just demonstrated
私たちが今実証したデータによると、
can be calculated
計算できる
So let's say 1000 patients
では、患者が 1000 人だとしましょう
If multiplied by 0.24%
0.24%を掛けると
1000 are CBG's
1000はCBGです
There will probably be two Steven Johnsons
おそらくスティーブン・ジョンソンは二人いるだろう
So 1,000 people on pills
つまり 1,000 人が薬を飲んでいる
there will be two steven johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンは二人いるだろう
Those 1,000 people multiplied by the
その 1,000 人に
It costs 3,000 yuan to do a screening
検査には3,000元かかります
3000 times 1000
3000 掛ける 1000
is 3 million
300万です
3 million divided by two patients
300 万を患者 2 人で割った値
3 million divided by 2
300万を2で割ったもの
That's 1.5 million
それは150万です
he means to say
彼は言い​​たいのです
You want to prevent a trigeminal neuralgia
三叉神経痛を予防したい
People who eat CBG and get Steven Johnson
CBGを食べるとスティーブン・ジョンソンになる人
You prevent a Steven Johnson on average
あなたは平均してスティーブン・ジョンソンを阻止します
it will cost 1.5 million
150万かかります
Then suppose I don't prevent
それなら私が妨げないと仮定します
that's too expensive
あれは高すぎる
shall we accompany
同行しましょう
Let's do the math here
ここで計算してみましょう
Vital Relief Foundation
バイタルリリーフ財団
Steven Johnson has several conditions
スティーブ・ジョンソンにはいくつかの条件がある
no sequelae
後遺症なし
Some people have very serious sequelae
非常に重篤な後遺症を残す人もいます
eyes will go blind
目が見えなくなる
Of course some people will die
もちろん死ぬ人もいるだろう
The vast majority of Steven Johnson are very serious
スティーブン・ジョンソンの大多数は非常に真面目です
But 92% of people
しかし、92%の人は
In the end, the skin will be healed after half a year
結局半年もすれば肌は治る
For treating a Steven Johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンの治療について
Almost 400,000 in health insurance
健康保険料約40万
that for those who are blind
それは目の見えない人にとって
Only 0.2%
わずか0.2%
Health insurance almost 1 million
健康保険は約100万
5.26% for the unlucky
不運な場合は 5.26%
Taiwan underground
台湾の地下鉄
How much is a human life worth?
人間の命の価値はいくらですか?
two million
二百万
So you multiply 400,000 by 0.29
つまり、400,000 に 0.29 を掛けます。
1 million times 0.02
100万倍 0.02
2 million times 0.05
200万倍 0.05
count up
カウントアップ
Average to pay
平均的な支払い額
You don't do any fund screening
ファンド審査は一切行いません
you pay on average
あなたは平均して支払います
A Patient of Stephen Ginger
スティーブン・ジンジャーの患者
The state will spend 500,000
国は50万ドルを支出する
1.5 million vs. 500,000
150万対50万
which one compares
どっちを比較するか
Of course 500,000 accounting
もちろん50万会計
but this thing
しかし、このこと
At the Department of Health
保健省で
The Drug Harm Relief Foundation
薬物被害救済財団
Indeed, some teachers of medical economics say
実際、医療経済学の先生の中にはこう言う人もいます。
you pay
あなたが支払う
1.5 million vs. 500,000
150万対50万
Of course this calculation
もちろんこの計算は
But then I thought of what example
しかし、そのとき私はどんな例を考えましたか
I think it is an example that you often see in newspapers
新聞などでよく見る例だと思います
kill the driver
運転手を殺す
I'd rather kill someone
むしろ誰かを殺したい
I don't want to put a person
人を入れたくない
crippled
不自由な
Isn't that what it looks like?
そう見えませんか？
I think you just let happen
あなたはただ起こってしまっただけだと思います
It's fine for the country to pay
国が金出せばいいじゃん
Because the compensation is only 500,000
賠償金が50万しかないから
You need 1.5 million to prevent one
防ぐには150万必要
Both are 1 million
どちらも100万です
Because why is there such a difference
だってなんでこんなに差があるんだろう
because we didn't count a single person
一人も数えていなかったから
After being disabled
無効化された後
We don't count after a person dies
人が死んだ後はカウントしない
his life's loss
彼の命の損失
In the current medical economics, there is no formula
現在の医療経済学には公式はない
the second
二番目
Our society in Taiwan
台湾における私たちの社会
Can this really be allowed to happen?
本当にこんなことが許されていいのでしょうか？
can really say
本当に言えます
Then once something happens to compensate
そしてそれを補う何かが起こったら
Then don't come and do precautions in advance
だったら来ないで事前に予防策を講じてください
Some doctors even say
と言う医師もいます。
say in terms of medical standards
医療基準の観点から言う
What is one thing that can be prevented and not prevented
予防できることと予防できないことは何ですか
illegal
違法的
This does not mean that it can be prevented and cannot be prevented
防げる、防げないということではありません
Now that Academia Sinica is very old
中央研究院はもう古いです
Study says 1502 has good checks
研究によると、1502 には良好なチェック機能がある
Come for 1502 genetic screening
1502遺伝子スクリーニングを受けに来てください
But why should we consider
しかし、なぜ考慮する必要があるのか
Is it ethically reasonable?
それは倫理的に合理的ですか？
and social affordability
社会的な手頃な価格
we really this society
私たちは本当にこの社会
Really only care about the difference between 1.5 million and 500,000
本当に気にするのは150万と50万の差だけ
certainly
そうです
we are a scholar
私たちは学者です
It's the Central Asian crowd garden. How can we
ここは中央アジアの群衆の庭です。
Taiwan is so developed
台湾は発展してるよ
How can you care about 1 million
どうやって100万を気にすることができますか
But Vice President Chen used to be the Director of Health
しかし、陳副総統はかつて保健部長だった
It's different when he sees here
彼がここを見たら違うよ
Because every disease is like this
どの病気もこんな感じだから
You have to choose breast cancer and tell you
乳がんを選択して告げなければなりません
The 800,000 yuan for Heshan disease is also worth spending
鶴山病の80万元も使う価値がある
When that lung cancer, that Aresa
あのアレサが肺がんになったとき
Your health insurance is so much money
あなたの健康保険はとてもお金がかかります
So what is the use of limited resources to treat
では、限られた資源を治療にどう活用するのか。
Heart to Pusture Breast Cancer Patient
Heart to Pusture 乳癌病人
Or to prevent a CBG
またはCBGを防ぐため
caused by steven johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンが原因
that's a hard choice
それは難しい選択だ
so this thing has no answer
だからこれには答えがない
This thing just prompts us to think carefully
このことは、私たちに注意深く考えるよう促すだけです
Personalized medicine is really coming to an end
個別化医療は本当に終わりに近づいている
When you really have to calculate medical costs
どうしても医療費を計算しなければならないとき
Your country has to choose to say
あなたの国は言うことを選択しなければなりません
where are you going to put your resources
リソースをどこに置くつもりですか
So this Steven Johnson with
それで、このスティーブン・ジョンソンと
The relationship between 1502 and CBG
1502とCBGの関係
is a very good example from a textbook
教科書の非常に良い例です
Find related from the beginning
関連するものを最初から探す
Take our new person to basic research
新しい人を基礎研究に連れて行きます
So it depends on how to do it clinically to be effective
したがって、効果的であるかどうかは臨床的にどのように行うかにかかっています
and being a reporter we ignore
そしてレポーターである私たちは無視します
HK's so-called medical economics
香港のいわゆる医療経済学
So this is a really good example
これは本当に良い例です
Tell us how personalized medicine should be done
個別化医療のあり方を教えてください
Finally, tell us that is personalized medicine
最後に、それが個別化医療であると教えてください
is to take into account the differences from person to person
人による違いを考慮することです
But the difference between this person
でもこの人との違いは
Finally, what we just said
最後に、今言ったこと
The 1502 and CBZ we just mentioned
先ほど触れた 1502 と CBZ
caused by steven johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソンが原因
That's a strong hurdle that's monofactorial
それは一因性の強いハードルです
is now what we encounter
それが今私たちが遭遇したものです
Hypertension Diabetes Cancer Cardiolipidemia
高血圧 糖尿病 がん 心脂質血症
and the occurrence of disease
そして病気の発生
Disease treatment is simple
病気の治療は簡単です
You can give different drugs according to different patients
患者ごとに異なる薬を投与できる
but what happens
しかし何が起こるか
That is to say
つまり
Let me take that as an example of a study by Vice President Chen.
陳副総統の研究を例に挙げてみましょう。
That's the study just now
それが今の勉強です
Their study looked at the liver function of a person at the same time
彼らの研究は人の肝機能を同時に調べた
People with poorer liver function
肝機能が低下している人
His one has a higher risk of liver cancer
彼の人は肝臓がんのリスクが高い
or according to just said
または今言った通り
Qixing should research the virus
七星はウイルスを研究すべきだ
Assuming that it belongs to the first type of management
第一のタイプの管理に属すると仮定すると、
It is equivalent to adding three factors into the
これは、次の式に 3 つの要素を追加することに相当します。
Just mentioned three factors
先ほど3つの要素を挙げました
High or low viral load
ウイルス量が高いか低いか
Then liver function is good or bad
そうすると肝機能が良いか悪いか
And in the end HCV belongs to
そして最終的にはHCVが属します
bad type or good type
悪いタイプか良いタイプか
Six situations are better than just one situation
1 つの状況よりも 6 つの状況のほうが優れています
More accurate prediction of a person's risk of liver cancer
個人の肝臓がんのリスクをより正確に予測できる
This means that
この意味は
for complex diseases
複雑な病気の場合
Nothing like 1502 and CBG caused
1502 や CBG のようなものは何も引き起こさない
Steven Johnson
スティーブン・ジョンソン
Because it is a single cause
原因はひとつだから
But for liver cancer
でも肝臓がんの場合は
Liver cancer caused by type C liver cancer
C型肝がんによる肝がん
you have to take into account besides you
あなたはあなた以外のことも考慮に入れなければなりません
Beyond the highs and lows of type C liver cancer
C型肝がんの浮き沈みを超えて
You have to consider the quality of liver function
肝機能の質を考慮する必要があります
you have to consider someone
あなたは誰かを考慮しなければなりません
In the end, type C liver cancer belongs to the strong and the weak
結局のところ、C型肝がんは強者と弱者に分類される
Therefore, the concept
したがって、コンセプトは、
It is used in the treatment of the five cancers we just talked about
先ほどお話しした 5 つのがんの治療に使用されます
We just said that the assumption is
前提条件は次のとおりであると先ほど言いました。
Her to Pasitidon
彼女とパシティドン
Can give him and setting
彼と設定を与えることができます
Here is another example
ここに別の例があります
Supposed to be Her to Pasitidon
パシティドンにとって彼女になるはずだった
Can two medicines be given? One is Leftal Role
2 つの薬を投与できますか? 1 つは左の役割です
One is that Tamazifen
一つはタマジフェンです
I didn’t just say that Leftal Role can cause serious osteoporosis
私は左翼の役割が深刻な骨粗鬆症を引き起こす可能性があるとだけ言ったわけではありません
So what is the way a person can decide to say
では、人はどのように判断して言うことができるのでしょうか？
Should I give Leftal Role or Tamazifen
レフトの役割を与えるべきかタマジフェンを与えるべきか
Then those of us who study breast cancer discovered one of the genes
そして、乳がんを研究している私たちは、遺伝子の 1 つを発見しました。
That gene is called CYP2D6
その遺伝子はCYP2D6と呼ばれます
Why? The Tamazifen that I ate
なぜ? 私が食べたタマジフェン
It's not about grabbing the position directly.
直接ポジションを掴むことではありません。
But through the activation of the gene CYP2D6
しかし、遺伝子CYP2D6の活性化によって
Thus a concept arises
こうして概念が生まれる
Suppose my CYP2D6 is very strong
私のCYP2D6が非常に強いと仮定すると、
Then I'll go eat Tamazifen
それからタマジフェンを食べに行きます
if i'm weak
私が弱ければ
Just go and eat this trick obediently with peace of mind
落ち着いてこのトリックを素直に食べてください
Really long track looks like
本当に長いトラックはこんな感じ
2008 really looked like this
2008年は本当にこんな感じでした
What to track after 5 years
5年後に何を追跡するか
All kinds are breast cancer survival
全種類が乳がん生存率
You can find that two of them survive the best
そのうちの 2 人が最もよく生き残ることがわかります
The top group is gray and this line is what I just said
一番上のグループは灰色で、この行は私が今言ったことです
The group that ate meat had the best survival rate
肉を食べたグループの生存率が最も高かった
I don't need to talk about it just now
今それについて話す必要はない
but it has side effects
しかし副作用もあります
but you found out
でもあなたは気づいた
there's another set that's as good as it
同じくらい良いセットがもう一つあります
That group of dots is this group
その点のグループがこのグループです
Tama 7
正解 7
Plus CYB2D6 is part of
さらに、CYB2D6 は
Mom and Dad give good words
お父さんとお母さんが良い言葉をかけてくれる
Its survival rate is almost as good as that meat
その生存率はその肉とほぼ同じです
Conversely which group is the worst
どのグループが一番悪いのか
That's Tama 7
就是Tama 7
Or if you add CYB2D6 and only bet on changing the epidemic situation
または、CYB2D6 を追加して流行の状況を変えることだけに賭ける場合
That is to say, eating equals to no effect
つまり、食べても効果がないということです
So the other one just mentioned
それで、今言及したもう一つは
You have to decide what a patient wants to eat
患者が何を食べたいかを決める必要がある
Lovers and love kings still grab the position
恋人と愛の王は依然としてその座を掴んでいる
Then do CYB2D6 gene screening first
次に、まず CYB2D6 遺伝子スクリーニングを行います。
If it is positive
陽性の場合
you don't go to that to endure
あなたは耐えるためにそこに行くわけではありません
that very complicated pause syndrome
非常に複雑なポーズ症候群
you go eat one cheap and effective
安くて効果的なものを食べに行きます
heavy duty medicine
強力な薬
That hypothesis is CYB2D6
その仮説はCYB2D6です
If it belongs to the bad genotype
悪い遺伝子型に属している場合
Then come and eat this obediently
じゃあ素直に食べに来いよ
This is also a contribution of personalized medicine
これも個別化医療の貢献です
the same reason
同じ理由
Progressive treatment
進行治療
from just now
さっきから
Just come with the example of bacterial hepatitis virus
細菌性肝炎ウイルスの例を挙げてください
or Liptoid CYB2D6
またはリプトイド CYB2D6
Or the Tamasibin example
あるいはタマシビンの例
Tell us about progressing treatment
治療の進歩について教えてください
to use more indicators
より多くのインジケーターを使用するには
Some of these indicators are external factors
これらの指標の一部は外部要因です
For example, is bacterial hepatitis virus strong or weak?
例えば、細菌性肝炎ウイルスは強いのでしょうか、それとも弱いのでしょうか？
and factors within governance
ガバナンス内の要素と
Is liver function good or bad?
肝機能は良いのか悪いのか？
Or is my CYB2D6 a strong worker or a weak worker?
それとも私のCYB2D6は強いワーカーなのか弱いワーカーなのか？
can determine the occurrence of disease
病気の発生を判断できる
Disease progression and disease treatment
病気の進行と治療
this is what we're talking about
これが私たちが話していることです
Customized Personalized Medicine
カスタマイズされた個別化医療
But it's really going to get to the point we imagined.
しかし、それは本当に私たちが想像していた地点に到達するでしょう。
We use this picture to show you Chinese painting at the beginning
冒頭で中国絵画を紹介するためにこの写真を使用します
Finally, let’s look at the famous Spanish Road No.
最後に、有名なスペイン道路 3 号線を見てみましょう。
Called Diago Velasquez
ディアゴ・ベラスケスと呼ばれる
A picture he drew is called the picture of ladies and gentlemen.
彼が描いた絵は紳士淑女の絵と呼ばれています。
What is the picture of ladies and gentlemen?
紳士淑女のイメージは何ですか？
He is Ukishi Taxi
浮石タクシーです
he painted little spanish princesses
彼は小さなスペインのお姫様を描きました
There is a group of ladies and gentlemen next to him
彼の隣には紳士淑女のグループがいる
Also includes things like come to make him laugh
笑わせに来るとかも含みます。
And the dog keeps coming by his side
そして犬は彼のそばに来続けます
Just this little Spanish princess to make him laugh
この小さなスペイン王女が彼を笑わせるためだけに
these people serve him
これらの人々は彼に仕える
That's why it's called the picture of the maid
だからメイドの絵と呼ばれる
So what is Diego Velazquez painting
では、ディエゴ・ベラスケスの絵とは何ですか？
What he paints is what he is here is a sense of painting
彼が描くものは彼がここにいるもの、それが絵画の感覚である
Vilazquez even drew himself in it
ビラスケスは自分自身もその中に描きました
Whose house is he drawing until the end guess
彼は最後まで誰の家を描いているのか推測します
inside the mirror
鏡の中
The father and the queen are here
お父さんとお母さんがここにいます
He means that this picture drawn by Vilazquez is
つまり、ビラスケスのこの絵は、
The father and the queen stand in front of this
父と王妃がこの前に立っています。
He was drawing his daughter bored beside him
彼は横で退屈している娘の絵を描いていた
Next to it is a group of maids to make him laugh
その隣には彼を笑わせるメイドのグループがあります
dog to accompany him
彼に同行する犬
The maid came to make him laugh
メイドは彼を笑わせに来た
So this is Diago Vilazquez's version
これはディアゴ・ビラスケスのバージョンです
On the right is the B.Casso version
右はB.Cassoバージョン
Put the painting of the maid by Vilazquez
ビラスケスのメイドの絵を置く
where did you say the princess
どこでお姫様って言ったの？
princess is here
プリンセスがここにいます
The maid is probably this
メイドさんはおそらくこれです
the dog is probably this
その犬はおそらくこれです
Then Vilazquez is a little unclear here
それからビラスケスはここで少し不明瞭です
I use this to mention
私はこれを言及するために使用します
1502 with diabetes
1502 糖尿病
1502 and breast cancer
1502と乳がん
1502 with lung cancer
1502 肺がん
As far as 1502 is black and white
1502までは白黒
Because as far as 1502 the relationship is strong
1502までの関係は強いので
Three genes, people are people, dogs are dogs
3 つの遺伝子、人は人、犬は犬
But the high blood that we generally care about
しかし、私たちが一般的に気にしている高血症は、
Diabetes and cancer
糖尿病とがん
Must-have version
必要なバージョン
everyone contributes a little bit
みんなが少しずつ貢献していく
That is to say
つまり
in the past
過去に
one or two big genes
1つまたは2つの大きな遺伝子
He decided to go east or west or west
彼は東か西か西に行くことに決めた
But the chronic diseases we often talk about
しかし、私たちがよく話題にする慢性疾患は、
It's a bunch of little dick genes
それは小さなペニスの遺伝子の集まりです
common combination
よくある組み合わせ
You're looking for the disease impact of large genes
大きな遺伝子の病気への影響を探している
That's like 1502 to decide
それは1502で決めるみたいな
State 1 caused by CPG
CPG による状態 1
well done
素晴らしい
Great for Personalized Medicine
個別化医療に最適
Because of the single factor relationship and
一因関係のため
But suppose we're talking about chronic diseases
しかし、私たちが慢性疾患について話していると仮定してください
If it's a combination of a lot of little dick genes
それがたくさんの小さなペニスの遺伝子の組み合わせなら
How much should it be reduced
どれくらい減らせばいいのか
Is it enough to subtract five? Is ten enough?
5 引くだけで十分ですか? 10 で十分ですか?
thirty is enough
30で十分です
Take the example of breast cancer that I am most familiar with
私が最もよく知っている乳がんを例に挙げてみましょう。
where are the benefits
どこにメリットがあるのか
good thing is to say
良いことは言うことです
Thanks to medical scientists and
医学者や科学者のおかげで、
technologist progress
技術者の進歩
They develop some biochips
彼らはいくつかのバイオチップを開発しています
Capable of whole-genome scanning
全ゲノムをスキャンする能力
It is equivalent to saying that a 1502 should be checked before
これは、1502 を事前にチェックする必要があると言っているのと同じです。
3 hours or 3 days
3時間または3日
But the one at Academia Sinica is called the National Genotyping Center
しかし、中央研究院のものは「国立遺伝子型解析センター」と呼ばれています。
He can check 500,000 genetic markers in one morning
彼はある朝に 500,000 個の遺伝子マーカーをチェックできる
In this way, it can be considered at the same time
このように同時に考えることができます
The effect of a large number of small cages
多数の小さなケージの効果
two aspects
二つの側面
used to be expensive to make
昔は作るのに高価だった
What now
今、何
Now it's time to advertise our national genotype
今こそ我が国の遺伝子型を宣伝する時です
Assuming that the whole genome scans 600,000 positions
ゲノム全体が 600,000 の位置をスキャンすると仮定します。
We say that there are 3 billion genomes
ゲノムは30億あると言われています
How much does it cost to make a 3 billion
30億稼ぐのにいくらかかりますか
In fact it is not expensive
実際には高価ではありません
I heard that Taiwanese people in that country and Wang Jianmin did it
あの国の台湾人と王建民がやったと聞いた
A person is 300,000
人は30万人
300,000 is not expensive
30万は高くないよ
Of course expensive
もちろん高価です
But 300,000 can take you 3 billion
でも30万あれば30億かかる
Re-read that genetic locus
その遺伝子座を読み直してください
Do you say it's expensive?
高価だと言いますか？
not expensive
高くない
not bad
悪くない
The 300,000 is slightly used for the provincial branch
30万は地方支部に少し使われます
That one or two years can be responsible
1年か2年で責任が持てるということ
Not to mention, suppose you said genetic typing
言うまでもなく、遺伝子型分類と言ったとします。
It only costs 4,000 yuan per person. What is genetic typing?
費用は一人当たりたったの4,000元です。
That is to say, you have a high-speed rail car
つまり、高速鉄道車両があります。
You don't need every passenger to ask him if he is
すべての乗客に彼に尋ねる必要はありません。
You just need to look at one person
一人を見ればいいだけ
It’s like you can do it with all high-speed trains
全ての高速鉄道でできるようなものだ
You can see a few representative
代表的なものをいくつかご覧いただけます
Just look at a few representative words
代表的な言葉をいくつか見てみましょう
Only 4000 yuan per person
一人あたりたったの4000元
4000 yuan in Taiwan
台湾では4000元
Probably everyone can afford it
おそらく誰でも余裕で買えるだろう
So you want a personalized medicine
個別化された医療が必要です
On the one hand, technological advances
一方でテクノロジーの進歩により、
On the other hand, because of the cost reduction
一方で、コストダウンのため、
lead to find this little dick gene now
この小さなペニスの遺伝子を今見つけようとしています
much more important than before
以前よりもはるかに重要です
Then the example of diabetes mellitus we just talked about
次に、先ほどお話しした糖尿病の例です。
It's what you saw in the upper right corner just now
先ほど右上隅に見えたのがそれです
Obese people more likely to develop diabetes
肥満の人は糖尿病を発症する可能性が高い
But in 2008
しかし2008年に
Whole genome scanning
全ゲノムスキャン
16 loci were found
16 個の遺伝子座が見つかりました
As a result, the 16 loci
その結果、16 の遺伝子座
Can find small differences in Datong
大同では小さな違いを見つけることができます
why
なぜ
The horizontal axis is a person's obesity index
横軸は人の肥満指数です
Obese people are more likely to develop diabetes
肥満の人は糖尿病を発症する可能性が高くなります
Watch DJ getting more and more
DJがどんどん成長していくのを見てください
But we just talked about genetic screening and humanized medicine
しかし、私たちは遺伝子スクリーニングとヒト化医療について話したばかりです
Definitely not saying obesity is important
肥満が重要だというわけではない
still important
まだ重要
The fatter you are, the easier it is to get obesity
太っているほど肥満になりやすい
but where is the point
しかし、要点はどこですか
The focus is to find the small differences in the great same
焦点は、大きな同じものの小さな違いを見つけることです
Under the same obesity index
同じ肥満指数の下で
Plus 16 loci for genes
さらに 16 の遺伝子座
The number of bad genes is 8, 9, and 10
悪い遺伝子の数は8、9、10です
11 12
11 12
The greater the number of bad genes, the higher the risk
悪い遺伝子の数が多いほどリスクが高くなります
So it is equal to the occurrence of diabetes
つまり糖尿病の発症と同じです
Traditional risk factors combined with genetic screening
従来の危険因子と遺伝子スクリーニングの組み合わせ
can affect a person's risk of developing diabetes
人の糖尿病発症リスクに影響を与える可能性がある
make a more accurate assessment
より正確な評価を行う
Just now my Vice President Chen mentioned
たった今、私の副社長チェンが言いました。
My laboratory participated in the world's first
私の研究室は世界初の
so-called genome-wide breast cancer screening
いわゆるゲノムワイド乳がんスクリーニング
Whole Genome
全ゲノム
The most important gene is called FGF2
最も重要な遺伝子はFGF2と呼ばれます
It's in different labs all over the world
世界中のさまざまな研究所にあります
The horizontal axis is the so-called risk
横軸はいわゆるリスクです
Different laboratories around the world
世界中のさまざまな研究室
Including my laboratory at Academia Sinica
中央研究院の私の研究室も含めて
Abbreviated as BCST is Bress Cancer Study
BCSTと略されるのは、ブレスガン研究です。
in the land of Taiwan
台湾の地で
It is said that this FGF8 degree assumption is not good to carry out
このFGF8度の仮定を行うのは良くないと言われています
It is 1.3 times more dangerous
1.3倍危険です
Everyone says it's taller than one
誰もがそれは1より高いと言います
but please pay attention
でも注意してください
1.3 is not 13 is not 130
1.3 は 13 ではありません、130 ではありません
How much was Steven Johnson just now? More than 1300
スティーブン ジョンソンは今いくらでしたか? 1300 以上
This is the so-called Xiaorouluo gene
これはいわゆるXiaorouluo遺伝子です
more complex disease
より複雑な病気
you have to explain the occurrence of the disease
あなたは病気の発生を説明しなければなりません
It's just a combination of a lot of Xiao Rouluo genes.
それはたくさんの小さなRouluo遺伝子の組み合わせです。
So for these little soft genes
この小さな柔らかい遺伝子については
How to use it in personalized medicine
個別化医療での活用方法
There are many different controversies at present
現在、さまざまな論争が巻き起こっている
some people say
と言う人もいます
Because of the advancement of technology
テクノロジーの進歩のせいで
I can reduce the cost of technological progress
技術進歩のコストを削減できる
I can put all these things in health insurance later
これらすべてを後で健康保険に入れることができます
that way you can afford it
そうすれば余裕ができます
but some people can say
しかし、一部の人は言うことができます
This little Rourou gene is only 1.3 times
この小さなルールー遺伝子はわずか1.3倍
1.3 times the words
単語数1.3倍
So how much can it contribute?
それで、どれくらい貢献できるでしょうか？
that's in our breasts
それは私たちの胸の中にあります
Because it has the most genetic screening sites in the world
世界で最も多くの遺伝子検査施設があるため
so would like to say
だから言いたいです
Can we take the whole genetic competition just now?
今の遺伝子競争全体を取り上げてもいいでしょうか？
The most important thing about the name of the station is the first place, what AGR
駅名で一番重要なのはAGRナンバーワンです
Can we make better predictions about diseases?
病気についてより正確に予測できるでしょうか?
His answer is here
彼の答えはここにあります
Just in industry last year
ちょうど昨年業界で
It is also the world's most famous Journal of New Geology
これは世界で最も有名な新地質学ジャーナルでもあります。
Use the medical model to tell us that
医学モデルを使用して次のことを伝えます
Suppose he uses a very complicated statistical model, I can't even understand it
彼が非常に複雑な統計モデルを使用していると仮定すると、私にはそれさえ理解できません
He said ten points
彼は10点言った
The ten loci with less global gene power
全体的な遺伝子力が低い 10 の遺伝子座
In addition, did you have any children just now?
また、さっきお子さんはいらっしゃいましたか？
See if you can predict
予測できるかどうかを確認してください
The case of a girl suffering from five cancers
5つのがんを患う少女のケース
Can we make better predictions
より良い予測ができるだろうか
two conclusions
二つの結論
The first conclusion is quite pessimistic
最初の結論はかなり悲観的です
what is the first conclusion
最初の結論は何ですか
Called Gail plus Sneed equals Gail
ゲイルとスニードを足したものはゲイルと呼ばれます
What is Gail
ゲイルとは
You go to the website of the National Health Bureau
国民健康局のウェブサイトにアクセスします
Gailmodel is based on traditional risk factors
Gailmodel は従来のリスク要因に基づいています
To assess how likely a girl is to have five cancers
女児が 5 つのがんに罹患する可能性を評価するには
traditional risk factors
従来の危険因子
Plus genetic screening for ten loci
さらに 10 遺伝子座の遺伝子スクリーニング
The predictability that can be equal to Gail
ゲイルに匹敵する予知能力
what is that
それは何ですか
Cooperating with genetic screening is one point
遺伝子検査への協力もポイント
so far
ここのところ
Suppose you only do ten
10回しかやらないとしましょう
traditional risk factors
従来の危険因子
Predictions for Female Breast Cancer
女性乳がんの予測
not much help
あまり役に立ちません
The pessimistic side What is the optimistic side?
悲観的な側面 楽観的な側面とは何ですか？
Suppose you only do ten positions
10 ポジションだけを行うとします。
You get the same predictability as Gale
ゲイルと同じ予測可能性が得られます
This is the optimistic side why?
これは楽観的な側面ですが、なぜですか？
Everyone assumes that they have done Gale
誰もがゲイルをやったと思っている
He asked you, how old are you?
彼はあなたに、あなたは何歳ですかと尋ねました。
Just because I don't understand
ただ理解できないからといって
Is it 11 years old? 12 years old or 13 years old?
11時ですか、12時ですか、それとも13時ですか？
Can not remember
思い出せない
Traditional risk factors rely on recall
従来の危険因子はリコールに依存している
Not very accurate, but the screening of genetic loci is very accurate
あまり正確ではありませんが、遺伝子座のスクリーニングは非常に正確です
A is AP is B
AはAP、BはB
A concept learned from the words of Gale just now
さっきのゲイルの言葉から学んだ概念
You use a more accurate method
より正確な方法を使用している
compared with an inaccurate method
不正確な方法と比較して
Both seem to have similar risk assessments
どちらも同様のリスク評価を行っているようです
but so far
しかし、これまでのところ
Assuming you only do ten
10個しか作らないと仮定すると、
Probably the contribution is very limited
おそらく貢献は非常に限られている
The last question is
最後の質問は
Here is a list of the whole genome physiology scans
これは全ゲノム生理学スキャンのリストです
Me and my friends abroad
私と海外の友達
You can see that most of them are white
ほとんどが白であることがわかります
overwhelmingly white
圧倒的に白い
All European countries and U.S. dollars
すべてのヨーロッパ諸国と米ドル
Our group ranks the top ten for breast cancer in the world
私たちのグループは世界の乳がんのトップ10にランクされています
The top ten starts from the first place, what HG's vomit
1位からトップ10、HGが吐いたもの
Then I write red to represent that these ten are very important
次に、これら 10 個が非常に重要であることを表すために赤で書き込みます
My purpose is not to memorize this number for everyone.
私の目的は、この数字を全員に暗記することではありません。
where is the point
どこがポイントですか
assuming only us asians
それが私たちアジア人だけだと仮定してください
That's us Taiwanese
それが私たち台湾人です
Among the ten, the only important one is this
10個の中で重要なのはこれだけです
top two
上位2名
In other words, personalized medicine even if everyone has done a full-body scan
言い換えれば、たとえ全員が全身スキャンを行っていたとしても、個別化医療は可能です。
There are also his characteristics among different races.
種族によっても彼の特徴はあります。
that is mentioned here
それはここで言及されています
For example, here's another breast cancer researcher
たとえば、これは別の乳がん研究者です。
We are also invited to participate
私たちも参加させていただきます
Even we Asians have formed an Asian alliance
私たちアジア人でもアジア同盟を結成しました
Find friends in Shanghai
上海で友達を探す
Friends of Tianjin Friends of Nanjin
天津の友達 南京の友達
Taiwan is our Hong Kong
台湾は私たちの香港です
One locus found in chromosome 6 is particularly important
6 番染色体で見つかった 1 つの遺伝子座は特に重要です
This is a representative of invalid
こちらは無効者の代表です
More than one is effective
複数あると効果的
But you can see that this position is common in Japanese
しかし、この立場は日本語では一般的であることがわかります。
we are here
私たちはここにいる
they will get closer
彼らはもっと近づくでしょう
Then at the white man, almost next to E
それからEのほぼ隣の白人のところで
Black people change color on pigs and sheep
黒人は豚や羊の体色を変える
he means to say
彼は言い​​たいのです
between different races
異なる種族の間で
The same point has different importance
同じ点でも重要度が異なる
therefore
したがって
And finally this
そして最後にこれ
personalized medicine
個別化医療
We really want to personalize medicine
私たちは本当に医療を個別化したいと考えています
on the one hand
一方では
Need more political evidence
もっと政治的な証拠が必要だ
It means that every case must be considered, starting from the first step
それは、あらゆるケースを最初のステップから検討する必要があることを意味します。
What to look for evidence related to the basis
根拠に関連する証拠を何を探すべきか
Can it be done clinically, can't be done by public health practitioners, and medical economics
臨床的にできるのか、公衆衛生家にはできないのか、医療経済的にはできないのか。
The first point
最初のポイント
Second point
2点目
It's just that you have to think that now it's all a combination of Little Lolo's genes
ただ、今はすべてリトル・ロロの遺伝子の組み合わせであると考えなければなりません。
Never again do you think that one or two big genes can determine
1 つや 2 つの大きな遺伝子が決定できるなどとは二度と思わないでしょう。
Even if all
たとえ全部だとしても
third point
3番目のポイント
between races
種族間
Differences
違い
The effect is
効果は
If you want to understand the influence of Little Lolo's genes
リトル・ロロの遺伝子の影響を知りたいなら
You want a large sample size
大きなサンプルサイズが必要な場合
You need to understand the influence of different races
さまざまな人種の影響を理解する必要がある
you want a different race
違う人種が欲しいのですか
Make his own personalized medicine basic information
自分だけのオーダーメイド医療を作る 基本情報
So in the end it is
結局のところそうなのです
Our Central Medical College started
私たちの中央医科大学が始まりました
biological database
生物資料庫
It was under the leadership of Vice President Chen that he aspired to be our president
陳副総統が大統領への野望を導く時です
The instruction means that since we
この指示は、次のことを意味します。
Since personalized medicine is a future trend
個別化医療は将来のトレンドなので
Since you need a large sample for personalized medicine
個別化医療には大量のサンプルが必要なため
Empirical data are specific to people of different races
経験的データはさまざまな人種に特有のものです
then we'll build a biobank
それからバイオバンクを構築します
This is to help you find these empirical materials.
これは、これらの経験的な資料を見つけるのに役立ちます。
Let the next generation
次世代に残しましょう
Let the next generation come back to find these empirical evidence
次世代がこれらの経験的証拠を見つけに戻ってくるようにしましょう
When the polygenic influence
多遺伝子の影響がある場合
There is no need to track another five, ten, or twenty years
さらに 5 年、10 年、20 年を追跡する必要はありません
So this is the one in our center
これが私たちのセンターにあるものです
Our dean is trying his best to promote this left and right
私たちの学部長はこの左派と右派を推進するために全力を尽くしています
Taiwan biological database and biomarkers
台湾の生物学データベースとバイオマーカー
Dean Chen Wu is now leading the project
このプロジェクトは現在、Dean Chen Wu が主導しています。
Then I'll make a fool of myself tonight
じゃあ今夜は自分をバカにするよ
Yes, it's late everyone, thank you all
はい、遅くなりました、みなさん、ありがとうございました
thanks a lot
どうもありがとう
This wonderful speech by our deputy director Chen Zhiqiang
弊社副所長の陳志強氏による素晴らしいスピーチです。
From the part of medicine to the part of humanities, social economics
医学の部分から人文・社会経済の部分へ
The whole involve to personalized medicine
個別化医療に関わる全体
a little late
少し遅れて
but we will allow you to ask a question or two
ただし、1 ～ 2 つの質問をさせていただきます
Is there a very...
とても...
The problem of not being able to go home today
今日は家に帰れない問題
come please
来てください
that i have two questions
質問が2つあるのですが
One is that you have found 1502 and SBG
1 つは、1502 と SBG を見つけたことです。
then it is directly related
それなら直接関係あるよ
So why is it only 5.8% in that positive predictive value
では、なぜ陽性的中率が 5.8% しかないのか
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question is to say
2番目の質問はこう言うことです
CBG is now used for that trigeminal neuralgia
CBGは現在、その三叉神経痛に使用されています
only drug of choice
唯一の選択の薬
Then if after going through the disaster volume
そして、災害ボリュームを通過した後であれば
It turned out that it was not suitable for this drug
この薬には適さないことが判明しました
But you said there is no alternative medicine
でも代替薬はないって言ってたよね
What should we do at this time?
この時、私たちは何をすべきでしょうか？
The second question is a clinical question
2 番目の質問は臨床的な質問です
As far as my clinician friend is concerned,
私の臨床医の友人に関する限り、
Suppose it is 1502
1502年だとします
because of trigeminal neuralgia
三叉神経痛のせいで
We joke that the pain is bearable
痛みは耐えられる程度だと冗談を言います
He said you just have to bear it
彼はただ耐えなければならないと言った
So when...
そうするとき...
So far, the three-pronged dust has penetrated 1502 positive words
これまでのところ、三叉の塵は 1502 のポジティブな言葉を浸透させています
In fact there is no medicine
実は薬はない
Then usually everyone will make some comparisons
そうすれば通常、誰もがいくつかの比較をします
less effective pain relievers
あまり効果のない鎮痛剤
Just eat like R-Spitling
R-スピトリングのように食べてください
is this
これは
What if it doesn't work then?
それでうまくいかなかったらどうしますか？
It didn't work and I cried for two days
うまくいかなくて二日間泣きました
That pain will go away
その痛みは消えていきます
But every day is different
でも毎日は違う
Every day is a lifetime thing
毎日が一生もの
So this is what you just mentioned
それで、これはあなたが今言ったことです
no alternative medicine
代替薬がない
What is genetic screening useful for?
遺伝子検査は何に役立ちますか?
suppose i know
私は知っていると思います
What is that CIP2D6
CIP2D6って何ですか？
The physical fitness of the doctor who treats the positive doctor is so poor
陽性の医師を治療する医師の体力があまりにも悪い
Then why am I doing genetic screening?
では、なぜ遺伝子検査をするのでしょうか？
so this has no answer
だからこれには答えがない
you are right
あなたが正しいです
no answer
答えはありません
This is what drives us
これが私たちを動かす原動力です
many people say
多くの人が言う
You scientists are desperately trying to discover a bunch of agents
あなたたち科学者たちは、大量のエージェントを発見しようと必死に努力しています
But really clinically
しかし実際に臨床的には
where is the contribution to public health
公衆衛生への貢献はどこにあるのか
I'm sorry about this
この件については申し訳ありません
we don't have an answer
私たちには答えがありません
so far
ここのところ
That put it mildly or because of some
控えめに言っても、あるいは何らかの理由で
Just take the medicine that doesn't seem to be effective
効果がなさそうな薬をそのまま飲む
Anyway, the pain took two days to bear.
とにかく痛みに耐えるのに2日かかりました。
Then the first answer is to say
そうすると、最初の答えはこうなります
why positive
なぜポジティブなのか
Positive-negative predictive value so high
陽性陰性的中率が非常に高い
Positive negative predictive value so low
陽性陰性的中率が非常に低い
This responsible person is the head of this Liu Qing's graduate essay
この責任者はこの劉青の卒業論文の筆頭者です
screening tool
スクリーニングツール
screening tool you are equal to
あなたと同等のスクリーニングツール
Are you looking for false positives or false negatives
偽陽性または偽陰性を見つけるつもりですか
your criteria you want your screening tools
必要な基準 スクリーニングツール
Able to cut the masculine from the feminine
男性性を女性性から切り離すことができる
But there must be overlap between the two
しかし、両者の間には重なる部分があるはずです
some people will be fine with medicine
薬で大丈夫な人もいるだろう
Some people take medicine
薬を飲んでいる人もいる
Some people will be fine if they don't take medicine
薬を飲まなくても大丈夫な人もいる
Then where do you cut the point?
では、どこでポイントを切るのでしょうか？
For example, what is called high blood?
たとえば、いわゆる高血症とは何ですか？
you can set it at 200 you can set it at 160
200に設定できます 160に設定できます
you cut 160
あなたは160を切りました
Say 160 is a person with high blood pressure
160が高血圧の人だとします
you should exercise more every day
もっと毎日運動したほうがいいよ
you'll catch a bunch
あなたはたくさん捕まえるでしょう
high blood pressure not high blood pressure
高血圧ではなく高血圧
Conversely, suppose your high blood pressure is cut to 200
逆に、あなたの高血圧が 200 まで下がったとします。
you will die a lot
あなたはたくさん死ぬでしょう
That is not high blood pressure is not high blood pressure
それは高血圧ではありません、それは高血圧ではありません
That's what we just talked about
それが今話したことです
The sensitivity and specificity
感度と特異度
The level of sensitivity and specificity
感度と特異度のレベル
It involves what we just said
それは私たちが今言ったことに関係します
Positive vs Predicted Value vs Predicted Value
正の値 vs 予測値 vs 予測値
What I just said is because we actually have some
私が今言ったのは、実際にいくつかのことがあるからです。
In fact, it is interlocking
実は連動しているんです
Back to the fact that it's simple math
それは単純な数学であるという事実に戻ります
In this way, keeping the total number unchanged
このようにして、合計数を変更しないでください
You still go to that I believe you will understand
あなたはまだそこに行きます、あなたは理解すると信じています
why? this may be a better answer
なぜですか?これはより良い答えかもしれません
In fact, I have just been in the clinic
実は、私はちょうどクリニックに行ったばかりです
or positive predictive value
または陽性的中率
means you may have
あなたが持っている可能性があることを意味します
I might get tested for nasal pregnancy cancer
鼻の妊娠がんの検査を受けるかもしれない
But what if I say Epstein-Barr virus positive?
でもEBウイルス陽性って言ったら
My chances of actually having nasal pregnancy cancer are maybe 10%
私が実際に鼻妊娠がんになる可能性はおそらく 10% です
But this 10% is very important to me
でもこの 10% は私にとってとても重要です
Because it is a serious disease that requires early detection and early treatment
早期発見、早期治療が必要な重篤な病気ですので、
I would rather
私はむしろ
Let me tell you that there is a possibility that I have nasal pregnancy cancer
鼻妊娠がんの可能性があると言わせてください
Then I will go for further treatment for nasal pregnancy
それから、鼻妊娠のさらなる治療に行くつもりです
allow me to get further diagnosis
さらに診断させてください
So it doesn't matter if the positive predictive value is low
だから陽性的中率が低くても問題ない
But I'm going to tell someone that you definitely don't have nasal pregnancy cancer.
でも、私は誰かに、あなたは絶対に鼻妊娠癌ではない、と言いたいと思います。
You must never say that the nasal pregnancy cancer he used later
彼が後で使用した鼻妊娠癌とは決して言えません
So we sometimes choose a high negative predictive value
そのため、高い陰性的中率を選択することがあります。
But the positive predictive value is not too high
でも陽性的中率はそこまで高くない
Because we still have further diagnostic opportunities
診断の機会はまだ残っているため
We can use something like this
このようなものを使用できます
to carry out
実行する
that this
これは
I think this one we wait maybe we can try again
これは待っていると思います、もう一度試してみることができるかもしれません
again
また
try it and talk
試してみて話してください
Just now there is another question, isn't it?
今、別の質問がありましたね。
No, there is another lady coming
いいえ、別の女性が来ています
Excuse me
すみません
consult
相談する
vice director
副所長
That's an average room
それは平均的な部屋です
all the troubles of women
女性のあらゆる悩みを
That is to say, most girls after menopause
つまり、閉経後のほとんどの女の子は、
there are two
二つあります
The associate doctor will advise him to take hormones
准医師は彼にホルモン剤を服用するようアドバイスするでしょう
Then some doctors suggested not to take hormones
その後、何人かの医師はホルモン剤を服用しないように勧めました
That
それか
The reason for suggesting not to take hormones is
ホルモン剤を摂取しないことを推奨する理由は次のとおりです。
explain
説明
you may get it if you eat it
食べれば取れるかもしれない
right
右
That
それか
The first person who took hormones because of you
あなたのせいで初めてホルモン剤を服用した人
they usually
彼らは通常
In the end, it will cause the devil in the womb
結局は子宮に悪魔を生むことになる
What about the devil in the womb?
子宮の中の悪魔はどうなるのでしょうか？
The method used by doctors before
以前医師が行っていた方法
That is to say, do a uterine scraping action
つまり、子宮をこする動作をするということです。
then it's ok
それなら大丈夫です
So the doctor also said
それで医者もこう言いました
If you eat it, you may return to uterine cancer
食べると子宮がんが再発する可能性がある
Now it's breast cancer
今度は乳がんです
what is the relationship between these two
この二人の関係は何ですか
please teach me
教えて下さい
We don't have very complex inquiries from here
こちらからはあまり複雑なお問い合わせは承っておりません
What is the role of hormones?
ホルモンの役割は何ですか?
Sudden death breast real body
サドンデス胸本体
But another role for hormones
しかし、ホルモンにはもう一つの役割があります
Assuming hormones are true if not good
ホルモンが良くない場合は真実であると仮定する
Then we don't need hormones long ago
そうすれば、ホルモンはずっと前から必要ありません
Why hormones control body temperature
なぜホルモンが体温をコントロールするのか
Educational real estate stocks say
教育不動産株は言う
Why does a person have a fever after menopause
閉経後に熱が出るのはなぜですか
red face
赤い顔
Why eat that after menopause
なぜ閉経後にそれを食べるのか
The so-called hormone replacement therapy
いわゆるホルモン補充療法
HRT
HRT
Because some people after menopause
閉経後の人もいるから
You will feel the nausea, vomiting and fried red just mentioned
先ほど述べた吐き気、嘔吐、揚げた赤味を感じるでしょう。
It's hard
それは難しい
So when standing in the objective point of the sub-factory
そこで、サブ工場の目標地点に立ったとき
Then you make it up?
じゃあ仲直りするの？
But to make up for it, judging from the benchmark just now
しかし、それを補うために、先ほどのベンチマークから判断すると、
it's easy
それは簡単です
That promotes cell proliferation that leads to breast cancer
それは乳がんにつながる細胞増殖を促進します
Therefore the same
したがって同じ
The concept of personalized medicine was born
個別化医療の概念が誕生
Who will eat properly
ちゃんと食べる人は
so just right
だからちょうどいい
This is what we are studying now
これが私たちが今勉強していることです
that is
あれは
just a word
ただ一言
HRT words
HRT の単語
some people eat very fast
とても早く食べる人もいます
Some people just happen to grow up to that twenty
たまたまその20歳まで成長する人もいる
won't get breast cancer
乳がんにならない
But it can prevent a person
しかし、それは人を防ぐことができます
That word still has a lot of research points of view
この言葉にはまだ研究の観点がたくさんあります
in terms of food
食べ物の面で
Now you ask the surgeon to
さて、あなたは外科医にこう尋ねます。
Obstetricians have different views
産婦人科医の意見も違う
because
なぜなら
practically
特に
This hormone replacement therapy
このホルモン補充療法は
The risk of breast cancer is
乳がんのリスクは、
1.3 times more than not eating
食べない場合の1.3倍
Equal to 1.3 is 0.3 more than 1
1.3 に等しいとは、0.3 が 1 より大きいことを意味します
His obstetrics department must tell you
彼の産科があなたに言うはずです
Secondhand smoke is twice as likely to cause breast cancer
受動喫煙は乳がんを引き起こす可能性が2倍
often speak
よく話す
You are not afraid of your husband smoking.
あなたは夫が喫煙することを恐れていません。
Why are you afraid that HRT will get breast cancer?
HRT が乳がんになるのをなぜ恐れるのですか?
So the surgeon said
そこで外科医はこう言いました
important risk factor
重要な危険因子
you dare to eat
あなたはあえて食べますか
So the surgeon with
そこで外科医は
The concept of negative productivity revolution is different
マイナス生産性革命の概念は違う
Of course we most hope that our scientists
もちろん、私たち科学者が最も望んでいるのは、
So the conclusion is not to eat subtleties, right?
結論は微妙なものは食べないということですよね？
Do not eat subtle
微妙なものは食べないでください
But some people just feel uncomfortable, so what should I do?
しかし、中には不快に感じる人もいるので、どうすればよいですか？
Let's eat for that negative productivity revolution
マイナスの生産性革命のために食べましょう
Then check it a few more times, that is, people do photography every two years
それからさらに数回チェックします。つまり、人々は 2 年ごとに写真を撮ります。
You do it every six months now, not to mention that some people may have breasts
今では半年ごとにそれを行っていますが、言うまでもなく、一部の人には乳房が存在する可能性があります
Before the cure, there was a cover point, as I said just now
治療前にキャッピングがありました。
Then you'd better not eat it because you are a high-risk situation
だったらリスクが高いから食べないほうがいいよ
Then this is where the concept of personalized medicine comes in.
そこで登場するのが個別化医療という概念です。
Then we'd like to do some more genetic testing.
それから遺伝子検査をしてみたいと思っています
I found that whoever eats it will be just right
誰が食べてもちょうどいいことが分かった
That's where we scientists haven't worked hard enough
そこは私たち科学者の努力が足りないところです
That is also the related one followed by
これも関連するもので、その後に続きます。
That is to say, the hormone itself is released after a girl's menopause
つまり、女性の閉経後にホルモン自体が分泌されるのです。
She'll increase yours just by taking that hormone
彼女はそのホルモンを摂取するだけであなたの値を増やすでしょう
would increase your hormone production, right?
ホルモンの分泌が増えるでしょう？
Hormones are equivalent to a power source of a human body
ホルモンは人間の体の動力源に相当します
you must have this hormone
このホルモンが必要です
Only then can many things in your body function more normally
そうして初めて、体内の多くのものがより正常に機能できるようになります
so it's good to say
だから言うのは良いことです
is it possible
出来ますか
For example, after a girl shuts down
たとえば、女の子がシャットダウンした後、
she's been on hormones for a while
彼女はしばらくホルモン剤を服用している
nothing happened
何も起こらなかった
Then she felt bored and didn't bother to eat.
それから彼女は退屈を感じて、食べる気にならなくなりました。
too lazy to eat
食べるのがめんどくさい
another ten years
あと10年
She felt that there was the situation that caused the shutdown before
彼女は以前にシャットダウンを引き起こした状況があったと感じました
For example, the heartbeat is a little irregular
たとえば、心拍が少し不規則になる
or sarcasm or bad sleep or something
皮肉とか寝相の悪さとか
Can she still eat and drink at this time?
この時点でも彼女は食べたり飲んだりできますか？
sure
もちろん
So this one uses the same more honorable medical concept
つまり、これは同じより名誉ある医学概念を使用しています
Let's compare two groups
2つのグループを比較してみましょう
One group is to taunt after shutdown
あるグループはシャットダウン後に罵倒する
One group will not taunt after shutdown
あるグループはシャットダウン後に挑発しません
It costs 4,000 yuan to do it
作るのに4000円かかります
4,000 yuan for a group energy scan
グループエネルギースキャンの場合は4,000元
Let's see where the mocking gene is
嘲笑遺伝子がどこにあるのか見てみましょう
then you can decide to say
それからあなたは言うことを決めることができます
who should eat and who should not eat
誰が食べるべきで誰が食べてはいけないのか
So a lot of the concepts we're talking about today
今日私たちが話しているコンセプトの多くは
It's actually very simple
実はとてもシンプルです
Our cost determination
コストによる当社の決定
Advances in technology, many things that were not possible before
テクノロジーの進歩により、以前は不可能だったことがたくさんあります
able to make better predictions
より良い予測を立てることができる
This is where our medical scientists work hard
ここは私たちの医学者が熱心に取り組んでいる場所です
That is to say, it still depends on the person
つまり、やはり人によるんですね
because of people
人のせいで
People with conditions can eat it
症状のある人でも食べられる
Yes, the straight line is just saying eat tomatoes, okay?
はい、単刀直入に言うとトマトを食べなさいと言っているだけですよね？
Of course it's good. Do you want to eat five or ten or one?
もちろん、5 つ、10 つ、それとも 1 つが欲しいですか?
Everyone is different
誰もが違う
Scientists hope to put that
科学者たちはそれを解明したいと考えている
Find out the genes that are different for each person
人それぞれに異なる遺伝子を調べよう
OK thank you
わかりました、ありがとう
pregene sequencing
プレジーン配列決定
About every three to five years
およそ3年から5年に一度
Just drop from 300,000 to 30,000
30万から3万に下がるだけ
Now technology is advancing rapidly
今、テクノロジーは急速に進歩しています
the future is like
未来はこんな感じ
when did you say it
いつ言いましたか
In fact, he emphasized that the latter is very important
実際、彼は後者が非常に重要であると強調しました
When the influence of this gene is very small
この遺伝子の影響が非常に小さい場合
Most diseases are genetic
ほとんどの病気は遺伝性です
Effects of interacting with the environment
環境との相互作用の影響
For example, eating foods high in sterol
たとえば、ステロールを多く含む食べ物を食べると、
but my steroid metabolizing genes
でも私のステロイド代謝遺伝子は
are different
異なっています
Then this reactivation is very important
それから、この再活性化は非常に重要です
i have bad genes for example
たとえば私は悪い遺伝子を持っています
i used to do
やったことある
If a person eats aflatoxin
アフラトキシンを摂取した場合
will get liver cancer
肝臓がんになります
But if it has a good read gene
しかし、それが優れた読み取り遺伝子を持っていれば、
If it is called GSTM1T1
GSTM1T1 と呼ばれる場合
No matter how much toxin it has
どんなに毒素が入っていても
it read it all
それはすべて読んだ
It won't get liver cancer
肝臓がんにはならないよ
this kind of person
このような人
Exotics
エキゾチック
It doesn't matter what he eats
彼が何を食べるかは問題ではない
but if your genes are bad
でも遺伝子が悪いなら
If there is no way to understand
理解する方法がない場合
then please don't eat
それなら食べないでください
Things that contain aflatoxin
アフラトキシンを含むもの
So what about the future?
それで、将来はどうですか
it's more about the environment
それはむしろ環境の問題です
The influence of interactions with genes
遺伝子との相互作用の影響
what you just said
あなたが今言ったこと
Hormonal factors are the same
ホルモン因子は同じ
if we know
私たちが知っていれば
Hormone basics in the human body
人体のホルモンの基礎
he in different women
彼はさまざまな女性の中にいる
he has different genes
彼は異なる遺伝子を持っています
his that
彼のそれ
Manifestations of stalled syndrome
失速症候群の症状
not the same
同じではありません
Then if we understand more and more
それで、もっともっと理解できたら
then we can
それならできます
tailor-made for everyone
誰にでも合わせてオーダーメイド
How much hormone should he take
どのくらいの量のホルモンを摂取すべきか
at what stage should you eat
どの段階で食べるべきか
if after a while
しばらくしたら
what happened again
また何が起こったのか
At what stage should you eat
どの段階で食べるべきか
then if by that time
それまでに
Well, medicine can help you a lot.
そうですね、薬は大いに役立ちます。
So let's all look forward to the day
それでは皆さんその日を楽しみにしましょう
We can all learn more about ourselves
私たちは皆、自分自身についてもっと学ぶことができます
know more about the environment
環境についてもっと知る
ok because of time
時間の関係でわかりました
I think we can first thank Deputy Director Shen
まずは沈副所長に感謝したいと思います
Then he will stay later
それから彼は後で残ります
I have some personal questions to ask
個人的な質問がいくつかあります
it's ok
大丈夫です
Okay, let's applaud him again and thank him.
さて、もう一度彼に拍手を送り、感謝しましょう。
Thanks
ありがとう